<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:smi="https://www.betterfeeds.org/series-media-info">
  <title>BSD Now</title>
  <subtitle>A weekly show covering the latest developments in the world of the BSD family of operating systems. News, Tutorials and Interviews for new users and long time developers alike.</subtitle>
  <link
    href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow.mp3.atom"
    rel="self"
    type="application/atom+xml"
    title="BSD Now - MP3 Audio" />
  <link
    href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow.ogg.atom"
    rel="alternate"
    type="application/atom+xml"
    title="BSD Now - OGG Audio" />
  <link href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/"/>
  <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/</id>
  <updated>2016-05-12T11:15:34Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jupiter Broadcasting</name>
    <uri>www.jupiterbroadcasting.com</uri>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>BSD Likes Ike!</title>
    <smi:episode>141</smi:episode>
    <link href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_05_11-bsd_likes_ike"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_05_11-bsd_likes_ike"/>
    <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_05_11-bsd_likes_ike</id>
    <updated>2016-05-12T11:15:34Z</updated>
    <link
      href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0141.mp3"
      rel="enclosure"
      length="48730165"
      type="audio/mpeg" />
    <contributor>
      <name>Kris Moore</name>
      <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
      <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
    </contributor>
    <contributor>
      <name>Allan Jude</name>
      <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
      <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
    </contributor>
    <contributor>
      <name>JT</name>
      <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
    </contributor>
    <content type="html">
&lt;h1&gt;Episode 141: BSD Likes Ike!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tedunangst.com/flak/post/regarding-embargoes&quot;&gt;Regarding Embargoes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our buddy TedU has a great thought piece today on the idea of “embargoes” for security advisories. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This all stemmed from a recent incident with LibreSSL patches from embargoed OpenSSL vulns, that accidentally got committed too early. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ted makes a pretty good case on the difficulties of having embargos, and maybe the reason there shouldn’t be. Couple of quotes to give you a taste:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“There are several difficulties maintaining embargoes. Keeping secrets is against human nature. I don’t want to be the one who leaks, but if I see something that looks like the secret is out, it’s a relief to be able to speak freely. There is a bias towards recognizing such signs where they may not really exist. (Exacerbated by broad embargoes where some parts leak but other parts don’t. It’s actually very hard to tell what’s not publicly known when you know everything.)&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;The most thorough embargo and release timeline reconstruction is the heartbleed timeline. It’s another great case study. Who exactly decided who were the haves and have nots? Was it determined by who needed to know or who you needed to know? Eventually the dam started to crack.”&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;“When Cloudflare brags that they get advance notice of vulnerabilities, attracting more customers, and therefore requiring even more early access, how are smaller players to compete? What happens if you’re not big enough to prenotify?&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;Sometimes vulnerabilities are announced unplanned. Zero day cyber missiles are part of our reality, which means end users don’t really have the luxury of only patching on Tuesday. They need to apply patches when they appear. If applying patches at inconvenient times is a problem, make it not a problem. Not really a gripe about embargoes per se, but the scheduled timing of coordinated release at the end of the embargo is catering to a problem that shouldn’t exist.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will admit that CloudFlare bragging around Heartbleed was upsetting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The biggest issue here is the difficulty with coordinating so many open source projects, which are often done by volunteers, in different countries and time zones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The other issue is determining when the secret is “out of the bag”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbsd.org/faq/current.html#r20160507&quot;&gt;MAJOR ABI BREAK: csu, ld.so, libc, libpthread update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenBSD warns those following the -current (development) branch to be careful as they upgrade because of a major ABI break that will result in applications not working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Handling of single-threaded programs is now closer to multi-threaded, with ld.so and libc.a doing thread information base (TIB) allocation. Threaded programs from before the 2016/03/19 csu and ld.so update will no longer run. An updated ld.so must be built and installed before running make build.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A special note for those on PowerPC: “PowerPC has been updated to offset the TIB from the hardware register. As a result, all threaded programs are broken until they have been rebuilt with the new libc and libpthread. perl must be built after building the libraries and before building the rest of base.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“The definitions of environ and __progname for dynamically linked programs have been moved from the C startup code to ld.so(1). An updated ld.so must be built and installed before running make build.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The link provides instructions on how to update your system properly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://random-notes-of-a-sysadmin.blogspot.be/2016/04/howto-install-freebsd-103-on-vmware.html&quot;&gt;How to install FreeBSD 10.3 on VMWare Workstation 12 Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This tutorial starts at the very basics, running through the FreeBSD installer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But then it goes on to configuring the machine specifically for VMWare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the system has been booted, the tutorial walks through installing the VMWare tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then networking is configured in both VMWare and FreeBSD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small hack is required to make the VMWare tools startup script wait until the network is up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A very nice tutorial for people using VMWare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am working on a patch to bsdinstall to ensure that the swap partition is put before the main partition, so it can more easily be resized if you later decide you need more space in your VM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svnweb.freebsd.org/base?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=299371&quot;&gt;the camcontrol reprobe subcommand has been added &lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“This makes it possible to manually force updating capacity data after the disk got resized. Without it it might be necessary to reboot before FreeBSD notices updated disk size under eg VMWare.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/bsdrp/files/BSD_Router_Project/1.59/&quot;&gt;BSD Router project releases v1.59&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We’ve talked about the BSD Router project a bit in the past, but today we have a brand new release to bring to you. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For those who don’t remember, the BSDrp is a router aimed at replacing more of your big-commercial type systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First up in the new hotness, we have it based upon recently released FreeBSD 10.3!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In addition, there is a new package: New package: mlvpn (aggregated network links in order to benefit from the bandwidth of multiple links)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other packages have gotten a bump with this release as well: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bsnmp-ucd to 0.4.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dma to 0.11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dmidecode to 3.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exabgp to 3.4.15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iperf3 to 3.1.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;monit to 5.17&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mpd5 to 5.8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;openvpn to 2.3.10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;python to 2.7.11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quagga to 1.0.20160315&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;strongswan to 5.4.0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are you waiting for? Amd64 and i386 images are ready for you to download now. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Interview - Isaac (.Ike) Levy -&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://semibug.org/&quot;&gt;See Ike again at SEMIBug in Troy, Michigan on May 17th&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tredly/&quot;&gt;Tredly - Prebuilt containers on FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/freebsd/comments/4gggw8/introducing_tredly_containers_for_unix_freebsd/&quot;&gt;Discussion regarding its GPLv3 licensing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new “container” solution called “Trendly” has started making some news around various tech sites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In particular, this new project uses FreeBSD as its base OS and jail functionality in the backend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their solution seems based around the idea of shipping containers as manifests, such as lists of packages to install and configuration knobs. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The project is still rather new, and we’ll be keeping an eye on it for the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One notable change already though, it was (for some reason) released under GPLv3. Understandably this caused quite a ruckus with various folks in the community, since it’s built specifically on BSD. Since this, the code has been re-licensed as MIT, which is far more in the spirit of a traditional BSD license. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netbsd.org/changes/changes-8.0.html#nvme%284%29&quot;&gt;NVMe driver added to NetBSD - ported from OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NetBSD has gained support for Non-Volatile Memory Express, the new standard for PCIe attached Flash Memory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The change of interface from SATA to NVMe offers a number of advantages, mostly, it doesn’t require the device to pretend to be a spinning disk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the biggest advantages is that it supports completing multiple operations at once, with the Intel hardware I have tested, 63 I/Os can happen concurrently, so a very large queue depth is required to keep the device busy. The 64th I/O channel is reserved for administrative commands, to keep them from being delayed by the large queue depth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The device I tested could read at 3800 MB/s, and write 1700MB/s, something that wouldn’t be possible with a normal SSD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is interesting that NetBSD took the NVMe support from OpenBSD, whereas the FreeBSD implementation was contributed directly by Intel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This may have to do with that fact that OpenBSD’s device model is closer to that of NetBSD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mail-index.netbsd.org/source-changes/2016/05/01/msg074367.html&quot;&gt;Commit Log &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://teespring.com/bsdnow&quot;&gt;New BSDNow T-Shirts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By popular demand, we have created a more subtle BSDNow shirt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Featuring only the smallish BSDNow logo over the left breast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Available in a number of styles (T-Shirt, Women’s T-Shirt, Long Sleeve, and Hoodie) as well as a number of colours: Black, Blue, Grey, and White&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hope is that enough orders come though so we can get them shipped in and your sweaty little hands in time for BSDCan. (I’ll be wearing mine, will you B...SD?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://teespring.com/bsd105&quot;&gt;If you still want one of our now-famous “The Usual BSD’s” t-shirts, you can also indicate your interest here, and once 10 or more shirts are ordered, a reprint will happen automatically&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.pcbsd.org/pipermail/testing/2016-May/010616.html&quot;&gt;PC-BSD 11-CURRENT with Package Base&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking for a way to play with the new FreeBSD base package system?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This month’s PC-BSD -CURRENT image now used packages for base system installation, and is asking for testers to help find bugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Known issues so far: 

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;setuid binaries (Fix in works)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Missing tzone files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distrib packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If all that doesn’t scare you away, then give it a whirl! Upgrades for previous APRIL images are now online also.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;BeastieBits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hardenedbsd.org/article/shawn-webb/2016-05-05/libressl-hardenedbsd-base&quot;&gt;HardenedBSD + LibreSSL&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6k1Mf0c6YW8&quot;&gt;Michael Dexter&#39;s talk at LFNW 2016 is the 2nd highest youtube views from this years conference&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ggr.com/why-openbsd-is-important-to-me.html&quot;&gt;Why OpenBSD is important to me&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.dragonflybsd.org/pipermail/users/2016-May/249581.html&quot;&gt;Study of nginx-1.9.12 performance/latency on DragonFlyBSD-g67a73&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geeklan.co.uk/?p=2109&quot;&gt;Running FreeBSD / OpenBSD / NetBSD as a virtualised guest on Online.net&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://zinascii.com/2016/the-illumos-syscall-handler.html&quot;&gt;The interesting story of how IllumOS syscalls work &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mezzantrop.wordpress.com/portfolio/the-beast/&quot;&gt;The BeaST is the FreeBSD based dual-controller reliable storage system concept with aim to implement ZFS and in-memory cache.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.dragonflybsd.org/pipermail/commits/2016-May/500352.html&quot;&gt;Francois Tigeot updates the drm/i915 driver to match what’s in Linux kernel 4.3&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ed_maste/status/730450314889924608&quot;&gt;FreeBSD is working on the update to Linux Kernel 4.6, we may finally get ahead of Dragonfly! &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/RT7tVtQ7&quot;&gt; Oskar - Torrent Jail&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/VkpMeims&quot;&gt; Shane - ZFS Delete&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/MmQ00Sv1&quot;&gt; Adam - Zimbra Port&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/Xx9TkX7A&quot;&gt; Ray - PC-BSD - FrameBuffer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/ncYxqpg3&quot;&gt; Richard - ZFS Backups&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tracing it back to BSD</title>
    <smi:episode>140</smi:episode>
    <link href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_05_04-tracing_it_back_to_bsd"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_05_04-tracing_it_back_to_bsd"/>
    <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_05_04-tracing_it_back_to_bsd</id>
    <updated>2016-05-04T16:30:02Z</updated>
    <link
      href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0140.mp3"
      rel="enclosure"
      length="43882256"
      type="audio/mpeg" />
    <contributor>
      <name>Kris Moore</name>
      <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
      <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
    </contributor>
    <contributor>
      <name>Allan Jude</name>
      <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
      <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
    </contributor>
    <contributor>
      <name>JT</name>
      <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
    </contributor>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;h1&gt;Episode 140: Tracing it back to 
BSD&lt;/h1&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;newsDate&quot;&gt;2016-05-04&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;hr/&gt;
      &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freebsd.org/news/status/report-2016-01-2016-03.html&quot;&gt;FreeBSD 
Quarterly Report&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;This quarterly status report starts with a rather 
interesting introduction by Warren Block&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;ASLR&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Porting CEPH to FreeBSD&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;RCTL I/O Rate Limiting&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;The Graphics Stack on FreeBSD (Haswell is in, work 
is progressing on the next update)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;CAM I/O Scheduler&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;NFS Server updates, working around the 16 group 
limit, and implementing pNFS, allowing NFS to scale 
beyond a single server&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Static Analysis of the FreeBSD Kernel with PVS 
Studio&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;PCI-express HotPlug&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;GitLab Port committed!&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;WITH&lt;em&gt;FAST&lt;/em&gt;DEPEND and other improvements to 
the FreeBSD build system&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Lots of other interesting stuff&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;hr/&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tedunangst.com/flak/post/a-prog-by-any-other-name&quot;&gt;A 
Prog By Any Other Name&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Ted Unangst looks at what goes into the name of a 
program&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;“Sometimes two similar programs are really the same 
program with two names. For example, grep and egrep are 
two commands that perform very similar functions and are 
therefore implemented as a single program. Running ls -i 
and observing the inode number of each file will reveal 
that there is only one file. Calling the program egrep 
is a shorthand for -E and does the same thing.”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;So BSD provides __progname in libc, so a program can 
tell what its name is&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;But, what if it has more than one name?&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;“In fact, every program has three names: its name in 
the filesystem, the name it has been invoked with, and 
whatever it believes its own name to be.”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Of course it is not that easy. &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;“there’s another set of choices for each name, the 
full path and the basename”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;“It’s even possible on some systems for argv[0] to 
be NULL.”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;He then goes on to rename doas (the OpenBSD light 
replacement for sudo) to banana and discuss what 
happens&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;“On that note, another possible bug is to realize 
that syslog by default uses progname. A user may be able 
to evade log monitoring by invoking doas with a 
different name. (Just fixed.)”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Another interesting article from our friend Ted&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;hr/&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/organizations/4892834293350400/&quot;&gt;FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt; 
and &lt;a href=&quot;https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/organizations/6246531984261120/&quot;&gt;NetBSD&lt;/a&gt; 
  Google Summer of Code projects have been 
announced&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Some FreeBSD highlights:

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add SCSI passthrough to CTL (share an optical drive 
via iSCSI)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add USB target mode driver based on CTL (share a USB 
device via iSCSI)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;API to link created /dev entries to sysctl 
nodes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Implement Ethernet Ring Protection Switching 
(ERPS)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;HD Audio device model in userspace for bhyve&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Some NetBSD highlights:

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Implement Ext4fs support in ReadOnly mode&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;NPF and blacklistd web interface&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Port U-Boot so it can be compiled on NetBSD&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Split debug symbols for pkgsrc builds&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;hr/&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tedunangst.com/flak/post/libressl-more-vague-promises&quot;&gt;libressl 
- more vague priomises&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;We haven’t had a Ted U article on the show as of 
late, however this week we get several! In his next 
entry “LibreSSL, more vague promises”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;He then goes into some detail on what has happened 
with LibreSSL in the past while, as well as future plans 
going forward. &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;“With an eye to the future, what new promises can we 
make? Some time ago I joked that we only promised to 
make a better TLS implementation, not a better TLS. 
Remains true, but fortunately there are people working 
on that, too. TLS 1.3 support is on the short term 
watchlist. The good news is we may be ahead of the game, 
having already removed compression. How much more work 
can there be?”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;“LibreSSL integrated the draft chacha20-poly1305 
construction from BoringSSL. The IETF has since 
standardized a slightly different version because if it 
were the same it wouldn’t be different. Support for 
standard variant, and the beginning of deprecation for 
the existing code, should be landing very shortly. 
Incidentally, some people got bent out of shape because 
shipping chacha20 meant exposing non IANA approved 
numbers to Internet. No promises that won’t happen 
again.”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;hr/&gt;
      &lt;h2&gt;Interview - Samy Al Bahra - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/0xF390&quot;&gt;@0xF390&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Backtrace&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;hr/&gt;
      &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://marc.info/?l=openbsd-cvs&amp;amp;m=146161167911029&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;systrace(1) 
is removed for OpenBSD 6.0&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;OpenBSD has removed systrace, an older mechanism for 
limiting what syscalls an application can make&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;It is mostly replaced by the pledge() system&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;OpenBSD was the first implementation, most others 
have been unmaintained for some time&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;The last reported Linux version was for kernel 
2.6.1&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;NetBSD removed systrace in 2007&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;hr/&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLE726R7YUJTePGvo0Zga2juUBxxFTH4Bk&quot;&gt;pfSense 
Video Series: Comprehensive Guide To pfSense 
2.3&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;A series of videos (11 so far), about pfSense&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Covers Why you would use it, how to pick your 
hardware, and installation&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Then the series covers some networking basics, to 
make sure you are up to speed before configuring your 
pfSense&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Then a comprehensive tour of the WebUI&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Then goes on to cover graphing, backing up and 
restoring configuration&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;There are also videos on running DHCP, NTP, and DNS 
servers&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;hr/&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://duck.co/blog/post/303/2016-foss-donations-announcement&quot;&gt;DuckDuckGo 
announces its 2016 FOSS Donations &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;The theme is “raising the standard of trust 
online”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Supported projects include:&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://undeadly.org/cgi?action=article&amp;amp;sid=20160503085227&amp;amp;mode=expanded&quot;&gt;OpenBSD 
Foundation announces DuckDuckGo as a Gold 
Sponsor&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;the Freedom of the Press Foundation for 
SecureDrop&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;the Freenet Project&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;the CrypTech Project&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;the Tor Project&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Fight for the Future for Save Security&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Open Source Technology Improvement Fund for 
VeraCrypt (based on TrueCrypt)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Riseup Labs for LEAP (LEAP Encryption Access 
Project)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;GPGTools for GPGMail&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;hr/&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://fossforce.com/2016/04/bsd-linuxfest-northwest/&quot;&gt;Larry 
the BSD Guy hangs up his hat at FOSS Force&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;After 15 years, Larry the BSD Guy has decided to 
hang it up, and walk into the sunset! (Figuratively of 
course)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;After wrapping up coverage of recent LinuxFest 
NorthWest (Which he didn’t attend), Larry has decided 
it’s time for a change and is giving up his column over 
at FOSS Force, as well as stepping away from all things 
technical. &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;His last write-up is a good one, and he has some 
nice plugs for both Dru Lavigne and Michael Dexter of 
the BSD community. &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;He will be missed, but we wish him all the luck with 
the future! He also puts out the plug that FOSS Force 
will be needing a new columnist in the near future, so 
if you are interested please let them know!&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;hr/&gt;
      &lt;h2&gt;Beastie Bits&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://blather.michaelwlucas.com/archives/2648&quot;&gt;If 
you sponsored “FreeBSD Mastery: Advanced ZFS”, check 
your mail box &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?l=freebsd-ports&amp;amp;m=146001143408868&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;pkg-1.7.0 
is an order of magnitude slower than pkg-1.6.4&lt;/a&gt; -- 
Caused by a problem not in pkg&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ixsystems.com/blog/linuxfest-northwest-2016/&quot;&gt;LinuxFest 
Northwest 2016 Recap&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxfestnorthwest.org/2016/sessions/doc-egyptian&quot;&gt;Dru 
Lavigne&#39;s &#39;Doc like an Egyption&#39; talk from LFNW&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxfestnorthwest.org/2016/sessions/devil-details-switching-bsd-linux&quot;&gt;Michael 
Dexters&#39; &#39;Switching to BSD from Linux&#39; talk from 
LFNW&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxfestnorthwest.org/2016/sessions/20-year-and-counting-secrets-enduring-user-groups&quot;&gt;Michael 
Dexters&#39; &#39;Secrets to enduring user groups&#39; talk from 
LFNW&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freebsdfoundation.org/journal/&quot;&gt;January 
issue of Freebsd Journal online for free&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://ghostbsd.org/10.3_alpha1&quot;&gt;Ghost BSD 
releases 10.3 Alpha1 for testing&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freebsdnews.com/2016/04/15/eurobsdcon-2016-call-for-papers/&quot;&gt;EuroBSDcon 
2016 - Call for Papers - Dealine: May 8th&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.knoxbug.org/content/knoxbug-maiden-voyage&quot;&gt;KnoxBUG 
Initial Meeting&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netways.de/en/events_trainings/osdc/archive/osdc2016/&quot;&gt;Photos, 
slides, and videos from the Open Source Data Center 
Conference &lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;hr/&gt;
      &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/KDnyWf6Y&quot;&gt; Mohammad - 
Replication&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/mAbRwbEF&quot;&gt; John - 
Rolling new packages&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/BNa6pyir&quot;&gt;Clint - 
Unicast&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/KDjS2Hxa&quot;&gt; Bill - 
GhostBSD&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/ABUUtzWM&quot;&gt; Charles - 
BSD Videos&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;hr/&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or 
stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
