<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed
        xml:lang="en"
        xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
        xmlns:smi="https://www.betterfeeds.org/series-media-info"
        xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
        xmlns:psc="http://podlove.org/simple-chapters">
    <title>BSD Now</title>
    <subtitle>A weekly show covering the latest developments in the world of the BSD family of operating systems. News,
        Tutorials and Interviews for new users and long time developers alike.
    </subtitle>
    <icon>http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/images/bsdnow-badge.jpg</icon>
    <media:thumbnail
            url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/images/bsdnow-badge.jpg"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow.atom"
            rel="self"
            type="application/atom+xml"
            title="BSD Now"/>
    <link
            href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/"
            rel="alternate"
            type="text/html"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowMp3"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now MP3 Audio"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowOgg"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now OGG Audio"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowMobile"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now SD Video"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowHd"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now HD Video"/>
    <link
            href="http://bitlove.org/jupiterbroadcasting/bsdnowhd/feed"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now HD Video (BitTorrent)"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow/bsdnow-2016-07.atom"
            rel="next"
            type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/</id>
    <updated>2016-08-07T11:35:00Z</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Jupiter Broadcasting</name>
        <uri>www.jupiterbroadcasting.com</uri>
    </author>
    <smi:sequential>false</smi:sequential>
    <entry>
        <title>Big Int Trouble</title>
        <smi:episode>153</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_08_03-big_int_trouble"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_08_03-big_int_trouble</id>
        <published>2016-08-04T10:06:54-07:00</published>
        <updated>2016-08-07T11:34:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0153.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="60563375"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0153.ogg"
                    fileSize="60563375"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0153.mp3"
                    fileSize="37379856"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/bsd-0153-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <psc:chapters version="1.1">
            <psc:chapter start="00:00:58" title="Headlines"/>
            <psc:chapter start="00:00:58" title="my int is too big"
                         href="http://www.tedunangst.com/flak/post/my-int-is-too-big"/>
            <psc:chapter start="00:08:42" title="FreeBSD Quarterly Status Report Q2 2016"
                         href="https://www.freebsd.org/news/status/report-2016-04-2016-06.html"/>
            <psc:chapter start="00:16:49" title="AD: DigitalOcean - Simple Cloud Hosting, Built for Developers"
                         href="http://www.digitalocean.com/" image="http://www.bsdnow.tv/images/2.png"/>
            <psc:chapter start="00:18:57" title="Vulnerabilities discovered in freebsd-update and portsnap"
                         href="https://lists.freebsd.org/pipermail/freebsd-security/2016-July/009016.html"/>
            <psc:chapter start="00:31:39" title="OpenSSH 7.3 Released" href="http://www.openssh.com/txt/release-7.3"/>
            <psc:chapter start="00:35:55" title="News Roundup"/>
            <psc:chapter start="00:35:55" title="OpenBSD Ports - Integrating Third Party Applications [pdf]"
                         href="http://jggimi.homeip.net/semibug.pdf"/>
            <psc:chapter start="00:42:50" title="NetBSD removes last RWX page in amd64 kernel"
                         href="http://mail-index.netbsd.org/source-changes/2016/07/27/msg076413.html"/>
            <psc:chapter start="00:44:30" title="AD: iXsystems - Enterprise Servers and Storage for Open Source"
                         href="http://www.ixsystems.com/bsdnow/" image="http://www.bsdnow.tv/images/1.png"/>
            <psc:chapter start="00:48:30"
                         title="DragonFly BSD 4.6 launches with home-grown support for NVMe Controllers"
                         href="http://linux.softpedia.com/blog/dragonfly-bsd-4-6-0-launches-with-home-grown-support-for-nvme-controllers-506908.shtml"/>
            <psc:chapter start="00:53:34"
                         title="The powerd++ daemon monitors the system load and adjusts the CPU clock accordingly and is a drop-in replacement for FreeBSD's native powerd(8)."
                         href="http://www.freshports.org/sysutils/powerdxx/"/>
            <psc:chapter start="00:58:40" title="Beastie Bits"/>
            <psc:chapter start="00:58:40"
                         title="Hyper-V: Unmapped I/O improves userland direct disk performance by 35% ~ 135%"
                         href="https://svnweb.freebsd.org/base?view=revision&amp;revision=303474"/>
            <psc:chapter start="00:59:25" title="One does not simply remove FreeBSD"
                         href="https://imgur.com/a/gjGoq"/>
            <psc:chapter start="01:00:02" title="A new BSD Podcast &quot;BSD Synergy&quot; has started"
                         href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBua6yMtJ6W5ExYSREnS3UQ"/>
            <psc:chapter start="01:00:56" title="KnoxBug - Next Meeting - Aug 30th"
                         href="http://knoxbug.org/content/2016-08-30"/>
            <psc:chapter start="01:01:54" title="AD: Tarsnap - Online Backups for the Truly Paranoid"
                         href="http://www.tarsnap.com/bsdnow" image="http://www.bsdnow.tv/images/3.png"/>
            <psc:chapter start="01:04:00" title="Feedback/Questions"/>
            <psc:chapter start="01:04:00" title="Daniel - Root/Wheel" href="http://pastebin.com/8sMyKm6c"/>
            <psc:chapter start="01:05:25" title="Joe - IPV6 Frag" href="http://pastebin.com/r5Y0gbxf"/>
            <psc:chapter start="01:09:30" title="Paul - ChicagoBug" href="http://pastebin.com/iVYPYcVs"/>
            <psc:chapter start="01:11:35" title="Chris - SSH BruteBlock" href="http://pastebin.com/597m9gHa"/>
            <psc:chapter start="01:13:25" title="Todd - Jails" href="http://pastebin.com/xjbKwSaz"/>
        </psc:chapters>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>JT</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
        </contributor>
        <summary>This week on BSDNow, we have a variety of news to discuss, covering quite the spectrum of BSD,
            including a new DragonFly release! That plus your feedback &amp; questions, all coming up on your place to
            B...SD!
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 153: Big int trouble&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tedunangst.com/flak/post/my-int-is-too-big&quot;&gt;my int is too big&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“The &lt;a href=&quot;http://marc.info/?l=oss-security&amp;amp;m=146853062403622&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;NCC
            Group report&lt;/a&gt; describes the bugs, but not the history of the code.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“Several of them, as reported by NCC, involved similar integer truncation issues. Actually, they
            involved very similar modern 64 bit code meeting classic 32 bit code”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“The thrsleep system call is a part of the kernel code that supports threads. As the name implies,
            it gives userland a measure of control over scheduling and lets a thread sleep until something happens. As
            such, it takes a timeout in the form of a timespec. The kernel, however, internally implements time keeping
            using ticks (there are HZ, 100, ticks per second). The tsleep function (t is for timed) takes an int number
            of ticks and performs basic validation by checking that it’s not negative. A negative timeout would indicate
            that the caller has miscalculated. The kernel panics so you can fix the bug, instead of stalling forever.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“The trouble therefore is when userland is allowed to specify a timeout that could be negative.
            The existing code made an attempt to handle various tricks by converting the timespec to a ticks value
            stored as a 64 bit long long which was checked against INT&lt;em&gt;MAX before passing to sleep. Any value
            over INT&lt;/em&gt;MAX would be truncated, so we can’t allow that. Instead, we saturate the value to
            INT_MAX. Unfortunately, this check didn’t account for the possibility that the tick conversion from the
            timespec could also overflow and result in a negative value.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Then there is the description of the kqueue flaw:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“Every kqueue keeps a list of all the attached events it’s watching for. A simple array is used to
            store file events, indexed by fd.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“This array is scaled to accommodate the largest fd that needs to be stored. This would obviously
            cause trouble, consuming too much memory, if the identifier were not validated first. Which is exactly what
            kqueue tries to do. The fd&lt;em&gt;getfile function checks that the identifier is a file that the process
            has open. One wrinkle. fd&lt;/em&gt;getfile takes an int argument but ident is a uintptr_t, possibly 64
            bits. An ident of 2^32 + 2 will look like a valid file descriptor, but then cause the array to be resized to
            gargantuan proportions.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“Again, the fix is pretty simple. We must check that the ident is bounded by INT&lt;em&gt;MAX
            before calling fd&lt;/em&gt;getfile. This bug likely would have been exploitable beyond a panic, but the
            array allocation was changed to use mallocarray instead of multiplying arguments by hand, thus preventing
            another overflow.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Then there is a description of the anonymous mmap flaw, and the “secret magic” __MAP_NOFAULT flag&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freebsd.org/news/status/report-2016-04-2016-06.html&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            Quarterly Status Report Q2 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It’s time for another round of FreeBSD Quarterly Status Reports!&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In this edition, we have status updates from the various teams, including IRC/Bugs/RE/Ports/Core
            and Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;We also have updates on some specific projects, including from Konstantin on the on-going work for
            his implementation of ASLR, including the new ‘proccontrol’ command which provides the following:
            &amp;gt; “The proccontrol(1) utility was written to manage and query ASLR enforcement on a per-process
            basis. It is required for analyzing ASLR failures in specific programs. This utility leverages the
            procctl(2) interface which was added to the previous version of the patch, with some bug fixes.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Next are updates on porting CEPH to FreeBSD, the ongoing work to improve EFI+GELI (touched on last
            week) and more robust Mutexes. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Additionally we have an update from Matt Macy and the Xorg team discussing the current work to
            update FreeBSD’s graphic stack:
            &amp;gt; “All Intel GPUs up to and including the unreleased Kaby Lake are supported. The xf86-video-intel
            driver will be updated soon. Updating this driver requires updating Xorg, which in turn is blocked on Nvidia
            updates.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The kernel also got some feature status updates, including on the new Allwinner SoC support, an
            update on FreeBSD in Hyper-V and VIMAGE &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In addition to a quick update on the arm64 architecture (It’s getting there, RPi3 is almost a
            thing), we also have a slew of port updates, including support for GitLab in ports, updates on GNOME / KDE
            and some additional Intel-specific networking tools.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.freebsd.org/pipermail/freebsd-security/2016-July/009016.html&quot;&gt;Vulnerabilities
            discovered in freebsd-update and portsnap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There are two vulnerabilities discovered in freebsd-update and portsnap, where an attacker could
            place files in the portsnap directory and they would be used without being subject to having their checksum
            verified (but this requires root access), and the second where a man-in-the-middle attacker could guess the
            name of a file you will fetch by exploiting the time-gap between when you download the initial snapshot, and
            when you fetch the updated files.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There are a number of vulnerabilities that were discovered in libarchive/tar as well&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There is also an issue with bspatch. A security advisory for bspatch has already been released, as
            this vulnerabilities was also discovered by the Chromium team, which uses this same code. The patch
            discussed in this mailing list thread is larger, but secteam@ believes at least one of the additional checks
            introduced is incorrect and may prevent a valid patch from being applied. The smaller patch was pushed out
            first, to solve the main attack vector, while the larger patch is investigated. Automated fuzz testing is
            underway. Great care is being taken fixing bspatch, as if it is broken installing future updates becomes
            much more difficult&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;secteam@ and core@ would like to emphasize that the FreeBSD project takes these issue very
            seriously and are working on it
            &amp;gt; “As a general rule, secteam@ does not announce vulnerabilities for which we don&#39;t have patches,
            but we concede that we should have considered making an exception in this case”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Work is underway to re-architect freebsd-update and portsnap to do signature verification on all
            files before they are passed to libarchive/tar, to help protect users from any future vulnerabilities in
            libarchive.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;However, this requires changes to the metadata format to provide these additional signatures, and
            backwards compatibilities must be preserved, so people can update to the newer versions to get these
            additional security features &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There is also discussion of using HTTPS for delivery of the files, but certificate verification
            and trust are always an issue. FreeBSD does not distribute a certificate trust store by default.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There will be more on this in the coming days.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openssh.com/txt/release-7.3&quot;&gt;OpenSSH 7.3 Released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;OpenSSH 7.3 has landed! &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Primarily a bug-fix release, the release notes do mention the pending deprecation of some more
            legacy Crypto in the future, including denying all RSA keys &amp;lt; 1024bit, and removal of SSHv1 support.
            (Already disabled via compile option)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the bug side, there was a security issue addressed in sshd:&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;“sshd(8): Mitigate a potential denial-of-service attack against the system&#39;s crypt(3) function
            via sshd(8). An attacker could send very long passwords that would cause excessive CPU use in crypt(3).
            sshd(8) now refuses to accept password authentication requests of length greater than 1024 characters”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also a timing issue was resolved in regard to password auth, which could possibly allow
            an attacker to discern between valid/invalid account names.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;On the feature side, we have the new ProxyJump option (-J flag) which allows you to do simplified
            indirection through various SSH jump hosts.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Various bugs were fixed, and some compile failures resolved in the portable version to
            auto-disable some ciphers not supported by OpenSSL.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jggimi.homeip.net/semibug.pdf&quot;&gt;OpenBSD Ports - Integrating Third
            Party Applications [pdf]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A talk from Josh Grosse, presented at SEMIBUG (South-East Michigan BSD Users Group), about OpenBSD
            Ports&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It opens by explaining the separation of the ‘base system’ from ‘packages’, as is common in most
            all BSDs&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It explains the contents of OpenBSD package tar file, which contain some metadata files (+CONTENTS
            and +DESC) and then the actual package files&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The talk goes on to explain the different branches (-release, -stable, and -current), and warn
            users that there are no official -stable packages from the project&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Then it goes on into the development model, including what new contributors should expect&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Then it walks through the entire process of creating a port and getting it contributed&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mail-index.netbsd.org/source-changes/2016/07/27/msg076413.html&quot;&gt;NetBSD
            removes last RWX page in amd64 kernel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;NetBSD has purged the last holdout RWX page on the amd64 platform
            &amp;gt; “Use UVM&lt;em&gt;PROT&lt;/em&gt;ALL only if UVM&lt;em&gt;KMF&lt;/em&gt;EXEC is given as argument.
            Otherwise, if UVM&lt;em&gt;KMF&lt;/em&gt;PAGEABLE is also given as argument, only the VA is allocated and
            UVM waits for the page to fault before kentering it. When kentering it, it will use the UVM&lt;em&gt;PROT&lt;/em&gt;
            flag that was passed to uvm_map; which means that it will kenter it as RWX. With this change, the number of
            RWX pages in the amd64 kernel reaches strictly zero.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Break out the party favors! Hopefully any last stragglers in any of the other BSD’s gets retired
            soon as well.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://linux.softpedia.com/blog/dragonfly-bsd-4-6-0-launches-with-home-grown-support-for-nvme-controllers-506908.shtml&quot;&gt;DragonFly
            BSD 4.6 launches with home-grown support for NVMe Controllers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Softpedia picked up on the release of DragonFlyBSD 4.6, specifically about their new home-grown
            NVMe driver.
            &amp;gt; “We now have a NVMe driver (PCIe SSDs). It currently must be kldloaded with nvme_load=&quot;YES&quot;
            in /boot/loader.conf. The driver uses all concurrency features offered by the chip and will distribute
            queues and interrupts across multiple CPUs to maximize performance. It has been tested up to around 1.05M
            IOPS @4K, and roughly 6.5 GBytes/sec @32K (random read from urandom-filled partition, physio, many threads),
            with the 2xE5-2620v4 (xeon) test server 78% idle in the IOPS test and 72% idle on the bandwidth test. In
            other words, we maxed out the three NVMe devices we had plugged in and the system still had plenty of suds
            left over. Please note that a machine&#39;s ability to boot from an NVMe device depends on the BIOS, and not
            DragonFly. Most BIOSes cannot boot from NVMe devices and those that can probably only do it through UEFI.
            Info on device state is available with the new utility nvmectl.“&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In addition to this improved support, 4.6 also brings in the improved graphics support, matching
            what is in Linux 4.4 and support for Broadwell/Skylake.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;SMP also got some love:
            &amp;gt; “SMP performance was already very good. As part of the NVMe driver work we revamped the buffer
            cache subsystem and a number of other I/O related paths, further reducing lock contention and IPI signalling
            overheads. We also put topology-aware cpu cache localization into the kernel memory allocator (primarily
            helps multi-socket systems and systems with high core counts). The network subsystem also continues to
            receive significant improvement, with modest machine configurations now capable of handling upwards of 580K
            conns/sec.“
            +&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dragonflybsd.org/release46/&quot;&gt;Full Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freshports.org/sysutils/powerdxx/&quot;&gt;The powerd++ daemon
            monitors the system load and adjusts the CPU clock accordingly and is a drop-in replacement for FreeBSD&#39;s
            native powerd(8).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;As mentioned in our EuroBSDCon 2016 rundown, Dominic Fandrey will be giving a presentation about
            his powerd replacement, powerd++&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The source code is already available on github, and is in ports&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The major difference is the newer design handle many-core systems much better. The original powerd
            was written at a time when most laptops only had a single core, and maybe a hyperthread.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The new design decides which CPU frequency to use by looking at the busiest core, rather than the
            average across the cores, resulting in a more meaningful result. It also supports averaging over a longer
            period of time, to avoid jumping to a higher frequency to quickly&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;powerd++ also avoids ‘slewing’ the cpu frequency, ratching it up and down one step at a time, and
            instead jumps directly to the target frequency.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Often times, you will use less battery by jumping to maximum frequency, finishing the work, and
            going back to a low power state, than trying to do that work over a longer period of time in low power mode&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Beastie Bits&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svnweb.freebsd.org/base?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=303474&quot;&gt;Hyper-V:
            Unmapped I/O improves userland direct disk performance by 35% ~ 135%&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgur.com/a/gjGoq&quot;&gt;One does not simply remove FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBua6yMtJ6W5ExYSREnS3UQ&quot;&gt;A new BSD
            Podcast &quot;BSD Synergy&quot; has started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://knoxbug.org/content/2016-08-30&quot;&gt;KnoxBug - Next Meeting - Aug 30th
            &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/8sMyKm6c&quot;&gt; Daniel - Root/Wheel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/r5Y0gbxf&quot;&gt; Joe - IPV6 Frag&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/iVYPYcVs&quot;&gt; Paul - ChicagoBug&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/597m9gHa&quot;&gt; Chris - SSH BruteBlock&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/xjbKwSaz&quot;&gt; Todd - Jails &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a
            href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
