<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed
        xml:lang="en-us"
        xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
        xmlns:smi="https://www.betterfeeds.org/series-media-info"
        xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
        xmlns:psc="http://podlove.org/simple-chapters">
    <title>BSD Now</title>
    <subtitle>A weekly show covering the latest developments in the world of the BSD family of operating systems. News,
        Tutorials and Interviews for new users and long time developers alike.
    </subtitle>
    <icon>http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/images/bsdnow-badge.jpg</icon>
    <media:thumbnail
            url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/images/bsdnow-badge.jpg"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow/bsdnow-2016-02.atom"
            rel="self"
            type="application/atom+xml; charset=utf-8"
            title="BSD Now"/>
    <link
            href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/"
            rel="alternate"
            type="text/html"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowMp3"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now MP3 Audio"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowOgg"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now OGG Audio"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowMobile"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now SD Video"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowHd"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now HD Video"/>
    <link
            href="http://bitlove.org/jupiterbroadcasting/bsdnowhd/feed"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now HD Video (BitTorrent)"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow/bsdnow-2016-03.atom"
            rel="previous"
            type="application/atom+xml; charset=utf-8"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow/bsdnow-2016-01.atom"
            rel="next"
            type="application/atom+xml; charset=utf-8"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow.atom"
            rel="first"
            type="application/atom+xml; charset=utf-8"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow/bsdnow-2013-09.atom"
            rel="last"
            type="application/atom+xml; charset=utf-8"/>
    <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/</id>
    <updated>2016-06-17T12:34:00Z</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Jupiter Broadcasting</name>
        <uri>www.jupiterbroadcasting.com</uri>
    </author>
    <smi:sequential>false</smi:sequential>
    <entry>
        <title>Store all the Things</title>
        <smi:episode>130</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_02_24-store_all_the_things"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_02_24-store_all_the_things</id>
        <published>2016-02-25T11:28:18-08:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-17T12:19:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jupiterbroadcasting/bsd-0130.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="100777604"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jupiterbroadcasting/bsd-0130.ogg"
                    fileSize="100777604"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0130.mp3"
                    fileSize="62623755"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/bsd-0130-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>JT</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
        </contributor>
        <summary>Allan is back from the Storage Summit in Silicon Valley! We are going to get his thoughts on how the
            conference went, plus bring you the latest ZFS info discussed. That plus the usual BSD news is headed your
            way right now!
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 130: Store all the Things&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2016/02/21/openbsd_website_operator_patch_now_for_the_sake_of_your_sanity/?mt=1456206806399&quot;&gt;OpenBSD
            website operators urged to fix mind-alteringly bad bug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;We start off a bit light-hearted this week, with the important, breaking news that &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt;
            a long-standing OpenBSD bug has been addressed for the HTTP daemon.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Specifically? It changes the default 404 page fonts away from Comic Sans, to a bit more
            crowd-pleasing alternative:

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“For some reason the httpd status pages (e.g. 404) use the Comic Sans typeface. This patch removes
            comic sans and sets the typeface to the default sans-serif typeface of the client.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“This lowers the number of people contacting website maintainers with typeface complaints
            bordering on harassment”.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Operators running HTTPD are highly encouraged to update their systems to the latest code, right
            now……... No seriously, we are waiting for you. Get it done now and then we’ll continue with the show.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2016.asiabsdcon.org/registration/?lang=en&quot;&gt;Registration for
            AsiaBSDCon 2016 is now open + Talk Schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;After a few delays, the registration for AsiaBSDCon has now opened!&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The conference starts in less than two weeks! now, so be sure to get signed up ASAP.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In addition the schedule has been posted, and here’s some of the highlights of this year’s
            conference.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In addition to FreeBSD and NetBSD dev summits on the first two days, we have some excellent
            tutorials being given this year by Kirk, Gnn, Dru and more! (https://2016.asiabsdcon.org/program.html.en)
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The regular paper talks also have lots of good ones this year, including this crazy encrypted boot
            loader one given by our very own Allan Jude!&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.d2-si.fr/2016/02/15/openbsd-on-aws/?hn&quot;&gt;OPENBSD ON AWS : AN
            UNEXPECTED JOURNEY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;We have a blog post from Antoine Jacoutot, talking about the process of getting OpenBSD up and
            running in AWS&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It starts with his process of creating an AMI from scratch, which ended up not being that
            bad:&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;create and loopback-mount a raw image containing a UFS filesystem extract the OpenBSD base sets
            (which are just regular tarballs) and kernel enable console output (so that one could “aws ec2
            get-console-output”)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;install the boot loader on the image then use the ec2 tools to import the RAW image to S3, convert
            it into a volume (ec2-import-volume) which we can snapshot (ec2-create-snapshot) and create an AMI from
            (ec2-register)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The blog post also has a link to a script which automates this process, so don’t be
            daunted if you didn’t quite follow all of that. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Thanks to the recently landed DomU support, the final pieces of the puzzle fell into place,
            allowing OpenBSD to function as a proper guest (with networking!)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Next it details the process of injecting a public SSH key into the instances for instant remote
            access. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;An ec2-init.sh script was created (also on github) which does the following:&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;setting the hostname&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;installing the provided SSH public key to /root/.ssh/authorized_keys&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;executing user-data (if it starts with a shebang)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;displaying the host SSH fingerprints on the console (to match cloud-init)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;With that done, OpenBSD is pretty much AWS ready! He then gives a brief walkthrough of
            setting up nginx for new users, but if you’ve already done this before then the instance is ready for you to
            hacking on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.freebsd.org/SummerOfCodeIdeas&quot;&gt;Start thinking of ideas for
            things with FreeBSD for Google&#39;s 2016 Summer of Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Students and Developers, listen up! It’s time to start thinking about GSoC again, and FreeBSD is
            looking to update its project ideas page.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There’s some good ones on the list, plus ones that should be pruned (such as GELI boot), but now
            is the time to start adding new ones before we get too deep into the process.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This goes for the other BSD’s as well, start thinking about your proposals, or if you are
            developer, which projects would be a good fit for mentoring.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;(Improving the Linux Compat layer is one I think should be done!)
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.freebsd.org/Graphics/Getting%20started%20with%20kernel%20projects&quot;&gt;Guide
            to getting started with kernel hacking&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;One of the things that’s been asked frequently is how to contribute towards the efforts to bring
            updated DRM / X drivers to the FreeBSD kernel. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Jean-S&#233;bastien P&#233;dron has started a great guide on the Wiki which details how to get
            started with the porting effort, and that developers need not be afraid of helping.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;Storage Summit Roundup&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Earlier this week a number of developers from FreeBSD, as well as various vendors that use
            FreeBSD, or provide products used with FreeBSD met for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.freebsd.org/201602StorageSummit&quot;&gt;Storage
            Summit&lt;/a&gt;, to discuss the
            future of these technologies&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The summit was co-located with the USENIX FAST (Filesystems And Storage Technologies) conference&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The summit was sponsored by the FreeBSD Foundation and FlightAware&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;After a short introduction, the event opened with a Networking Synergy panel&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The focus of this panel was to see if there were techniques and lessons learned in improving the
            networking stack over the last 10 years that could be applied to improving the storage stack&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A lot of time was spent discussing issues like multi-queue support, CPU scheduling, and ways to
            modernize the stack&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.freebsd.org/201602StorageSummit/CAM&quot;&gt;CAM Scheduling &amp;amp;
            Locking Revamp&lt;/a&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;No notes posted&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.freebsd.org/201602StorageSummit/UserSpace&quot;&gt;User Space
            Storage Stack&lt;/a&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;One of the user space storage stacks discussed was Diskmap&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Like netmap, but for disks (diskmap)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Kernel bypass for accessing disks&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Ilias Marinos, who is working on diskmap at Cambridge University, described diskmap to the group&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A design discussion then followed in which the memory management was covered as that&#39;s an
            issue for any sort of &quot;IO&quot; map system

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Action Items:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Discuss with Luigi the idea of code merges&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Need a reset path API&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Kernel buffer mapping for reliability&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Support for other interfaces (SATA/SCSI)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;GEOM layer adaptation&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.freebsd.org/201602StorageSummit/NewStorageTechnologies&quot;&gt;Adapting
            to New Storage Technologies&lt;/a&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This working group was led by Adrian Palmer, from Seagate&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;SMR&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Persistent Memory&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Session 1: Device Identification and the structural requirements

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Agenda: We&#39;ll look over the Identification nuances and what needs to change to support the
            structure. Support for IO order guarantees, forward-write only requirements, new commands and topology. Dig
            into CAM and GEOM layers. Solutions should be fast and have as few code paths as possible&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Results: Small audience. We talked about zoned characteristics, and how it can be used in various
            workloads, projected to be implemented in years&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Session 2: Information dissemination and consumption

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Agenda: Where and how will information from the report_zones command be gathered, stored, combined
            and used. This will include userspace storage and multi-volume management. Will CAM store this data, or will
            GEOM? How frequently will this need to be queried/updated/verified from the drive?&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Results: Merged with ZFS working group to discuss SMR. Came up with idea that could be implemented
            as circular buffer zone type. Began to discuss solutions among developers&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.freebsd.org/201602StorageSummit/ZFS&quot;&gt;ZFS&lt;/a&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;During the first session we discussed how to improve dedup support
            + A dedup throttle or cap was discussed. When the size of the DDT grows beyond this size, new entries would
            not be deduped.

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;An alternative to this was also discussed, where when the DDT reached the cap size, it would
            remove a random entry with only a single reference from the DDT to make room for the new entry. When a block
            is going to be freed, if it is not found in the DDT, it is assumed to have only 1 reference, and removed.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There was also discussion of replacing the DDT with an in-memory hash table and a “log” of
            increment/decrement operations, that is periodically compacted. The hash table is recreated from the log at
            pool import time. This would reduce the in-memory footprint of the DDT, as well as speed up all write
            operations as adding an entry to the dedup log will be less expensive than updating the DDT.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There was also discussion of using dedicated device(s) for the DDT, either using the DDT on SSD
            work by Nexenta, or the Metadata Classes work by Intel&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The first session also discussed Secure Delete and related things

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The desire for an implementation of TRIM that uses the “secure erase” functionality provided by
            some disks was expressed&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Overwriting sectors with patterns of garbage may be insufficient because SSDs may internally remap
            where a specific LBA physically resides&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The possibility of using something like the “eager zero” feature to periodically write zeros over
            all free blocks in the pool to erase any lingering data fragments&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Problems with the FreeBSD TRIM implementation were discussed, as well as looking at ways to
            implement the new ZFS TRIM implementation on FreeBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;ABD (ARC Buf Data) was discussed, a new design that lessens the requirement for contiguous memory.
            Only a small area of contiguous blocks is reserved at boot, and compressed ARC blocks are constructed of
            scatter-gather lists of individual pages&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The second session combined with the SMR group and talked about SMR support in ZFS

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Later in the second session ZFS Encryption was also discussed, mostly with a focus on what the use
            cases are&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The third session combined all of the groups for an overview of upcoming ZFS features including
            device removal and channel programs&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There was also a request for code review, for mostly finished projects like Persistent L2ARC,
            Writeback cache, and Large dnode support&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Hallway Track

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;ZFS / VFS Interaction&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Adrian Palmer has been a FreeBSD hobbyist since FreeBSD 7, and I think I managed to convince him
            to start contributing&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jamesdeagle.blogspot.com/2016/02/one-week-with-netbsd-70-back-to-unix.html&quot;&gt;One
            Week with NetBSD 7.0: Back to Unix basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The author of this blog series is sending a week using NetBSD 7.0, following a previous series on
            Solaris 10&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“This is actually familiar territory, as I&#39;ve been using BSD variants almost exclusively since
            2006. My recent SunOS explorations were triggered last summer by OpenBSD having choked on my current laptop&#39;s
            NVIDIA card, and from what I could see at the time, FreeBSD had the same problem, although I now know NVIDIA
            drivers exist for that system. The thing that keeps me from going all-in with FreeBSD 10.x, however, is the
            fact that Firefox crashes and leaves &quot;core dump&quot; messages in its wake, and I&#39;m just not a
            Chrome kinda guy.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“For those with a catholic taste in Unix, NetBSD is a keg party at the Vatican. If you&#39;re an
            absolute Unix beginner, or have been living on Ubuntu-based Linux distros for too long, then you may feel
            stranded at first by NetBSD&#39;s sparseness. You&#39;ll find yourself staring into the abyss and seeing
            only a blinking cursor staring back. If you have the presence of mind to type startx, you&#39;ll be greeted
            by twm, a window manager offering little more than an xterm window with the same blinking cursor until you
            learn how to configure the .twmrc file to include whatever applications you want or need in the right-click
            menu.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“As for NetBSD itself, I can&#39;t think of any major productivity applications that can&#39;t be
            installed, and most multimedia stuff works fine.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Issues the author hopes to sort out in later posts:

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Audio playback (youtube videos in Firefox)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Wireless&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Flash&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Digital Camera SD Card readability, video playback&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Audacity&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A “fancy” desktop like Gnome 2, KDE, or xfce&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jamesdeagle.blogspot.com/2016/02/one-week-with-netbsd-70-libreoffice.html&quot;&gt;follow-up
            post&lt;/a&gt;, the author got LibreOffice installed and sorted out the audio issues they were having&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jamesdeagle.blogspot.com/2016/02/one-week-with-netbsd-70-mixed-review-of.html&quot;&gt;later
            follow-up&lt;/a&gt; XFCE is up and running as well&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.dustinkirkland.com/2016/02/zfs-is-fs-for-containers-in-ubuntu-1604.html&quot;&gt;ZFS
            is for Containers in Ubuntu 16.04&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;As you may have heard, Ubuntu 16.04 will include ZFS -- baked directly into Ubuntu -- supported by
            Canonical&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“ZFS one of the most beloved features of Solaris, universally coveted by every Linux sysadmin with
            a Solaris background. To our delight, we&#39;re happy to make to OpenZFS available on every Ubuntu system.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;What does “supported by Canonical” mean?&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“You&#39;ll find zfs.ko automatically built and installed on your Ubuntu systems. No more
            DKMS-built modules”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“The user space zfsutils-linux package will be included in Ubuntu Main, with security updates
            provided by Canonical”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The article then provides a quick tutorial for setting up Linux Containers (LXC) backed by ZFS&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In the example, ZFS is backed by a file on the existing disk, not by a real disk, and with no
            redundancy&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;However, the setup script seems to support using real block devices&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://sfconservancy.org/&quot;&gt;Software Freedom Conservancy&lt;/a&gt; is
            expected to issue a statement detailing their opinion on the legalities and licensing issues of bundling ZFS
            with Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hypatia.software/2016/01/29/polling-is-a-hack-server-sent-events-eventsource-with-gevent-flask-nginx-and-freebsd/&quot;&gt;Polling
            is a Hack: Server Sent Events (EventSource) with gevent, Flask, nginx, and FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A tutorial on setting up ‘Server-Sent Events’, also know as EventSource in javascript, to notify
            website clients of new data, rather than having the javascript constantly poll for new data.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The setup uses FreeBSD, nginx, gevent, Python, and the Flask framework&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The tutorial walks through setting a basic Python application using the Flask framework&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Then setting up the client side in Javascript&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Then for the server side setup, it covers installing and configuring nginx, and py-supervisor on
            FreeBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The tutorial also includes links to additional resources and examples, including how to rate limit
            the Flash application&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aikchar.me/blog/why-freebsd.html&quot;&gt;Why FreeBSD?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;An excellent article written by Hamza Sheikh, discussing why FreeBSD is now his clear choice for
            learning UNIX.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The article is pretty well written and lengthy, but has some great parts which we wanted to share
            with you:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;There were many rough edges in the Linux world and some of them exist even today. Choosing the
            right distribution (distro) for the task at hand is always the first and most difficult decision to make.
            While this is a strength of the Linux community it is also its weakness. This is exacerbated with the toxic
            infighting within the community in the last few years.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;A herd of voices believes it is their right to bring down a distro community because it is not like
            their distro of choice. Forking upstream projects has somehow become taboo. Hurling abuse in mailing lists
            is acceptable. Helping new users is limited to lambasting their distro of choice. Creating conspiracy
            theories over software decisions is the way to go. Copyleft zealots roam social media declaring non-copyleft
            free software heretic abominations. It all boils down to an ecosystem soured by the presence of maniacs who
            have the loudest voices and they seem to be everywhere you turn.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Where is the engineering among all this noise? Btrfs - baking for a long time - is still nowhere
            near ZFS in stability or feature parity. systemd is an insatiable entity that feeds on every idea in sight
            and just devours indiscriminately. Wayland was promised years ago and its time has yet to arrive. Containers
            are represented by Docker that neither securely contains applications nor makes them easy to manage in
            production. Firewalling is dithering between firewalld, nftables, etc. SystemTap cannot match DTrace.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;In the same time span what do various BSDs offer? pf, CARP, ZFS, Hammer, OpenSSH, jails, pkgsrc,
            (software) ports, DTrace, hardware portability; just to name a few. Few would deny that BSDs have delivered
            great engineering with free software licenses to the entire world. To me they appear to be better flag
            bearers of free software with engineering to back it.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;He then goes through some of the various BSD’s and the specifics on why FreeBSD was the logical
            choice for his situation. But at the end has a great summary on the community as a whole:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Finally - and maybe repeating myself here - I have nothing but praise for the community. Be it BSD
            Now, mailing lists, Reddit, Twitter, LFNW, or SeaGL, people have encouraged me, answered my questions, and
            filed bugs for me. I have been welcomed and made a part of the community with open arms. These reasons are
            (good) enough for me to use FreeBSD and contribute to it.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;BeastieBits&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://opnsense.org/opnsense-16-1-3-released/&quot;&gt;OPNsense 16.1.3 released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Savagedlight/status/700001944547491842&quot;&gt;Copies of
            &quot;FreeBSD Mastery: Specialty Filesystems&quot; seen in the wild&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netgate.com/training/&quot;&gt;pfsense training available in Europe&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ibara/LiteBSD-Ports&quot;&gt;LiteBSD now has 50 ports in its
            ports tree&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://marc.info/?l=openbsd-ports&amp;amp;m=145615281431064&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;Ports
            tree locked for OpenBSD 5.9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blather.michaelwlucas.com/archives/2556&quot;&gt;“FreeBSD Filesystem Fun”
            at March semibug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://oshug.org/event/46&quot;&gt;Event #46 — Embedded Platforms (BSD, OpenWRT,
            Plan 9 &amp;amp; Inferno)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s21lcCKrSB&quot;&gt;Frank - ZFS RAM?&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s204lxjvlq&quot;&gt;David - ARM Porting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2xMiSNLYn&quot;&gt; Johnny - Lumina Default?&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s214gJbLwD&quot;&gt; Adam - PC-BSD Install and Q’s&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s20UNyzEeh&quot;&gt; Jeremy - Video Card Q&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a
            href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Synthesize all the Things!</title>
        <smi:episode>129</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_02_17-synthesize_all_the_things"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_02_17-synthesize_all_the_things</id>
        <published>2016-02-17T16:54:33-08:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-17T12:24:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0129.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="75221555"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0129.ogg"
                    fileSize="75221555"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0129.mp3"
                    fileSize="49795961"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/bsd-0129b-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>JT</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>John Marino</name>
            <email>marino@freebsd.org</email>
        </contributor>
        <summary>Coming up this week, we will be talking to John Marino about his work on the ports-mgmt utility “Synth”
            and the cross-pollination between DragonFly and FreeBSD. That plus the latest news and your email here on
            BSD Now, the place to B… SD!
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 129: Synthesize all the Things!&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.des.no/2016/02/freebsd-and-cve-2015-7547/&quot;&gt;glibc and the
            BSDs &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;You have likely already heard about &lt;a href=&quot;https://access.redhat.com/security/cve/cve-2015-7547&quot;&gt;CVE-2015-7547
            &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“A stack-based buffer overflow was found in the way the libresolv library performed dual A/AAAA
            DNS queries. A remote attacker could create a specially crafted DNS response which could cause libresolv to
            crash or,
            potentially, execute code with the permissions of the user running the library.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“Note: this issue is only exposed when libresolv is called from the nss_dns NSS service module.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://googleonlinesecurity.blogspot.ca/2016/02/cve-2015-7547-glibc-getaddrinfo-stack.html&quot;&gt;More
            details from Google’s Online Security team blog &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“Naturally, people have started asking whether FreeBSD is affected. The FreeBSD Security Officer
            has not yet released an official statement, but in the meantime, here is a brief look at the issue as far as
            FreeBSD is concerned.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“First of all: neither FreeBSD itself nor native FreeBSD applications are affected. While the
            resolver in FreeBSD’s libc and GNU libc share a common parentage, the bug was introduced when the latter was
            rewritten to send A and AAAA queries in parallel rather than sequentially when the application requests
            both.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The same most likely applies to the other BSDs&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“However, Linux applications running under emulation on a FreeBSD system use the GNU libc and are
            therefore vulnerable unless patched.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A patch to update emulation/linux_base-c6 has been prepared and should be committed soon&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Running ‘pkg audit’ will list any known vulnerable packages installed on your system&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“The issue can be mitigated by only using resolvers you trust, and configuring them to avoid
            sending responses which can trigger the bug.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“If you already have your own resolvers, you can configure them to avoid sending UDP responses
            larger than 2048 bytes. If the response does not fit in 2048 bytes, the server will send a truncated
            response, and the client should retry using TCP. While a similar bug exists in the code path for TCP
            requests, I believe that it can only be exploited by a malicious resolver, and interposing your own resolver
            will protect affected Linux systems and applications.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Dag-Erling’s blog post also includes instructions and configuration examples for locking down your
            resolver, or setting up your own resolver if you don’t have one already&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbsdfoundation.org/campaign2016.html&quot;&gt;OpenBSD Foundation -
            2016 Fundraising Campaign&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The OpenBSD foundation has announced their 2016 fundraising campaign, and set the goal of raising
            $250k for the year. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;While they mention that fundraising for 2015 didn’t hit 2014’s blockbuster numbers, it still
            exceeded the goal set, with an almost equal mix of corporate and community donors. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;‘Our goal for 2016 is to increase the amount of support we offer for development, without
            compromising our regular support for the projects. We would like to:
            Plan and support more developer events (hackathons), and allow for more developers to attend these events.
            Continue to improve the project infrastructure.
            Fund more dedicated developer time for targeted development of specific projects.‘&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;To give you an idea of how much OpenBSD technology is used around the world, they broke it down
            this way:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;If $10 were given for every installation of OpenBSD in the last year from the master site (ignoring
            the mirrors) we would be at our goal.
            If $2 were given for every download of the OpenSSH source code in the last year from the master site
            (ignoring the mirrors) we would be at our goal.
            If a penny was donated for every pf or OpenSSH installed with a mainstream operating system or phone in the
            last year we would be at our goal.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sgeos.github.io/freebsd/ion/dtn/2016/02/07/getting-started-with-ion-dtn-3-4-0-on-freebsd.html&quot;&gt;Getting
            Started with ION-DTN 3.4.0 on FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“The Interplanetary Overlay Network (ION) software distribution is an implementation of
            Delay-Tolerant Networking (DTN) architecture as described in Internet RFC 4838, suitable for use in
            spacecraft”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This tutorial covers setting up ION 3.4.0 on FreeBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The tutorial starts by downloading the ION software, and installing the relevant build tools&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The instructions allow ION to be installed system-wide, or for a specific user&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The each host is configured&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Then pings are traded between the hosts to ensure everything works&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Then a web page is served over the interplanetary network&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Sadly I don’t have any hosts on other planets to test with.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The tutorial also includes a troubleshooting guide&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bsdmag.org/download/open_storage/&quot;&gt;Open Storage Issue – New BSD
            Mag is Out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The next issue of BSDMag (The Open Storage Issue) just landed which features an interview with
            Matt Olander of iXsystems. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;During the interview, Matt talks about the culture of support for open-source down at iX, not only
            FreeNAS and PC-BSD, but the FreeBSD foundation, Slackware and more. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;He also gets to extol the virtues of the open-source development model itself, why it tends to
            lead to better code overall. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In addition to the lead interview with Matt, this issue also features some other great interviews
            with Open Source storage vendors, and even some ZFS howto’s about setting up your ZIL devive&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Interview - John Marino - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:marino@freebsd.org&quot;&gt;marino@freebsd.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ixsystems.com/whats-new/2016/02/11/january-missioncomplete-best-story/&quot;&gt;FreeNAS
            with FreeBSD as its base helped save taxpayers $36,000 for a small public school district&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sgeos.github.io/tor/freebsd/nc/curl/2016/02/06/getting-started-with-tor-hidden-services-on-freebsd.html&quot;&gt;Getting
            Started With Tor Hidden Services on FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Ever wondered how to setup and use a Tor hidden service? We have a walkthrough posted over on
            github.io which details how to do that on a FreeBSD -CURRENT system.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The basics are pretty simple, installing security/tor is the first step (although, he is using
            portmaster, you may wish to just ‘pkg install security/tor’)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The walkthrough provides an example server hosting just the date/time on port 8080, which you can
            use as an example and to verify it works, before serving anything real.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Once a local server is ready to serve something, the Tor setup is pretty quick, basically just two
            lines of config in torrc:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;HiddenServiceDir /usr/home/tor/hidden_service/&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;HiddenServicePort 80 127.0.0.1:8080&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;After starting the service, the walkthrough will show you how to get the new hostname for this
            hidden service and verify its functionality. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hughobrien/zfs-remote-mirror&quot;&gt;ZFS Remote Mirrors for
            Home Use&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A recently updated tutorial on remotely mirroring your ZFS files&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Using a spare old computer, or a SBC like a Raspberry Pi, and an (external) hard drive&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It covers installing and configuring FreeBSD for both sides of the remote replication&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The new appendix covers the creation of a Raspberry Pi image, although a prebuilt one is also
            provided&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The setup uses GELI to ensure the data is encrypted at-rest&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Updating and maintaining both systems is covered in detail&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The article is very detailed, and covers pretty much every aspect of the setup, including
            suggestions on where to physically locate the remote system, and configuration tips to reduce the chance
            that local intervention will be required&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Most importantly, it covers the disaster recovery steps. How to get your files back when bad
            things happen&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lumina-desktop.org/lumina-desktop-0-8-8-released/&quot;&gt;Lumina Desktop
            0.8.8 Released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;PC-BSD’s very own Lumina desktop has issued a new release, 0.8.8&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Notable in this release is support for NetBSD out of box, improvements to the start menu, and
            ability to change monitor resolutions in the X configuration tool. (Also the desktop font colors look
            better!)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;0.8.8 is now available in PC-BSD via pkg, and FreeBSD ports/pkg system as well.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fossforce.com/2016/02/lumina-desktop-getting-ready-freebsd-11-0/&quot;&gt;Lumina
            Desktop aims for v1.0 in July 2016&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;We also have a blog post from Larry over at FossForce, highlighting that 1.0 of Lumina is still
            targeted for July(ish)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feyrer.de/NetBSD/bx/blosxom.cgi/nb_20160213_1951.html&quot;&gt;NetBSD
            on Google&#39;s Compute Engine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A NetBSD developer has gotten NetBSD running on Google Compute Engine, a service somewhat similar
            to Amazon’s EC2, and Microsoft’s Azure&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Support is still being worked on, but I imagine it will land in NetBSD before too long&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dmesgd.nycbug.org/index.cgi?action=dmesgd&amp;amp;do=view&amp;amp;id=2900&quot;&gt;NetBSD
            on GCE dmesg &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://marc.info/?l=openbsd-misc&amp;amp;m=138610199311393&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;OpenBSD
            on GCE &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/swills/FreeBSD-gcloud&quot;&gt;FreeBSD on GCE &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;BeastieBits&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hisham.hm/htop/&quot;&gt;htop 2.0 released - an interactive process viewer
            for Unix (including FreeBSD and OpenBSD)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mail-index.netbsd.org/port-arm/2016/01/31/msg003648.html&quot;&gt;Full set
            of binary packages for 7.0 released for ARM v6 and v7 (hf)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dragonflybsd.org/release44/&quot;&gt;DragonFly 4.4.2 released&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://libertybsd.net/&quot;&gt;LibertyBSD 5.8 has been released&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.dragonflybsd.org/pipermail/commits/2016-January/459239.html&quot;&gt;Broadwell
            systems may want to take advantage of the patch by Imre Vadasz&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.viva64.com/en/b/0377/&quot;&gt;Finding the hard-to-spot bugs in FreeBSD
            &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s21dwzoXRn&quot;&gt;Johnny - The Daily Show&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2Hmmu5pUr&quot;&gt; Randy - Let it BSD&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s20tOLsHHj&quot;&gt; Miguel - NullFS &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2N9wQ1n5X&quot;&gt; Jaek - PC-BSD Hardware&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a
            href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The State of BSD</title>
        <smi:episode>128</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_02_10-the_state_of_bsd"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_02_10-the_state_of_bsd</id>
        <published>2016-02-11T09:10:43-08:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-17T12:30:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0128.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="68038137"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0128.ogg"
                    fileSize="68038137"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0128.mp3"
                    fileSize="43505675"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/bsd-0128-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>JT</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Nick Wolff</name>
            <email>darkfiberiru@gmail.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/darkfiberiru</uri>
        </contributor>
        <summary>This week on BSDNow, we interview Nick Wolff about how FreeBSD is used across the State of Ohio &amp;
            some of the specific technology used. That, plus the latest news is coming your way right now on BSDNow, the
            place to B...SD!
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 128: The State of BSD&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.com/business/16/1/scale-14x-interview-dru-lavigne&quot;&gt;Doc
            like an Egyptian: Managing project documentation with Sphinx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In case you didn’t make it out to SCALE a few weeks back, we have a great interview with Dru
            Lavigne over at OpenSource.com which goes over her talk on “Doc like an Egyptian”. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In particular she discusses the challenges of running a wiki for documentation for PC-BSD and
            FreeNAS which prompted the shift to using Sphinx instead.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;“While the main purpose of a wiki is to invite user contributions and to provide a low barrier to
            entry, very few people come to write documentation (however, every spambot on the planet will quickly find
            your wiki, which creates its own set of maintenance issues).&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Wikis are designed for separate, one-ish page infobytes, such as how-tos. They really aren&#39;t
            designed to provide navigation in a Table of Contents or to provide a flow of Chapters, though you can hack
            your pages to provide navigational elements to match the document&#39;s flow. This gets more difficult as
            the document increases in size—our guides tend to be 300+ pages. It becomes a nightmare as you try to
            provide versioned copies of each of those pages so that the user is finding and reading the right page for
            their version of software.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;While wiki translation extensions are available, how to configure them is not well documented,
            their use is slow and clunky, and translated pages only increase the number of available pages, getting you
            back to the problems in the previous bullet. This is a big deal for projects that have a global audience.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;While output-generation wiki extensions are available (for example, to convert your wiki pages to
            HTML or PDF), how to configure them is not well documented, and they provide very little control for the
            layout of the generated format. This is a big deal for projects that need to make their documentation
            available in multiple formats.“&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;She then discusses some of the hurdles of migration from the Wiki to Sphinx, and follows up with
            some of the differences using Sphinx you should be aware of for any documentation project.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;“While Sphinx is easy to learn, it does have its quirks. For example, it does not support stacked
            tags. This means, for example, you can not bold italic a phrase using tags—to achieve that requires a CSS
            workaround. And, while Sphinx does have extensive documentation, a lot of it assumes you already know what
            you are doing. When you don&#39;t, it can be difficult to find an example that does what you are trying to
            achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Sphinx is well suited for projects with an existing repository—say, on github—a build
            infrastructure, and contributors who are comfortable with using text editors and committing to the repo (or
            creating, say, git pull requests).“&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://freebsdfoundation.blogspot.com/2016/02/initial-freebsd-risc-v-architecture.html&quot;&gt;Initial
            FreeBSD RISC-V Architecture Port Committed.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Touching on a story we mentioned a few weeks back, we have a blog post from from Annie over at the
            FreeBSD foundation talking about the details behind the initial support for RISC-V.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;To start us off, you may be wondering what is RISC-V and what makes it special?RISC-V is an
            exciting new open-source Instruction-Set Architecture (ISA) developed at the University of California at
            Berkeley, which is seeing increasing interest in the embedded systems and hardware-software research
            communities.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Currently the improvements allows booting FreeBSD in the Spike simulator, from the university of
            Berkeley, with enough reliability to do various things, such as SSH, shell, mail, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The next steps include getting multi-core support working, and getting it working in simulations
            of Cambridge’s open-source LowRISC System-on-Chip functioning, and ready for early hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Both ports and packages are expected to land in the coming days, so if you love hacking on branch
            new architectures, this may be your time to jump in.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svnweb.freebsd.org/base?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=295124&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            Bhyve hypervisor supporting Windows UEFI guests &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;If you have not been following bhyve lately, you’re in for a treat when FreeBSD 10.3 ships in the
            coming weeks&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;bhyve now supports UEFI and CSM booting, in addition to its existing FreeBSD userboot loader, and
            grub-bhyve port&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The EFI support allows Windows guests to be run on FreeBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Due to the lack of graphics, this requires making a custom .iso to do an ‘Unattended Install’ of
            Windows, but this is easily done just editing and including a .xml file&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The bootrom can now allocate memory&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Added some SATA command emulations (no-op)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Increased the number of virtio-blk indirect descriptors&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Added a Firmware guest query interface&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Add -l option to specify userboot path
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://jameslodge.com/freebsd-bhyve-hypervisor-running-windows-server-2012-r2-standard/&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            Bhyve Hypervisor Running Windows Server 2012 R2 Standard&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In related news, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/tidalscale-releases-its-system-scaling-hyperkernel-300216105.html&quot;&gt;TidalScale
            officially released their product today &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;TidalScale is a commercial product based on bhyve that allows multiple physical machines to be
            combined into a single massive virtual machine, with the combined processor power, memory, disk I/O, and
            network capacity of all of the machines&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unixmen.com/freebsd-tacacs-gns3-and-cisco-3700-router/&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            TACACS+ GNS3 and Cisco 3700 Router&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“TACACS+ – (Terminal Access Controller Access Control System plus) — is a session protocol
            developed by Cisco.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This tutorial covers configuring FreeBSD and the tac_plus4 port to act as an authentication,
            authorization, and accounting server for Cisco routers&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The configuration of FreeBSD, the software, and the router are covered&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It also includes how to set the FreeBSD server up as a VM on windows, and bridge it to the network&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;I am sure there are some network administrators out there that would appreciate this&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Interview - Nick Wolff - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:darkfiberiru@gmail.com&quot;&gt;darkfiberiru@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;
            / &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/darkfiberiru&quot;&gt;@darkfiberiru&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.nycbug.org/pipermail/talk/2016-February/016495.html&quot;&gt;Papers
            We Love Presents : Bryan Cantrill on Jails &amp;amp; Solaris Zones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The folks over at NYCBug point us to “Papers We Love”, a New York based meetup group where past
            papers are presented. They have a talk scheduled for tomorrow (Feb 11th) with Bryan Cantrill discussing
            Jails and Solaris Zones&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The talk starts at 7PM at the Tumblr building, located between 5th and Park Ave South on 21st
            street&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“We&#39;re &lt;strong&gt;crazy&lt;/strong&gt; excited to have Bryan Cantrill, CTO of Joyent,
            formerly of Sun Microsystems, presenting on &lt;a href=&quot;https://us-east.manta.joyent.com/bcantrill/public/ppwl-cantrill-jails.pdf&quot;&gt;Jails:
            Confining the omnipotent root&lt;/a&gt;.
            by Poul-Henning Kamp and Robert Watson and &lt;a href=&quot;https://us-east.manta.joyent.com/bcantrill/public/ppwl-cantrill-zones.pdf&quot;&gt;Solaris
            Zones: Operating System Support for Consolidating Commercial Workloads&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Price and Andy
            Tucker!”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The abstract posted gives us a sneak peak of what to expect, first covering jails as a method to
            “partition” the operating system environment, but maintaining the UNIX “root” model.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Next it looks like he will compare and contrast with the Solaris Zones functionality, which
            creates virtualized application execution environments, within the single OS instance.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Sounds like a fantastic talk, hopefully somebody remembers to record and post it for us to enjoy
            later!&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There will not be a live stream, but a video of the event should appear online after it has been
            edited&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.freebsd.org/201602StorageSummit&quot;&gt;FreeBSD Storage Summit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The FreeBSD Foundation will be hosting a Storage Summit, co-located at the USENIX FAST
            (Filesystems And Storage Technology) conference&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Developers and Vendors are invited to work on storage related issues&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This summit will be a hackathon focused event, rather than a discussion focused devsummit&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;After setup and introductions, the summit will start with a “Networking Synergies Panel”, to
            discuss networking as it relates to storage&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;After a short break, the attendees will break up into a number of working groups focused on
            solving actual problems&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The current working groups include:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;CAM Scheduling &amp;amp; Locking, led by Justin Gibbs: “Updating CAM queuing/scheduling and
            locking models to minimize cross-cpu contention and support multi-queue controllers”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;ZFS, led by Matt Ahrens: topics will include enabling the new cryptographic hashes supported by
            OpenZFS on FreeBSD, Interaction with the kernel memory subsystem, and other upcoming features.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;User Space Storage Stack, led by George Neville-Neil&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This event offers a unique opportunity for developers and vendors from the storage industry to
            meet at an event they will likely already be attending&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.nycbug.org/pipermail/talk/2016-February/016514.html&quot;&gt;Tor
            Browser 5.5 for OpenBSD/amd64 -current is completed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“The Tor BSD Diversity Project (TDP) is proud to announce the release of Tor Browser (TB) version
            5.5 for OpenBSD. Please note that this version of TB remains in development mode, and is not meant to ensure
            strong privacy, anonymity or security.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“TDP (https://torbsd.github.io) is an effort to extend the use of the BSD Unixes into the Tor
            ecosystem, from the desktop to the network. TDP is focused on diversifying the Tor network, with TB being
            the flagship project.
            Additional efforts are made to increase the number of *BSD relays on the Tor network among other
            sub-projects”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Help test the new browser bundle, or help diversify the Tor network&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blather.michaelwlucas.com/archives/2548&quot;&gt;“FreeBSD Mastery:
            Advanced ZFS” Table of Contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We brought you the news about sponsoring the Advanced ZFS book that MWL is working on,
            now Michael has given us the tentative chapter layout of the (sure to be a classic) tome coming from him and
            Allan.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;0: Introduction&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;1: Boot Environments&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;2: Delegation and Jails&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;3: Sharing&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;4: Replication&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;5: zvols&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;6: Advanced Hardware&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;7: Caches&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;8: Performance&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;9: Tuning&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;10: ZFS Potpourri&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the tease about the upcoming book, michael has asked the community for
            assistance in coming up with the cover art for it as well. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In particular it should probably be in-line with his previous works, with a parody of some other
            classic art-work. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;If you have something, go tweet out to him at @mwlauthor&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;Beastie Bits&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2016.asiabsdcon.org/index.html.en&quot;&gt;Online registration
            for AsiaBSDCon 2016 now open &lt;em&gt;SOON&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bhyvecon.org/&quot;&gt;BhyveCon 2016&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nycbug.org/index.cgi?action=view&amp;amp;id=10640&quot;&gt;NYC*BUG
            shell-fu talk slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.dragonflybsd.org/pipermail/users/2016-February/228597.html&quot;&gt;Possible
            regression in DragonFly i915 graphics on older Core2Duos &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://video.fosdem.org/2016/&quot;&gt;Videos from FOSDEM 2016. BSD dev
            room was k4601&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2F39XEu9w&quot;&gt; Andrew - SMART Tests&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s20kk6lzc9&quot;&gt; JT - Secure File Delete&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s21zjZ0ci8&quot;&gt; Jordan - Migrate&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2Hqbt0Uq8&quot;&gt; Lars - Pros and Cons of VM&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2HnO1hxSO&quot;&gt; Alex - IPSEC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a
            href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>DNS, Black Holes &amp; Willem</title>
        <smi:episode>127</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_02_04-dns_blackholes_and_willem"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_02_04-dns_blackholes_and_willem</id>
        <published>2016-02-04T10:05:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-17T12:34:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0127.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="98679390"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0127.ogg"
                    fileSize="98679390"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0127.mp3"
                    fileSize="62398684"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/bsd-0127-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>JT</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Willem Toorop</name>
            <email>willem@nlnetlabs.nl</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/WillemToorop</uri>
        </contributor>
        <summary>Today on the show, we welcome Allan back from FOSSDEM &amp; enjoy an interview with Willem about DNS
            and MTU Black Holes. That plus all the weeks news, keep it turned here to BSD Now, the place to B...SD!
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 127: DNS, Black Holes &amp;amp; Willem&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freebsd.org/news/status/report-2015-10-2015-12.html&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            Quarterly Status Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It is that time of year again, reviewing the progress of the FreeBSD project over the last quarter
            of 2015&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There are a huge number of projects that have recently been completed or that are planned to
            finish in time for FreeBSD 10.3 or 11.0&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This is just a sample of the of the items that stood out most to us:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A number of new teams have been created, and existing teams report in. The Issue Triage,
            bugmeister, jenkins, IPv6 advocacy, and wiki-admin teams are all mentioned in the status report&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Progress is reported on the i915 project to update the Intel graphics drivers&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In the storage subsystem: RCTL I/O rate limiting, Warner Losh’s CAM I/O Scheduler is progressing,
            Mellanox iSCSI Extensions for RDMA (iSER) was added, Chelsio iSCSI offload drivers, Mellanox 100 gbit/s
            drivers&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In Security: Encrypted crash dumps, OpenBSM updates, and a status report on HardenedBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;For embedded: Support for Ralink/Mediatek MIPS devices, Raspberry Pi Video Code packages, touch
            screen support for RPI and BBB, new port to the Marvell Armada38x, and the work on arm64 and RISC-V&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;kib@ rewrote the out-of-memory handler, specifically to perform better in situations where a
            system does not have swap. Was tested on systems ranging from 32 MB of memory, to 512 GB&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Various improvements to the tool chain, build system, and nanobsd&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It was nice to see a bunch of reports from ports committers&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;An overview of the different proposed init replacements, with a report on each&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sarah.thesharps.us/2016/02/02/first-timers-guide-to-foss-conferences/&quot;&gt;First
            timer’s guide to FOSS conferences &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This post provides a lot of good information for those considering going to their first conference&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The very first item says the most: “Conference talks are great because they teach you new skills
            or give you ideas. However, what conference talks are really for is giving you additional topics of
            conversation to chat with your fellow conference goers with. Hanging out after a talk ends to chat with the
            speaker is a great way to connect with speakers or fellow attendees that are passionate about a particular
            subject.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The hallway track is the best part of the conference. I’ve ended up missing as much as 2/3rds of a
            conference, and still found it to be a very valuable conference, sometimes more so than if I attend a talk
            in every slot&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It is important to remember that missing a talk is not the end of the world, that discussion in
            the hallway may be much more valuable. Most of the talks end up on youtube anyway. The point of the
            conference is being in the same place as the other people at the conference, the talks are just a means to
            get us all there.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There is even a lot of good advice for people with social anxiety, and those like Allan who do not
            partake in alcohol&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Know the conference perks and the resources available to you. The author of the post commented on
            twitter about originally being unaware of the resources that some conferences provide for speakers, but also
            of discounts for students, and travel grants from Google and others like the FreeBSD Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There are also tips about swag, including watching out for booth wranglers (not common at BSD
            events, but many larger conferences have booths where your personal information can be exchanged for swag),
            as well as advice for following up with the people you meet at conferences.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Lastly, it provides thoughts on avoiding “Project Passion Explosion“, or what I call “overcharging
            your BSD battery”, where after hearing about the interesting stuff other people are doing, or about the
            things other need, you try to do everything at once, and burn yourself out&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;I know for myself, there are at least 10 projects I would love to work on, but I need to balance
            my free time, my work schedule, the FreeBSD release schedule, and which items might be better for someone
            else to work on.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unixmen.com/freebsd-10-1-x64-wifi-captive-portal/&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            10.1 based WiFi Captive Portal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Captive portals, the bane of many a traveler’s existence, however a necessary evil in the era of
            war-driving and other potentially nefarious uses of “free-wifi”. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This week we have an article from the folks at “unixmen”, showing (in great detail) how they setup
            a FreeBSD 10.1 based captive portal, and yes those are manual MySQL commands.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;First up is a diagram showing the layout of their new portal system, using multiple APs for
            different floors of the apartment / hotel?&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The walkthrough assumes you have Apache/MySQL and PHP already installed, so you’ll need to prep
            those bits beforehand.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Some Apache configuration is up next, which re-directs all port 80 requests over to 443/SSL and
            the captive portal web-login&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;At this point we have to install “pear” from ports or packages and begin to do the database setup
            which is fairly typical if you done any SQL before, such as create user / database / table, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;With the database finished, the article provides a nice and clean rc.conf which enables all the
            necessary services.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Next up is the firewall configuration, which is using IPFW, specifically DUMMYNET/IPALIAS/IPDIVERT
            and friends. The article does mention to compile a new minimal kernel with these features, if you plan on
            doing so they I would recommend starting off with that. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The article then continues, with setting up DHCP server, SUDO and the PHP file creation that will
            act as the interface between the client and mysql/firewall rules. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;When it’s all said and done, you end up with a nice web-interface for clients, plus a bonus Admin
            interface to manage creating and removing users. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;For convenience at the very end is a link to all the files / configurations used, so grab that and
            avoid some of the copy-n-paste&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NetBSDfr/sailor&quot;&gt;Sailor, a &#39;wannabe&#39; portable
            container system {their own words!}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In the world of docker / jails / VMs, containers are all the rage right now, and now we can
            introduce “Sailor” to this mix&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A unique thing about this new solution, is that its based upon chroot/pkgin, and available on
            NetBSD / OSX and CentOS&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Since it is not using “jail” or other security mechanism, they to give us this cavet “Note that
            sailor&#39;s goal is not to provide bullet-proof security, chroot is definitely not a trustable isolator;
            instead, sailor is a really convenient way of trying / testing an environment without compromising your
            workstation filesystem.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Creating a new “ship” is relatively straight-forward, a simple shell define file can supply most
            of the relevant information. Nginx for example is only a few lines:
            https://github.com/NetBSDfr/sailor/blob/master/examples/nginx.conf &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In addition to the basic pkg configuration, it also provides methods to do rw/ro mounts into the
            chroot, as well as IP aliases and copying of specific host binaries into the container&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Interview - Willem Toorop - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:willem@nlnetlabs.nl&quot;&gt;willem@nlnetlabs.nl&lt;/a&gt;
            / &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/WillemToorop&quot;&gt;@WillemToorop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;GetDNS&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=73M7h56Dsas&quot;&gt;vBSDCon 2015 Talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.tuhs.org/doku.php?id=publications:quarter_century_of_unix&quot;&gt;A
            Quarter Century of Unix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;An oldie, but goodie, the book “A Quarter Century of UNIX” is now available for free download via
            PDF format. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This provides an invaluable look into the history of UNIX, which of course we wouldn’t have BSD
            without. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There is also a print version still available via Amazon (link at the above URL also). If you find
            the book useful, consider buying a copy, since a % still goes to the original author&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freebsdfoundation.org/press/2016janupdate.pdf&quot;&gt;Bjoern Zeeb
            has been awarded grant to finalize VIMAGE fixes &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“Bjoern Zeeb has been awarded a project grant to finalize and integrate the work done to make the
            VIMAGE network stack virtualization infrastructure production ready.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;VIMAGE is the network virtualization kernel component that can be used to give jails their own
            network interfaces, so they can have their own firewalls, be assign addresses via DHCP, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Currently, a number of bugs prevent this feature from being enabled by default, or used in
            production&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The main areas of focus for the work are: network stack teardown, interface ordering, locking, and
            addressing the remaining memory leaks at teardown&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The work is expected to be completed by the end of March and to be included in FreeBSD 11.0&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbsd.org/opensmtpd/faq/example1.html&quot;&gt;Building a smtpd Mail
            Server on OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The OpenSMTPd FAQ has been updated with a new walkthrough of a complete installation&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Following this guide, the resulting installation will:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Accepting mails for multiple domains and virtual users&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Allowing virtual users to authenticate and send mails&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Applying anti-spam and anti-virus filters on mails&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Providing IMAP access for the virtual users&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Providing log statistics&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It covers setting up the new filter system, configuring TLS, creating the domain and user tables,
            configuring spamassassin and clamav, and setting up dovecot&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There is even a crontab to send you weekly stats on what your email server is doing&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.informit.com/store/introduction-to-the-freebsd-open-source-operating-system-9780134305868&quot;&gt;Introduction
            to the FreeBSD Open Source Operating System LiveLessons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Dr. Kirk McKusick has been one of the foremost authorities on FreeBSD for some time now, as
            co-author of the D&amp;amp;I of FreeBSD (along with George Neville-Neil and Robert Watson) and teaching
            numerous classes on the same. (Another good reason to come to a *BSD conference)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;As part of the Addison-Wesley Professional / LiveLessons series, he has made a 10+ hour video
            lecture you can now purchase to take his class from the comfort of your own home/couch/office/etc&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Aspiring FreeBSD developers, kernel developers, Application Developers and other interested
            individuals should really consider this invaluable resource in their learning.

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The video starts with an introduction to the FreeBSD community and explains how it differs from
            the Linux ecosystem. The video then goes on to provide a firm background in the FreeBSD kernel. The POSIX
            kernel interfaces are used as examples where they are defined. Where they are not defined, the FreeBSD
            interfaces are described.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The video covers basic kernel services, locking, process structure, scheduling, signal handling,
            jails, and virtual and physical memory management.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The kernel I/O structure is described showing how I/O is multiplexed and the virtual filesystem
            interface is used to support multiple filesystems.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Devices are described showing disk management and their auto-configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The organization and implementation of the fast filesystem is described concluding with a
            discussion of how to maintain consistency in the face of hardware or software failures.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The video includes an overview of the ZFS filesystem and covers the socket-based network
            architecture, layering and routing issues.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The presentations emphasize code organization, data structure navigation, and algorithms.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Normally the video will set you back $299, but right now you can pick it up for $239 (USD). We
            can’t recommend this enough, but also don’t forget to try and make it out to BSDCan or MeetBSD, where you
            can usually talk to Dr. McKusick in person.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;BeastieBits&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://freebsdfoundation.blogspot.ca/2016/01/faces-of-freebsd-2016-sean-bruno.html&quot;&gt;Faces
            of FreeBSD: Sean Bruno &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blather.michaelwlucas.com/archives/2539&quot;&gt;Support Michael
            W. Lucas writing BSD books, and get your name in the credits &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svnweb.freebsd.org/base?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=295124&quot;&gt;bhyve
            windows support merged to stable/10 branch, will be included in FreeBSD 10.3 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/01/ea-lets-slip-lifetime-xbox-one-and-ps4-consoles-sales/&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            Outsells Windows by almost 2-1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fanf.livejournal.com/140505.html&quot;&gt;A rant about the whois
            protocol&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bsdtalk.blogspot.com/2016/01/bsdtalk261-jails-and-system-management.html&quot;&gt;Kris
            Moore talks about Jails and system management on BSDTalk&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2016/schedule/event/illumos_overview/attachments/audio/873/export/events/attachments/illumos_overview/audio/873/FOSDEM_2016.pdf&quot;&gt;FOSDEM
            2016: Slides from the 5 years of IllumOS talk &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pvaneynd/status/693813132649697281&quot;&gt;A tweet
            from the first day of FOSDEM showed only 1 FreeBSD machine. Many of the FreeBSD developers were at a
            devsummit offsite that day, and more users arrived for the BSD dev room which was on the Sunday &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/ZWNHgqHQ&quot;&gt; Antonio - ZFS Book Formatting&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/XW97YSQK&quot;&gt; Simon - ZFS Corruption?&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/W7TwWwtE&quot;&gt; Christian - rm -r^^^OOOPSSS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/zA2ewPuF&quot;&gt; Phillipp - ZFS Send/Recv&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a
            href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
