<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed
        xml:lang="en-us"
        xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
        xmlns:smi="https://www.betterfeeds.org/series-media-info"
        xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
        xmlns:psc="http://podlove.org/simple-chapters">
    <title>BSD Now</title>
    <subtitle>A weekly show covering the latest developments in the world of the BSD family of operating systems. News,
        Tutorials and Interviews for new users and long time developers alike.
    </subtitle>
    <icon>http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/images/bsdnow-badge.jpg</icon>
    <media:thumbnail
            url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/images/bsdnow-badge.jpg"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow/bsdnow-2016-01.atom"
            rel="self"
            type="application/atom+xml"
            title="BSD Now"/>
    <link
            href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/"
            rel="alternate"
            type="text/html"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowMp3"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now MP3 Audio"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowOgg"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now OGG Audio"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowMobile"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now SD Video"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowHd"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now HD Video"/>
    <link
            href="http://bitlove.org/jupiterbroadcasting/bsdnowhd/feed"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now HD Video (BitTorrent)"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow/bsdnow-2016-02.atom"
            rel="previous"
            type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow/bsdnow-2015-12.atom"
            rel="next"
            type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow.atom"
            rel="first"
            type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow/bsdnow-2013-09.atom"
            rel="last"
            type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/</id>
    <updated>2016-06-18T08:43:00Z</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Jupiter Broadcasting</name>
        <uri>www.jupiterbroadcasting.com</uri>
    </author>
    <smi:sequential>false</smi:sequential>
    <entry>
        <title>Illuminating the future on PC-BSD</title>
        <smi:episode>126</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_01_27-illuminating_the_future_on_pcbsd"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_01_27-illuminating_the_future_on_pcbsd</id>
        <published>2016-01-28T07:59:38-08:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-18T08:24:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0126.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="82564037"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0126.ogg"
                    fileSize="82564037"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0126.mp3"
                    fileSize="52279683"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/bsd-0126-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>JT</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
        </contributor>
        <summary>This week on BSDNow, we are going to be talking to Ken Moore about the Lumina desktop environment,
            where it stands now and looking ahead. Then Allan turns the tables and interviews both myself and Ken about
            new ongoings in PC-BSD land. Stay tuned, lots of exciting show is coming your way right now on BSDNow, the
            place to B...SD!
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 126: Illuminating the future on PC-BSD&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxvoice.com/group-test-nas-distros/&quot;&gt;Linuxvoice reviews
            six NAS designed OSes and states that FreeNAS has the largest amount of features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The review compares the features of: FreeNAS, NAS4Free, Open Media Vault, Openfiler Community
            Edition, EasyNAS, and Turnkey Linux File Server&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“Many NAS solutions can do a lot more than just back up and restore files – you can extend them
            with plugins to do a variety of tasks. Some enable you to stream media to computers and others devices.
            Others can hook up with apps and services and allow them to use the NAS for storing and retrieving data”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Open Media Vault: 4/5, “A feature-rich NAS distro that’s easy to deploy and manage”. Many plugins,
            good UI&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Turnkey Linux File Server: 2/5, “A no-fuss distro that’ll set up a fully functional file sharing
            server in no time”. No RAID, LVM must be down manually&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Openfiler Community Edition: 1/5, “There is a target segment for Openfiler, but we can’t spot it”.
            In the middle of rebasing on CentOS, lacking documentation, confusing UI&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;EasyNAS: 3/5, “A simple NAS distro that balances the availability of features with reasonable
            assumptions”. Major updates require reinstall, lacks advanced features and advanced protocols&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;FreeNAS: 3/5, “FreeNAS The most feature-rich NAS distribution requires some getting used to”. Best
            documentation, best snapshot management, most plugins, jailed plugins, most enterprise features&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;NAS4Free: 3/5, “NAS4Free An advanced NAS distro that’s designed for advanced users”, additional
            flexibility with disk layout (partition the first disk to install the OS there, use remaining space for data
            storage)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“If we had to award this group test to the distro with the biggest number of features then the top
            two challengers would have been FreeNAS and its proteg&#233;e NAS4Free. While both of these solutions pitch
            themselves to users outside the corporate environment, they’d simply be overkill for most home users.
            Furthermore, their FreeBSD base and the ZFS filesystem, while a boon to enterprise users, virtually makes
            them alien technology to the average Linux household.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It is not clear why they gave NAS4Free and FreeNAS the same score when they wrote a list of
            reasons why FreeNAS was better.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It seems the goal of their rundown was to find the best Linux NAS, not the best NAS.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unixmen.com/freebsd-snort-ips/&quot;&gt;FreeBSD based Snort IPS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;UnixMen.com provides a new tutorial on setting up Snort, the IPS (Intrusion Prevention system) on
            FreeBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Install Apache, PHP, and MySQL, then Snort&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Download the latest Snort rules from the official website&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Disable the Packet Filter on the USB interfaces to avoid issues with Snort&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Install oinkmaster and barnyard2, and configure them&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Then install the Snorby WEB interface, which will give you a nice overview of the data generated
            by the IPS&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Then install SnortSAM, and connect it to ipfw&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Now when Snort detects a potential intrusion, it will be displayed in Snorby, and automatically
            blocked with IPFW&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.com/life/16/1/3-new-open-source-contributors-share-their-experiences&quot;&gt;Opensource.com
            features two BSD developers as examples of how open source can help your career&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“When contributing to open source projects and communities, one of the many benefits is that you
            can improve your tech skills. In this article, hear from three contributors on how their open source helped
            them get a job or improved their career.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Alexander Yurchenko, an OpenBSD developer who now works at Yandex says: “Participating in such a
            project yields colossal experience. A good, large open source project has everything that is typically
            required from a developer at job interviews: good planning, good coding, use of versioning systems and bug
            trackers, peer reviews, teamwork, and such. So, after stewing in such an environment for a year or two, you
            have a good opportunity to grow to a senior developer level.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“That is, in fact, what happened to me. I was hired as a senior developer without having any
            formal work experience on my service record. After the first week, my probation period was reduced from
            three months to zero.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;While you may not have “formal work experience”, you do have a body of work, a
            (code/documentation/etc) portfolio, you can point to&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Having spent a year working somewhere may say something about you, but showing some code you wrote
            that other people use every day, is usually more valuable&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Alexander Polyakov, a DragonFly contributor, worked on updating support for other languages and on
            ACPI.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“I even made some money in the process—a customer found me via git log. He wanted to use
            DragonFlyBSD in production and needed better ACPI support and some RAID driver or something.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“In a nutshell, contributing to various open source projects is how you gain great experience. Don&#39;t
            be afraid to send in bad code (happens to the best of us), keep calm (while being scolded for sending in
            that bad code), and choose projects you are really interested in. Then you&#39;ll both gain experience and
            have fun while you doing it.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Kirill Gorkunov talks about his experience with turning open source into a career: “For a few
            years, I&#39;ve been fixing the code, sending patches, getting scolded for bad code and complimented for
            good code. That experience was priceless. And you can be sure that as soon as you get good at it, job offers
            will follow. This is, in fact, how I met the kernel developers working on OpenVZ. Together, we decided to
            continue working on the OpenVZ kernel and related stuff as well”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;When you contribute to open source, you end up being the person who wrote “Foo”, and this can
            often turn into work, when someone wants to build something with “Foo”, or like “Foo”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This same point was focus of a panel the FreeBSD Foundation organized at the womENcourage
            conference in Sweden last year: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p7PW1E3IJvY&quot;&gt;Open
            Source as a Career Path
            &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.freebsd.org/BernardSpil/LetsEncrypt&quot;&gt;FreeBSD, LibreSSL and
            LetsEncrypt oh my!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Over on the FreeBSD Wiki, Bernard Spil (whom we’ve interviewed before) has started a walkthrough
            talking about how he uses LibreSSL and LetsEncrypt, without using the heavy python client&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The article provides detailed instructions on prepping the system and automating the process of
            updating the SSL certificates&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;If you’ve used the “official” letsencrypt client in the past, you’ll note some differences in his
            method, which keeps all the ‘acme-challenge’ files in a single-directory, which is aliased into domains.
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Using this method also drops the requirement to run the letsencrypt auth as root, and allows you
            to run it as the unprivileged “letsencrypt” user instead. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;He mentions that the bash/zsh scripts used may be added to ports at some point as well&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Interview - Ken Moore &amp;amp; Kris Moore - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ken@pcbsd.org&quot;&gt;ken@pcbsd.org&lt;/a&gt;
            / &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris&quot;&gt;@pcbsdkris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;PC-BSD’s new SysAdm Project and Lumina Update&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.dragonflybsd.org/pipermail/commits/2016-January/459241.html&quot;&gt;DragonFly
            Intel i915 support to match what’s in the Linux 4.1 kernel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In DragonFly’s ongoing quest for DRM awesomeness, they have now merged changes to bring them up to
            Linux 4.1 kernel features. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Some of the notables include that “Valleyview” support is greatly improved, and not considered
            preliminary anymore&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Skylake got some support improvements as well, including runtime power management, and that turbo
            and sleep states should be functional. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Some great improvements to power usage have been added, such as setting GPU frequencies to
            hardware minimum and enabling of DRRS (Dynamic Refresh Rate Switching) being enabled by default&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;They’ve even begun importing some of the prelim work for Broxton, the upcoming Atom SOC&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ramsdenj.github.io/server/2016/01/01/FreeNAS-Server-Build.html&quot;&gt;FreeNAS
            Home Server Build&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;We have a nice article to share with you this week by John Ramsden, which walks us through his
            home-brew FreeNAS server setup.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;As is typical with most home users, he will be using the system to both serve media, and as a
            backup target for other systems.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;His hardware setup is pretty impressive for a home-brew, made up of the following:

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Fractal Design Node 804 Chassis&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Supermicro X10SL7-F Motherboard&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Xeon E3-1231 v3 CPU&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;4x Samsung DDR3 1.35v-1600 M391B1G73QH0 RAM&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;2x 32GB SATA III SMC DOM Boot Drive&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;SeaSonic G-550 Power Supply&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Cyberpower CP1500PFCLCD 1500VA 900W PFC UPS&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;6x Western Digital 6TB Red HDD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;2 x ENERMAX T.B. Silence UCTB12P Case Fan&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;3x Noctua NF-P14s redux-1200 Case Fan&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The SATA DOM was neat to see in use, in his case in a mirror&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;He then walks us through his burn-in process, which involved memory testing for 46 hours, and then
            disk testing with the smartctl long tests. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is even details on how the fan thresholds were set up, which may be of use to other
            DiY’ers out there. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The SATA DOM was neat to see in use, in his case in a mirror&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;He then walks us through his burn-in process, which involved memory testing for 46 hours, and then
            disk testing with the smartctl long tests. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There is even details on how the fan thresholds were set up, which may be of use to other DiY’ers
            out there. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bwesterb/claviger&quot;&gt;claviger manages your SSH
            authorized_keys files for you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;An application to manage your SSH authorized_keys files for you&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Make a list of your keys (laptop, desktop, work)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Then a list of your ssh accounts&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;List which keys should be present, and which should be absent&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Optional setting to keep all “other” keys, such as those added by other users&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Optional list of specific “other” keys to allow (does not add them, but does not remove them if
            they are present)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;You say say ‘server2 like server1’, and it will inherit all of the settings from that server&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There is a “default” server, that all others inherit&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unixmen.com/openvpn-ad-authentication-with-crypt/&quot;&gt;FreeBSD 9.2
            x64 OpenVPN AD authentication with crypt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A few days back unixmen.com posted a nice tutorial walkthrough of a OpenVPN setup on FreeBSD 9.2
            using Active Directory for auth&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In this particular setup, FreeBSD is running the gateway / OpenVPN server, the client desktops are
            running Windows 7 and domain controller on Windows 2008&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The setup on FreeBSD pretty straightforward, thanks to the openvpn-auth-ldap port. (Unknown why
            they didn’t use the package)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In addition to showing the details on how configuration was done on BSD, what makes this
            walkthrough nice is the addition of so many screenshots of how the windows configuration was done. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Part of the walkthrough will also detail how they created their .ovpn files for importing on the
            OpenVPN clients. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;Beastie Bits&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cvsweb.netbsd.org/bsdweb.cgi/src/share/mk/bsd.own.mk.diff?r1=1.883&amp;amp;r2=1.884&amp;amp;only_with_tag=MAIN&amp;amp;f=h&quot;&gt;dtrace
            included by default in NetBSD&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fosdem.org/2016/schedule/track/bsd/&quot;&gt;FOSDEM16 is approaching, get
            ready to follow the BSD devroom&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://undeadly.org/cgi?action=article&amp;amp;sid=20160123165549&quot;&gt;Call
            for testing: Concurrent: malloc(3) calls (to speed up Firefox)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://daemonforums.org/showthread.php?p=57767&quot;&gt;&quot;With the PV drivers
            in -CURRENT, it is now possible to run OpenBSD within AWS.&quot;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcbsd.org/doc-archive/10.2/html-es/pcbsd.html&quot;&gt;PC-BSD Handbook
            in Spanish&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/WLpHzz3F&quot;&gt; Clint - ZIL on Partition&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/1QFZU2Bz&quot;&gt; Federico - LibreSSL and DMA&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/aesVaKG4&quot;&gt; Ghislain - FreeBSD vs Linux vs Illumos&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/x4DRHP0i&quot;&gt; Cary - ZFS - Caching - Replication&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a
            href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>DevSummits, Core and the Baldwin</title>
        <smi:episode>125</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_01_20-devsummits_core_and_the_baldwin"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_01_20-devsummits_core_and_the_baldwin</id>
        <published>2016-01-21T10:07:21-08:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-18T08:30:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0125.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="98491440"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0125.ogg"
                    fileSize="98491440"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0125.mp3"
                    fileSize="64426413"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/bsd-0125-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>JT</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>John Baldwin</name>
            <email>jhb@freebsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/BSDHokie</uri>
        </contributor>
        <summary>This week on the show, we will be talking to FreeBSD developer &amp; former core-team member John
            Baldwin about a variety of topics, including everything you wanted or needed to know about running a
            DevSummit. Coming up right now on BSDNow, the place to B...SD!
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 125: DevSummits, Core and the Baldwin&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2016/01/14/server_retired_after_18_years_and_ten_months_beat_that_readers/&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            server retired after almost 19 years&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;We’ve heard stories about this kind of thing before, that box that often sits under-appreciated,
            but refuses to die. Well the UK register has picked up on a story of a FreeBSD server finally being retired
            after almost 19 years of dedicated service.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;“In its day, it was a reasonable machine - 200MHz Pentium, 32MB RAM, 4GB SCSI-2 drive,” Ross
            writes. “And up until recently, it was doing its job fine.” Of late, however the “hard drive finally started
            throwing errors, it was time to retire it before it gave up the ghost!” The drive&#39;s a Seagate, for those
            of you looking to avoid drives that can&#39;t deliver more than 19 years of error-free operations.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This system in particular had been running FreeBSD 2.2.1 over the years. Why not upgrade you ask?
            Ross has an answer for that:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;“It was heavily firewalled and only very specific services were visible to anyone, and most only
            visible to our directly connected customers,” Ross told Vulture South. “By the time it was probably due for
            a review, things had moved so far that all the original code was so tightly bound to the operating system
            itself, that later versions of the OS would have (and ultimately, did) require substantial rework. While it
            was running and not showing any signs of stress, it was simply expedient to leave sleeping dogs lie.”&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;All in all, an amazing story of the longevity of a system and its operating system. Do you have a
            server with a similar or even greater uptime? Let us know so we can try and top this story.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxvoice.com/group-test-bsd-distros/&quot;&gt;Roundup of all the
            BSDs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The magazine LinuxVoice recently did a group test of a variety of “BSD Distros”.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Included in their review were Free/Open/Net/Dragon/Ghost/PC&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It starts with a pretty good overview of BSD in general, its starts and the various projects /
            forks that spawned from it, such as FreeNAS / Junos / Playstation / PFSense / etc&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The review starts with a look at OpenBSD, and the consensus reached is that it is good, but does
            require a bit more manual work to run as a desktop. (Most of the review focuses on desktop usage). It ends
            up with a solid ⅘ stars though. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Next it moves into GhostBSD, discusses it being a “Live” distro, which can optionally be installed
            to disk. It loses a few points for lacking a graphical package management utility, and some bugs during the
            installation, but still earns a respectable ⅗ stars.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Dragonfly gets the next spin and gets praise for its very-up to date video driver support and
            availability of the HAMMER filesystem. It also lands at ⅗ stars, partly due to the reviewer having to use
            the command-line for management. (Notice a trend here?)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;NetBSD is up next, and gets special mention for being one of the only “distros” that doesn’t do
            frequent releases. However that doesn’t mean you can’t have updated packages, since the review mentions
            pkgsrc and pkg as both available to customize your desktop. The reviewer was slightly haunted by having to
            edit files in /etc by hand to do wireless, but still gives NetBSD a ⅗ overall. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Last up are FreeBSD and PC-BSD, which get a different sort of head-to-head review. FreeBSD goes
            first, with mention that the text-install is fairly straight-forward and most configuration will require
            being done by hand. However the reviewer must be getting use to the command-line at this point, because he
            mentions:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;“This might sound cumbersome, but is actually pretty straightforward and at the end produces a
            finely tuned aerodynamic system that does exactly what you want it to do and nothing else.”&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;He does mention that FreeBSD is the ultimate DIY system, even to the point of not having the
            package management tools provided out of box. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;PC-BSD ultimately gets a lot of love in this review, again with it being focused on desktop usage
            this follows. Particularly popular are all the various tools written to make PC-BSD easier to use, such as
            Life-Preserver, Warden, the graphical installer and more. (slight mistake though, Life-Preserver does not
            use rsync to backup to FreeNAS, it does ZFS replication)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In the end he rates FreeBSD ⅘ and PC-BSD a whopping 5/5 for this roundup. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;While reviews may be subjective to the particular use-case being evaluated for, it is still nice
            to see BSD getting some press and more interest from the Linux community in general. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tedunangst.com/flak/post/openbsd-laptops&quot;&gt;OpenBSD Laptops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Our buddy Ted Unangst has posted a nice “planning ahead” guide for those thinking of new laptops
            for 2016 and the upcoming OpenBSD 5.9&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;He starts by giving us a status update on several of the key driver components that will be in 5.9
            release“5.9 will be the first release to support the graphics on Broadwell CPUs. This is anything that looks
            like i5-5xxx. There are a few minor quirks, but generally it works well. There’s no support for the new
            Skylake models, however. They’ll probably work with the VESA driver but minus suspend/resume/acceleration
            (just as 5.8 did with Broadwell).”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;He then goes on to mention that the IWM driver works well with most of the revisions (7260, 7265,
            and 3160) that ship with broadwell based laptops, however the newer skylake series ships with the 8260,
            which is NOT yet supported.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;He then goes on to list some of the more common makes and models to look for, starting with the
            broadwell based X1 carbons which work really well (Kris gives +++), but make sure its not the newer skylake
            model just yet.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The macbook gets a mention, but probably should be avoided due to broadcom wifi&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The Dell XPS he mentions as a good choice for a powerful (portable) desktops&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netbsd.org/changes/changes-8.0.html&quot;&gt;Significant changes from
            NetBSD 7.0 to 8.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Updated to GCC 4.8.5&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Imported dhcpcd and replaced rtsol and rtsold&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;gpt(8) utility gained the ability to resize partitions and disks, as well as change the type of a
            partition&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;OpenSSH 7.1 and OpenSSL 1.0.1q&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;FTP client got support for SNI for https&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Imported dtrace from FreeBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Add syscall support&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Add lockstat support&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Interview - John Baldwin - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jhb@freebsd.org&quot;&gt;jhb@freebsd.org&lt;/a&gt;
            / &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BSDHokie&quot;&gt;@BSDHokie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;FreeBSD Kernel Debugging&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dragonflydigest.com/2016/01/18/17508.html&quot;&gt;Dragonfly Mail
            Agent spreads to FreeBSD and NetBSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;DMA, the Dragonfly Mail Agent is now available not only in Dragonfly’s dports, but also FreeBSD
            ports, and NetBSD pkgsrc&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“dma is a small Mail Transport Agent (MTA), designed for home and office use. It accepts mails
            from locally installed Mail User Agents (MUA) and delivers the mails either locally or to a remote
            destination. Remote delivery includes several features like TLS/SSL support and SMTP authentication. dma is
            not intended as a replacement for real, big MTAs like sendmail(8) or postfix(1). Consequently, dma does not
            listen on port 25 for incoming connections.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There was a project looking at importing DMA into the FreeBSD base system to replace sendmail, I
            wonder of the port signals that some of the blockers have been fixed&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svnweb.freebsd.org/base?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=294068&quot;&gt;ZFS
            UEFI Support has landed!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Originally started by Eric McCorkle&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Picked up by Steven Hartland&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Including modularizing the existing UFS boot code, and adding ZFS boot code&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;General improvements to the EFI loader including using more of libstand instead of containing its
            own implementations of many common functions&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Thanks to work by Toomas Soome, there is now a Beastie Menu as part of the EFI loader, similar to
            the regular loader&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;As soon as this was committed, I added a few lines to it to connect the ZFS BE Menu to it, thanks
            to all of the above, without whom my work wouldn’t be usable&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It should be relatively easy to hook my GELI boot stuff in as a module, and possibly just stack
            the UFS and ZFS modules on top of it&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;I might try to redesign the non-EFI boot code to use a similar design instead of what I have now&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=article&amp;amp;item=3bsd-10linux&quot;&gt;How
            three BSD OSes compare to ten Linux Distros&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;After benchmarking 10 of the latest Linux distros, Phoronix took to benchmarking 3 of the big BSDs&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;DragonFlyBSD 4.4.1 - The latest DragonFly release with GCC 5.2.1 and the HAMMER file-system.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;OpenBSD 5.8 - OpenBSD 5.8 with GCC 4.2.1 as the default compiler and FFS file-system.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;PC-BSD 10.2 - Derived off FreeBSD 10.2, the defaults were the Clang 3.4.1 compiler and ZFS
            file-system.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In the SQLite test, PCBSD+ZFS won out over all of the Linux distros, including those that were
            also using ZFS&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In the first compile benchmark, PCBSD came second only to Intel’s Linux distro, Clear Linux.
            OpenBSD can last, although it is not clear if the benchmark was just comparing the system compiler, which
            would be unfair to OpenBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In Disk transaction performance, against ZFS won the day, with PCBSD edging out the Linux distros.
            OpenBSD’s older ffs was hurt by the lack of soft updates, and DragonFly’s Hammer did not perform well.
            Although in an fsync() heavy test, safety is more important that speed&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;As with all benchmarks, these obviously need to be taken with a grain of salt&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In some of them you can clearly see that the ‘winner’ has a much higher standard error, suggesting
            that the numbers are quite variable&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://opnsense.org/opnsense-15-7-24-released/&quot;&gt;OPNSense 15.7.24
            Released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;We are just barely into the new year and OPNSense has dropped a new release on us to play with.
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This new version, 15.7.24 brings a bunch of notable changes, which includes improvements to the
            firewall UI and a plugin management section of the firmware page. Additionally better signature verification
            using PKG’s internal verification mechanisms was added for kernel and world updates.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The announcement contains the full rundown of changes, including the suricata, openvpn and ntp got
            package bumps as well. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;Beastie Bits&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cooltrainer.org/a-freebsd-desktop-howto/&quot;&gt;A FreeBSD 10 Desktop
            How-to&lt;/a&gt; (A bit old, but still one of the most complete walkthroughs of a desktop FreeBSD setup from
            scratch)&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fossforce.com/2016/01/bsd-ready-scale-14x/&quot;&gt;BSD and Scale 14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://undeadly.org/cgi?action=article&amp;amp;sid=20160114113445&amp;amp;mode=expanded&quot;&gt;Xen
            support enabled in OpenBSD -current&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s20a0mLaAv&quot;&gt; Matt - Zil Sizes&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s21qpiTF8h&quot;&gt; Drin - IPSEC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2HCq0r0aD&quot;&gt; John - ZFS + UEFI&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2VORfyqlS&quot;&gt; Jake - ZFS Cluster SAN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s20ycRhUkM&quot;&gt; Phillip - Media Server&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a
            href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Get your engine(x) started!</title>
        <smi:episode>124</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2015_01_12-get_your_engine_x_started"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2015_01_12-get_your_engine_x_started</id>
        <published>2016-01-14T10:58:27-08:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-18T08:36:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0124.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="57161594"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0124.ogg"
                    fileSize="57161594"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0124.mp3"
                    fileSize="36398488"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/bsd-0124-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>JT</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Igor Sysoev</name>
            <email>igor@sysoev.ru</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/isysoev</uri>
        </contributor>
        <summary>This week on the show, we have a very full news roster to rundown, plus an oldie, but goodie with Igor
            of the nginx project. That plus all your questions and feedback, keep it tuned to BSDNow, the place to
            B...SD!
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 124: Get your engine(x) started!&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.randi.io/2015/12/31/the-developer-formerly-known-as-freebsdgirl/&quot;&gt;Clearing
            the air &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A number of you have written in the past few weeks asking why Allan and I didn’t talk about one of
            the biggest stories to make headlines last week. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Both of us are quite aware of the details surrounding the incidents between former FreeBSD
            developers “freebsdgirl” and “xmj”, however the news was still ongoing and we didn’t feel it right to
            discuss until some of the facts had time to shake out and a more clear (and calm) discussion could be had.
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;However, without getting into all the gory details here’s some of the key points that we want to
            highlight for our listeners. We each have our own thoughts on this.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Kris:&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The FreeBSD that I know has been VERY open and inclusive to all who want to contribute. The saying
            “Shut up and code” is there for a reason. We’ve seen developers of all types, different race / gender /
            creed, and the one thing we all have in common is the love for BSD.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This particular incident has been linked to FreeBSD, which isn’t exactly a fair association, since
            the project and other members of community were not directly involved. What started out as a disagreement
            (over something non-BSD related) turned into an ugly slugfest all across social media and (briefly) on a BSD
            chatroom.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In this case after reviewing lots of the facts, I think both sides were WAY out of line, and hope
            they recognize that. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There has been slamming of the core team and foundation in social media, as somehow the delay /
            silence is an admission of wrong-doing. Nothing could be further from the truth. These are serious people
            doing a serious job, and much like BSD they would rather take the time to do it right instead of just going
            off on social media and making things worse. (Plus they all are volunteers who are spread across many
            different time-zones)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Also, if you hear rumors of incidents of harassment, remember that without details all those will
            ever be is rumors. Obviously those in the project would take any incident like that seriously, but without
            coming forward and sharing the details it’s impossible to take any action or make changes for the better.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Allan:&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The FreeBSD community is the best group of people I have ever worked with, but that doesn’t mean
            that it is immune to the same problems that every other group of people faces. As much as all of us wish it
            didn’t, harassment and other ill-behavior does happen, and must be dealt with&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The FreeBSD Core team has previously sanctioned committers and revoked commit bits for things that
            happened entirely offline and outside of the FreeBSD community. Part of being a committer is representing
            the project in everything that you do, so anything you do that reflects badly upon the project is grounds
            for your removal&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There was something written about this in the project documentation somewhere (that I can not find
            for the live of me), specifically about the prestige that comes with (or used to) an @freebsd.org account,
            and how new members of the community need to keep that in mind as they work to earn, and keep, a commit bit&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In this specific situation, I am not sure what core did exactly, we’ll have to wait for their
            report to find out, but I am not sure what more they could have done.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“Individual members of core have the power to temporarily suspend commit privileges until core as
            a whole has the chance to review the issue. Only a 2/3 majority of core has the authority to suspend commit
            privileges for longer than a week or to remove them permanently. Core&#39;s “special powers” only kick in
            when it acts as a group, not on an individual basis. As individuals, the core team members are all
            committers first and core second”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;So, an individual member of core can revoke the commit bit of someone who is reported to have
            acted in a manner not conducive with the rules, but I don’t know how that would have made a difference in
            this case.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The only point from Randi’s list of 10 things the project should change that I do not think is
            possible is #6. As stated in the “Committers&#39; Big List of Rules” that I quoted earlier, the core team
            can only take action after they have had time for everyone to review and discuss a matter, and then vote on
            it.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The core team is made up of 9 people with other responsibilities and commitments. Further, they
            are currently spread across 6 different countries, and 6 different times zones (even the countries and time
            zones do not line up).&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;We eagerly await Cores report on this matter, and more importantly, Core and the Foundation&#39;s
            work to come up with a better framework and response policy to deal with such situations in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The important thing is to ensure that incident reports are properly handled, so that those
            reporting issues feel safe in doing so&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;While we hope there is never another incident of harassment in the FreeBSD community, the
            realities of the world we live in mean we need to be ready to deal with it&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/3zv64t/the_home_lab_9_servers_about_98tb_working_url/&quot;&gt;Dan
            Langille discussing his rig&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/gallery/nuBBD&quot;&gt;Pictures of Dan Langille&#39;s Home Lab&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Ever read FreeBSD Diary? How about used FreshPorts or FreshSource? Gone to BSDCan? If so you may
            be interested in seeing exactly where those sites are served from.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Dan Langille posts to reddit with information about his home lab, with the obligatory pictures to
            back it up&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;As most good home racks do, this one starts at Home Depot and ends up with a variety of systems
            and hardware living on it. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;All in all an impressive rig and nice job wiring&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;(I wonder what that ASUS RT‑N66U is doing, if it’s running FreeBSD or just an access point??)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Reminder: Get your BSDCan talk proposal submitted before the deadline, January 19th&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://undeadly.org/cgi?action=article&amp;amp;sid=20160107174436&quot;&gt;Pre-5.9
            pledge(2) update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Theo gives us a status update on pledge() for pre OpenBSD 5.9“For the next upcoming release, we
            will disable the &#39;paths&#39; argument.Reasoning: We have been very busy making as much of the tree set
            thepromises right in applications, and building a few new promises aswell. We simply don&#39;t have enough
            time to review the kernel code andmake sure it is bug-free. We&#39;ll use the next 6 months developmentcycle
            to decide on paths, and then re-audit the tree to use theinterface where it is suitable.
            The base tree (/bin /sbin /usr/bin /usr/sbin /usr/libexec /usr/games)contains 652 ELF binaries. 451 use
            pledge. 201 do not. Approximately47 do not need or cannot use pledge. Leaving 154 we could potentiallypledge
            in the future. Most of those are not very important. Thereare a few hot spots, but most of what people use
            has been handled wellby the team.“&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://undeadly.org/cgi?action=article&amp;amp;sid=20160107075227&quot;&gt;Chromium:
            now with OpenBSD pledge(2)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In addition to the pledge news, we also have a story about the Chromium browser being converted to
            use pledge on OpenBSD.“The renderer, gpu, plugin and utility processes are now using pledge(2)Unfortunately
            the GPU process only requires an rpath pledge because ofMesa trying to parse two configuration files,
            /etc/drirc and ${HOME}/.drircSo currently the GPU process will use an rpath pledge in the nextweek or so so
            that people can test, but this situation has to beresolved because it is not acceptable that a mostly unused
            configurationfile is being parsed from a library and that stops us from using lesspledges and thus
            disallowing the GPU process to have read accessto the filesystem ... like your ssh keys.”
            UPDATE: the rpath pledge has been removed. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;iXsystems&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;https://forums.freenas.org/index.php?threads/freenas-logo-design-contest.39968/&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Interview - Igor Sysoev - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:igor@sysoev.ru&quot;&gt;igor@sysoev.ru&lt;/a&gt;
            / &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/isysoev&quot;&gt;@isysoev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;NGINX and FreeBSD&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.daemonology.net/blog/2016-01-10-FreeBSD-EdgeRouter-Lite.html&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            on EdgeRouter Lite - no serial port required&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A few years back there was a neat story on how to setup FreeBSD on the EdgeRouter-Lite&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This last week we get to revisit this, as Colin Percival posts a script, and a very detailed
            walkthrough of using it to generate your own custom image which does NOT require hooking up a serial cable.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Currently the script only works on -CURRENT, but may work later for 10.3&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The script is pretty complete, does the buildworld and creation of a USB image for you. It also
            does a basic firewall configuration and even growfs for expanding to the full-size of your USB media.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Using the ‘firstboot’ keyword, an rc.d script does all the initial configuration allowing you
            access to the system&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;If you have one, or are looking at switching to a FreeBSD based router, do yourself a favor and
            take a look at this article. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.dragonflybsd.org/pipermail/users/2016-January/228540.html&quot;&gt;John
            Marino reaches out to the community for testing of Synth, a new custom package repo builder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A hybrid of poudriere and portmaster/portupgrade&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Uses your regular ports tree and your running system, but built builds packages faster, the
            poudriere way&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Requires no setup, no downloading or building reference versions of the OS, no checking out yet
            another copy of the ports tree&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In the future may have support for using binary packages for dependencies, build only the apps you
            actually want to customize&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Looks very promising&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://android-review.googlesource.com/#/c/196090/&quot;&gt;OpenBSD malloc finds
            use-after-free in Android OS &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Score one for OpenBSD’s rigorous security and attention to detail. We have an interesting commit /
            comment from Android&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It looks like this particular mistake was found in the uncrypt routines, in particular the using
            of a variable memory which had already gone out of scope. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Through the usage of OpenBSD’s malloc junk filling feature, the developers were able to identify
            and correct the issue.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Maybe there is a case to be made that this be used more widely, especially during testing?&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/facepalmtarbz2/new-sendfile-in-english&quot;&gt;Netflix&#39;s
            async sendfile now in FreeBSD-current&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;We have some slides presented by Gleb Smirnoff at last years FreeBSD storage summit, talking about
            changes to sendfile made by Netflix. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It starts off with a bit of history, showing the misery of life without sendfile(2) back in
            FreeBSD 1.0, specifically the ftpd daemon.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Then in 1997 that all changed, HP-UX 11.00 grew the sendfile function, and FreeBSD 3.0 / Linux 2.2
            added it in ‘98&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The slides then go into other details, on how the first implementations would map the userland
            cycle into the kernel. Then in 2004 the SF_NODISKIO flag was added, followed by changes in 2006 and 2013 to
            using sbspace() bytes and sending shared memory descriptor data respectively. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The idea is that instead of the web server waiting for the send to complete, it calls sendfile
            then goes about its other work, then it gets a notification when the work is done, and finishes up any of
            the request handling, like logging how many bytes were sent&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The new sendfile implementation took the maximum load of an older netflix box from 25 gigabits/sec
            to 35 gigabits/sec&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Separately, Netflix has also done work on implementing a TLS version of sendfile(), to streamline
            the process of sending encrypted data&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There is still a todo list, including making sendfile() play nice with ZFS. Currently files sent
            via sendfile from ZFS are stored in memory twice, once in the ARC, and once in the buffer cache that
            sendfile uses&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;Beastie Bits&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.levenez.com/unix/&quot;&gt;Unix Timeline of how Unix versions
            have evolved&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svnweb.freebsd.org/base?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=293459&quot;&gt;netmap
            support now in bhyve in FreeBSD -Current&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dragonflydigest.com/2016/01/12/17478.html&quot;&gt;McCabe
            complexity and Dragonfly BSD&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/cander/2785819&quot;&gt;Bourne Basic - a BASIC
            interpreter implemented (painfully) in pure Bourne shell&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NixOS/nixpkgs/pull/10816#issuecomment-169298385&quot;&gt;NixOS
            on FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbsd.org/faq/pf/example1.html&quot;&gt;Turning an ordinary
            OpenBSD system into a router&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://devtalk.nvidia.com/default/topic/908423/unix-graphics-announcements-and-news/linux-solaris-and-freebsd-driver-361-16-beta-/&quot;&gt;nvidia
            releases beta 361.16 driver for FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2BLZeBrSK&quot;&gt; Bryson - SmartOS / KVM / ZFS&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2OQIxkZst&quot;&gt; Samba 1969&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s206j2ekTZ&quot;&gt; DO / VPN / PF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s20kyrKSH9&quot;&gt; Unstable VM / Update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a
            href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>ZFS in the trenches</title>
        <smi:episode>123</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2015_01_06-zfs_in_the_trenches"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2015_01_06-zfs_in_the_trenches</id>
        <published>2016-01-07T10:37:52-07:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-18T08:43:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jupiterbroadcasting/bsd-0123.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="90084531"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jupiterbroadcasting/bsd-0123.ogg"
                    fileSize="90084531"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jupiterbroadcasting/bsd-0123.mp3"
                    fileSize="58287847"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/bsd-0123-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>JT</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Josh Paetzel</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/bsdunix4ever</uri>
        </contributor>
        <summary>his week on BSDNow, we will be talking shop with Josh Paetzel of FreeNAS fame, hearing about his best
            dos and don'ts of using ZFS in production. Also, a quick look back at 2015 &amp; lots of stuff to start
            talking about for 2016; Welcome to another exciting year of BSD Now!
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 123: ZFS in the trenches&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fossforce.com/2015/12/bsd-brief-look-back-2015/&quot;&gt;A Brief look back
            at 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;As we start the show this week, we begin with a brief look back at BSD in 2015, brought to us by
            Larry at FOSS force.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Aside from his issue with tap-to-click on the touchpad, his PC-BSD experience has been pretty
            good. (Larry, if you hear this, jump on #pcbsd on FreeNode and we will lend a hand)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;He mentions that this &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; isn’t his first time running BSD, apparently
            back in ye-olden days he got NetBSD up and running on a PowerBook G3, until an update brought that
            experience to abrupt ending. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;He gives a shout-out to the FreeBSD Foundation as being a great go-to source for wrapup on the
            previous year in FreeBSD land, while also mentioning the great 4.4 release of DragonFly, and some of the
            variants, such as RetroBSD and LiteBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;He leaves us with a tease for 2016 that work is ongoing on Twitter to port over Mopidy, a python
            based extensible music server&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bsdevents.org/scheduler/&quot;&gt;A look forward at BSD events
            throughout 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;After a quick look back at 2015, now its time to start planning your 2016 schedule. The BSDEvents
            site has a calendar of all the upcoming conferences / shows where BSD will have a presence this year. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There are quite a few items on the agenda, including non BSD specific conferences, such as SCALE /
            Fosdem and more.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Take a look and see, you may be able to find something close your location where you can come hang
            out with other BSD developers.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;(or better yet), if a linux conference is coming to your town, think about submitting a BSD talk!&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Additionally, if getting BSD Certification is something on your 2016 resolutions, you can often
            take the test at one of these shows, avoiding the need to travel to a testing center. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://louwrentius.com/the-hidden-cost-of-using-zfs-for-your-home-nas.html&quot;&gt;The
            &#39;Hidden&#39; Cost of Using ZFS for Your Home NAS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;An article was recently posted that seems to be trying to dissuade people from using ZFS for their
            home NAS&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It points out what experienced users already know, but many newcomers are not strictly aware of:
            Expanding a ZFS pool is not always as straightforward as you think it should be&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;ZFS was designed to be expanded, and it handled this very well&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;However, a ZFS pool is made up of VDEVs, and it is these VDEVs that provide the redundancy. RAID-Z
            VDEVs cannot be changed once they are created. You can replace each disk individually, and the VDEV will
            grow to its new larger size, but you cannot add additional disks to a RAID-Z VDEV&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;At this point, your option is to add an additional VDEV, although best practises dictate that the
            new VDEV should use an equal number of disks, to avoid uneven performance&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;So, if you started with a 6 disk RAID-Z2, having to add 6 more disks to grow the pool does seem
            excessive&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;For the best flexibility, use mirrors. If you had used 6 disks as 3 mirrors of 2 disks each, you
            could then just add 2 more disks at a time. The downside is that using 2TB disks, you’d only have 6TB of
            usable space, versus the 8TB you would get from those disks in a RAID-Z2&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This is the trade-off, mirrors give you better performance and flexibility, but less space
            efficiency&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It is important to note that the diagrams in this article make it appear as if all parity
            information is stored on specific drives. In ZFS parity is spread across all drives. Often times, the data
            written to the drive is not of a size that can evenly be split across all drives, so the data actually ends
            up &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.delphix.com/matt/files/2014/06/RAIDZ.png&quot;&gt;looking like this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The errors as I see it in the original article are:

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It notes that the hidden cost of ZFS is that if you add a second RAID-Z VDEV, you will have a
            whole second set of parity drives. While this is a cost, it is the cost of making sure your data is safe. If
            you had an array with more than 12 drives, it is likely that you would to be able to withstand the failure
            of the larger number of drives&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The article does not consider the resilver time. If you did create a configuration with a very
            wide RAID-Z stripe, the failure of a disk would leave the pool degraded for a much longer time, leaving your
            pool at risk for that longer period.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The article does not consider performance. Two RAID-Z2 VDEVs of 6 disks each will give much better
            performance than a single VDEV of 10 or 12 disks, especially when it comes to IOPS.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svnweb.freebsd.org/base?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=293001&quot;&gt;ZFS
            Boot Enviroments now availble in the FreeBSD bootloader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It’s been in phabricator for a while (and PC-BSD), but the support for Boot-Environments has now
            landed upstream in -CURRENT&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This work was helped by cross-project collaboration when an IllumOS Developer, Toomas Soome,
            started porting the FreeBSD loader to IllumOS to replace GRUB there&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This gives Beastie menu the ability to look at the ZFS disk, and dynamically list
            boot-environments that it finds. (Much nicer than GRUB, which required a pre-written configuration file)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This work was extended further, when Toomas Soome also ported the &lt;a href=&quot;https://svnweb.freebsd.org/base?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=293233&quot;&gt;Beastie
            Menu to the UEFI loader&lt;/a&gt; which is now &lt;a href=&quot;https://svnweb.freebsd.org/base?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=293234&quot;&gt;enabled
            by default for UEFI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;All of these changes are scheduled to be merged back in time for FreeBSD 10.3 as well.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There is also a patch being worked on to &lt;a href=&quot;https://reviews.freebsd.org/D4515&quot;&gt;support
            booting from ZFS in UEFI&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This is exciting times for doing neat things with ZFS on root, these plus Allans forthcoming &lt;a
            href=&quot;https://reviews.freebsd.org/D4593&quot;&gt;GELI support&lt;/a&gt; will negate the necessity for
            GRUB on PC-BSD for example (Kris is very happy)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Interview - Josh Paetzel - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:email@email&quot;&gt;email@email&lt;/a&gt; /
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bsdunix4ever&quot;&gt;@bsdunix4ever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;ZFS Support&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://retrobsd.org/viewtopic.php?f=1&amp;amp;t=37470&quot;&gt;RetroBSD being
            tested on ESP32&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;More hardware news for RetroBSD and LiteBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;I don’t know much about this hardware, but there is a lot of discussion in the forum threads about
            it&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Not sure what you are supposed to accomplish with only 400kb of ram&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2016/01/04/litebsd-brings-4-4bsd-to-pic32/&quot;&gt;LITEBSD
            Brings 4.4BSD to PIC32&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It is interesting to see these super-small boards with only 512kb of memory, but will crypto
            offload support&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It is also interesting to see talk of 140mbps WiFi, can the processor actually handle that much
            traffic?
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevarguy.com/open-source-application-software-companies/bsd-unix-os-resurrected-embedded-iot-market&quot;&gt;BSD
            Unix-like OS is Resurrected for Embedded IoT Market&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Related to the above stories, we also have an article about BSD making a resurgence on various
            Internet of things devices, which mentions both RetroBSD and LiteBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The article mentions that this is an exciting development for embedded vars who now have an
            alternative licensed open-source OS to potentially use&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hardenedbsd.org/article/shawn-webb/2015-12-31/introducing-hardenedbsds-new-binary-updater&quot;&gt;HardenedBSD’s
            new Binary Updater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It looks like there is now another way to update your FreeBSD(hardened) system&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The post by Shawn Web, details how the new updater will work in future releases of HBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Right now it looks fairly straight-forward, creating both the base.txz and kernel.txz, along with
            some data for etcupdate&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It includes a nice option for the kernel name in the update, allowing different kernels to be
            installed / updated at will&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Everything is cryptographically signed and verified using the base system openssl&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The build system is fairly simple, only requiring “sh/git/openssl” to create the binary updates&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Planned features also include updating of jails, and ZFS boot-environments&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://functionallyparanoid.com/2016/01/02/sometimes-processors-need-love-too/&quot;&gt;Sometimes,
            processors need (BSD) love too&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;We have a blog post from Brian Everly, talking about his long journey into legacy processors and
            the plans for the future to work on better supporting them on OpenBSD ports&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;He begins with the story of his UNIX journey to today, and why this fostered his love for many of
            these old (and not so old) architectures, such as Sparc64, PPC32, i386.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This journey ended up with the purchase of some legacy hardware (ebay is your friend), and the
            creation of a database listing the major port blockers on each platform&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This is the great kind of thing folks can do to step up and help a project, even as a weekend
            hobby it’s great to run some hardware and help test / fix up issues that other developers maybe don’t
            interact with as much anymore. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;Beastie Bits&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blather.michaelwlucas.com/archives/2510&quot;&gt;The standard MWL
            disclaimer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.pcbsd.org/pipermail/testing/2016-January/010350.html&quot;&gt;PC-BSD
            11.0-CURRENTJAN2016 Available&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mail-index.netbsd.org/tech-pkg/2015/12/28/msg016193.html&quot;&gt;NetBSD
            pkgsrc-2015Q3 statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mail-index.netbsd.org/tech-pkg/2016/01/01/msg016213.html&quot;&gt;NetBSD
            pkgsrc-2015Q4 released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.netbsd.org/tnf/entry/reproducible_builds_conference_in_athens&quot;&gt;First
            Reproducible builds conference in Athens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2016/01/06/thinkpad_designer_obituary&quot;&gt;The
            creator of the original ThinkPad design passes away &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s213iCKLwn&quot;&gt; Andrew - High Contrast&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s21ClGePLP&quot;&gt; John - FreeNAS followup&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s21527pkO1&quot;&gt; Giorgio - Custom Install&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2jOlCsjkU&quot;&gt; Don - ZFS Slowdowns&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s21uaB0FDU&quot;&gt; Fred - Dual Boot PC-BSD/Linux&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a
            href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
