<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed
        xml:lang="en-us"
        xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
        xmlns:smi="https://www.betterfeeds.org/series-media-info"
        xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
        xmlns:psc="http://podlove.org/simple-chapters">
    <title>BSD Now</title>
    <subtitle>A weekly show covering the latest developments in the world of the BSD family of operating systems. News,
        Tutorials and Interviews for new users and long time developers alike.
    </subtitle>
    <icon>http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/images/bsdnow-badge.jpg</icon>
    <media:thumbnail
            url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/images/bsdnow-badge.jpg"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow/bsdnow-2016-03.atom"
            rel="self"
            type="application/atom+xml"
            title="BSD Now"/>
    <link
            href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/"
            rel="alternate"
            type="text/html"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowMp3"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now MP3 Audio"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowOgg"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now OGG Audio"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowMobile"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now SD Video"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowHd"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now HD Video"/>
    <link
            href="http://bitlove.org/jupiterbroadcasting/bsdnowhd/feed"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now HD Video (BitTorrent)"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow/bsdnow-2016-04.atom"
            rel="previous"
            type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow/bsdnow-2016-02.atom"
            rel="next"
            type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/</id>
    <updated>2016-06-16T08:20:00Z</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Jupiter Broadcasting</name>
        <uri>www.jupiterbroadcasting.com</uri>
    </author>
    <smi:sequential>false</smi:sequential>
    <entry>
        <title>Speciality MWL</title>
        <smi:episode>135</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_03_30-speciality-mwl"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_03_30-speciality-mwl</id>
        <published>2016-03-31T11:25:39-07:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-16T07:57:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0135.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="75737000"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0135.ogg"
                    fileSize="75737000"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0135.mp3"
                    fileSize="48632780"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/bsd-0135-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>JT</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Michael W. Lucas</name>
            <email>mwlucas@michaelwlucas.com</email>
        </contributor>
        <summary>This week on the show, we interview author Michael W Lucas to discuss his new book in the FreeBSD
            Mastery series: “Specialty Filesystems”. That plus the latest news, feedback &amp; more!
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 135: Speciality MWL&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://undeadly.org/cgi?action=article&amp;amp;sid=20160329181346&amp;amp;mode=expanded&quot;&gt;OpenBSD
            5.9 Released early&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Finished ahead of schedule! OpenBSD 5.9 has officially landed&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;We’ve been covering some of the ongoing changes as they landed in the tree, but with the official
            release it’s time to bring you the final list of the new hotness which landed.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;First up:

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Pledge - Over 70%! Of the userland utilities have been converted to use it, and the best part, you
            probably didn’t even notice&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;UEFI - Laptops which are pre-locked down to boot UEFI only can now be installed and used - GPT
            support has also been greatly improved&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;‘Less’ was replaced with a fork from Illumos, and has been further improved&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Xen DomU support - OpenBSD now plays nice in the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;X11 - Broadwell and Bay Trail are now supported&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Initial work on making the network stack better support SMP has been added, this is still ongoing,
            but things are starting to happen&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;802.11N! Specifically for the iwn/iwm drivers&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In addition to support for UTF-8, most other locales have been ripped out, leaving only C and
            UTF-8 left standing in the wake&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;All and all, sounds like a solid new release with plenty of new goodies to play with. Go grab a
            copy now!&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://undeadly.org/cgi?action=article&amp;amp;sid=20160324093944&quot;&gt;New
            routing table code (ART) enabled in -current&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;While OpenBSD 5.9 just landed, we also have some interesting work landing right now in -CURRENT as
            well. Specifically the new routing table code (ART) has landed:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;“I just enabled ART in -current, it will be the default routing table backend in the next
            snapshots.
            The plan is to squash the possible regressions with this new routing table backend then when we&#39;re
            confident enough, take its route lookup out of the KERNEL_LOCK(). Yes, this is one of the big steps for our
            network SMP improvements.
            In order to make progress, we need your help to make sure this new backend works well on your setup. So
            please, go download the next snapshot and report back.
            If you encounter any routing table regression, please make sure that you cannot reproduce it with your old
            kernel and include the output of # route -n show
            for the 2 kernels as well as the dmesg in your report.
            I know that simple dhclient(8) based setups work with ART, so please do not flood us too much. It&#39;s
            always great to know that things work, but it&#39;s also hard to keep focus ;)
            Thank your very much for your support!”
            + There you have it folks! If 5.9 is already too stale for you, time to move over to -CURRENT and give the
            new routing tables a whirl.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.freebsd.org/threads/55561/&quot;&gt;fractal cells - FreeBSD-based
            All-In-One solution for software development startups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Fractal Cells is a suite that transforms a stock FreeBSD installation into an instant “Startup
            Software Development Platform”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It Integrates ZFS, PostgreSQL, OpenSMTPD, NGINX, OpenVPN, Redmine, Jenkins, Zabbix, Gitlab, and
            Ansible, all under OpenLDAP common authentication&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The suite is available under the 2-clause BSD license&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Provides all of the tools and infrastructure to build your application, including code review,
            issue tracking, continuous integration, and monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;An interesting way to make it easier for people to start building new applications and startups on
            top of FreeBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxsecrets.com/blog/51freebsd/2016/02/29/1726-installing&quot;&gt;LinuxSecrets
            publishes guide on installing FreeBSD ezJail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Covers all of the steps of setting up ezjail on FreeBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Includes the instructions for updating the version of the OS in the jail&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In a number of places the tutorial uses:&lt;br&gt;
            &amp;gt; cat &amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/rc.conf &amp;gt; setting=”value”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Instead, use: sysrc setting=”value”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It is safer, and easier to type&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;When you create the jail, if you specify an IP address, it is expected that this IP address is
            already setup on the host machine&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;If instead you specify: ‘em0|192.168.1.105’ (where em0 is your network interface), the IP address
            will be added as an alias when the jail starts, and removed from the host when the jail is stopped&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;You can also comma separate a list of addresses to have multiple IPs (possibly on different
            interfaces) in the jail&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Although recently posted, this appears as if it might be an update to a previous tutorial, as
            there are a few old references that have not been updated (pkg_add, rc.d/ezjail.sh), while the start of the
            article clearly covers pkg(8)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Interview - Michael W. Lucas - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mwlucas@michaelwlucas.com&quot;&gt;mwlucas@michaelwlucas.com&lt;/a&gt;
            /&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mwlauthor&quot;&gt;@mwlauthor&lt;/a&gt;
            + New Book: “FreeBSD Mastery: Specialty Filesystems”&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fwbug/dreamcast-slides&quot;&gt;NetBSD on Dreamcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Ahh the dreamcast, so much promise. So much potential. If you are still holding onto your beloved
            dreamcast hoping that someday Sega will re-enter the console market… Then give it up now!&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In the meantime, you can now do something more interesting with that box taking up space in the
            closet. We have a link to a GitHub repo where a user has uploaded his curses-based slide-show for the
            upcoming Fort-Wayne, Indiana meetup.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Aside from the novelty of using a curses-based slide setup, the presenter will also be displaying
            them from his beloved dreamcast, which “of course” runs NetBSD 7&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The slide source code is available, which you too can view / compile and find out details of
            getting NetBSD boot-strapped on the DC.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://opnsense.org/opnsense-16-1-7-released/&quot;&gt;OPNsense 16.1.7 Released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;captive portal: add session timeout to status info&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;firewall: fix non-report of errors when filter reload errors couldn’t be parsed&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;proxy: adjust category visibility as not all of them were shown before&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;firmware: fix an overzealous upgrade run when the package tool only changes options&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;firmware: fixed the binary upgrade patch from 15.7.x in FreeBSD’s package tool&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;system: removed NTP settings from general settings&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;access: let only root access status.php as it leaks too much info&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;development: remove the automount features&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;development: addition of “opnsense-stable” package on our way to nightly builds&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;development: opnsense-update can now install locally available base and kernel sets&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blather.michaelwlucas.com/archives/2570&quot;&gt;“FreeBSD Mastery:
            Advanced ZFS” in tech review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Most of the tech review is finished&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It was very interesting to hear from many ZFS experts that they learned something from reading the
            review copy of the book, I was not expecting this&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Many minor corrections and clarifications have been integrated&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The book is now being copy edited&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cambus.net/why-openbsd/&quot;&gt;Why OpenBSD?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Frederic Cambus gives us a nice perspective piece today on what his particular reasons are for
            choosing OpenBSD.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Frederic is no stranger to UNIX-Like systems, having used them for 20 years now. In particular
            starting on Slackware back in ‘96 and moving to FreeBSD from 2000-2005 (around the 4.x series)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;His adventure into OpenBSD began sometime after 2005 (specific time unknown), but a bunch of
            things left a very good impression on him throughout the years.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;First, was the ease of installation, with its very minimalistic layout, which was one of the
            fastest installs he had ever done.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Second was the extensive documentation, which extends beyond just manpages, but into other forms
            of documentation, such as presentations and papers as well.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;He makes the point about an “ecosystem of quality” that surrounds OpenBSD:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;OpenBSD is an ecosystem of quality. This is the result of a culture of code auditing, reviewing,
            and a rigorous development process where each commit hitting the tree must be approved by other developers.
            It has a slower evolution pace and a more carefully planned development model which leads to better code
            quality overall. Its well deserved reputation of being an ultra secure operating system is the byproduct of
            a no compromise attitude valuing simplicity, correctness, and most importantly proactivity. OpenBSD also
            deletes code, a lot of code. Everyone should know that removing code and keeping the codebase modern is
            probably as important as adding new one. Quoting Saint-Exupery: &quot;It seems that perfection is attained
            not when there is nothing more to add, but when there is nothing more to remove&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The article then covers security mechanisms, as well as the defaults which are turned specifically
            with an eye towards security.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;All-in-all a good perspective piece about the reasons why OpenBSD is the right choice for
            Frederic, worth your time to read up on it if you want to learn more about OpenBSD’s differences.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;BeastieBits&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.freebsd.org/cgi/getmsg.cgi?fetch=9011+0+current/freebsd-hackers&quot;&gt;Call
            for 2016Q1 quarterly status reports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blather.michaelwlucas.com/archives/2593&quot;&gt;FreeBSD Mastery: Advanced
            ZFS” sponsorships ending soon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.freebsd.org/cgi/getmsg.cgi?fetch=250105+0+archive/2016/freebsd-arm/20160306.freebsd-arm&quot;&gt;Shawn
            Webb from HardenedBSD talking about giving away RPi3’s at BSDCan and hacking on them to get FreeBSD working&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://undeadly.org/cgi?action=article&amp;amp;sid=20160308204011&quot;&gt;xterm(1)
            now UTF-8 by default&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.pcbsd.org/2016/03/call-for-artists-new-icon-theme/&quot;&gt;Call For
            Artists: New Icon Theme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.netbsd.org/tnf/entry/happy_23rd_birthday_src&quot;&gt;Happy 23rd
            Birthday, src!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2oqRuXCYW&quot;&gt; Alison - Readahead and Wayland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2sQ8MxNPh&quot;&gt; Kenny - Gear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s20SRvXPZA&quot;&gt; Ben - IPFW2/3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s207mV2Ph1&quot;&gt; Brad - ZFS Writeback&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s202loSWdf&quot;&gt; Simon - BSD Toonz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to
            &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Marking up the Ports tree</title>
        <smi:episode>134</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_03_23-marking_up_the_ports_tree"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_03_23-marking_up_the_ports_tree</id>
        <published>2016-03-24T10:13:03-07:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-16T08:02:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0134.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="94111170"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0134.ogg"
                    fileSize="94111170"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0134.mp3"
                    fileSize="60416304"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/bsd-0134-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>JT</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Mark Felder</name>
            <email>feld@freebsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/feldpos</uri>
        </contributor>
        <summary>This week on the show, Allan &amp; Kris have gotten a bit more sleep since AsiaBSDCon, which is excellent
            since there is a LOT of news to cover. That plus our interview with Ports SecTeam member Mark Felder. So
            keep it tuned to BSDNow, the place to B...SD!
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 134: Marking up the Ports tree&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.freenas.org/pipermail/freenas-announce/2016-March/000028.html&quot;&gt;FreeNAS
            9.10 Released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;OS:

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The base OS version for FreeNAS 9.10 is now FreeBSD 10.3-RC3, bringing in a huge number of
            OS-related bug fixes, performance improvements and new features.
            +Directory Services:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;You can now connect to large AD domains with cache disabled.
            +Reporting:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Add the ability to send collectd data to a remote graphite server.
            +Hardware Support:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Added Support for Intel I219-V &amp;amp; I219-LM Gigabit Ethernet Chipset&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Added Support for Intel Skylake architecture&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Improved support for USB devices (like network adapters)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;USB 3.0 devices now supported.
            +Filesharing:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Samba (SMB filesharing) updated from version 4.1 to 4.3.4&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Added GUI feature to allow nfsv3-like ownership when using nfsv4&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Various bug fixes related to FreeBSD 10.
            +Ports:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;FreeBSD ports updated to follow the FreeBSD 2016Q1 branch.
            +Jails:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;FreeBSD Jails now default to a FreeBSD 10.3-RC2 based template.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Old jails, or systems on which jails have been installed, will still default to the previous
            FreeBSD 9.3 based template. Only those machinesusing jails for the first time (or deleting and recreating
            their jails dataset) will use the new template.
            +bhyve:
            ++In the upcoming 10 release, the CLI will offer full support for managing virtual machines and containers.
            Until then, the iohyve command is bundled as a stop-gap solution to provide basic VM management support -&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/ubuntubsd/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu BSD&#39;s first Beta
            Release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Under the category of “Where did this come from?”, we have a first beta release of Ubuntu BSD.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Specifically it is Ubuntu, respun to use the FreeBSD kernel and ZFS natively.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;From looking at the minimal information up on sourceforge, we gather that is has a nice text-based
            installer, which supports ZFS configuration and iSCSI volume creation setups.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Aside from that, it includes the XFCE desktop out of box, but claims to be suitable for both
            desktops and servers alike right now.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;We will keep an eye on this, if anybody listening has already tested it out, maybe drop us a line
            on your thoughts of how this mash-up works out.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vez.mrsk.me/freebsd-defaults.txt&quot;&gt;FreeBSD - a lesson in poor
            defaults&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Former BSD producer, and now OpenBSD developer, TJ, writes a post detailing the defaults he
            changes in a fresh FreeBSD installation&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Maybe some of these should be the defaults&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;While others are definitely a personal preference, or are not as security related as they seem&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A few of these, while valid criticisms, but some are done for a reason&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Specifically, the OpenSSH changes.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;So, you’re a user, you install FreeBSD 10.0, and it comes with OpenSSH version X, which has some
            specific defaults&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;As guaranteed by the FreeBSD Project, you will have a nice smooth upgrade path to any version in
            the 10.x branch&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Just because OpenSSH has released version Y, doesn’t mean that the upgrade can suddenly remove
            support for DSA keys, or re-adding support for AES-CBC (which is not really weak, and which can be hardware
            accelerated, unlikely most of the replacements)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“FreeBSD is the team trying to increase the risk.” Is incorrect, they are trying to reduce the
            impact on the end user&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Specifically, a user upgrading from 10.x to 10.3, should not end up locked out of their SSH
            server, or otherwise confronted by unexpected errors or slowdowns because of upstream changes&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;I will note again, (and again), that the NONE cipher can NOT allow a user to “shoot themselves in
            the foot”, encryption is still used during the login phase, it is just disabled for the file transfer phase.
            The NONE cipher will refuse to work for an interactive session.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;While the post states that the NONE cipher doesn’t improve performance that much, it infact does&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In my own testing, chacha20-poly1305 1.3 gbps, aes128-gcm (fastest) 5.0 gbps, NONE cipher 6.3 gbps&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;That means that the NONE cipher is an hour faster to transfer 10 TB over the LAN.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The article suggests just removing sendmail with no replacement. Not sure how they expect users to
            deliver mail, or the daily/weekly reports&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Ports can be compiled as a regular user. Only the install phase requires root&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;for ntpd, it is not clear that there is an acceptable replacement yet, but I will not that it is
            off by default&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In the sysctl section, I am not sure I see how enabling tcp blackhole actually increases security
            at all&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;I am not sure that linking to every security advisory in openssl since 2001 is actually useful&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Encrypted swap is an option in bsdinstall now, but I am not sure it is really that important&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;FreeBSD now uses the Fortuna PRNG, upgraded to replace the older Yarrow, not vanilla RC4.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“The resistance from the security team to phase out legacy options makes mewonder if they should
            be called a compatibility team instead.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;I do not think this is the choice of the security team, it is the ABI guarantee that the project
            makes. The stable/10 branch will always have the same ABI, and a program or driver compiled against it will
            work with any version on that branch&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The security team doesn’t really have a choice in the matter. Switching the version of OpenSSL
            used in FreeBSD 9.x would likely break a large number of applications the user has installed&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Something may need to be done differently, since it doesn’t look like any version of OpenSSL, (or
            OpenSSH), will be supported for 5 years ever again&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://calomel.org/zfs_raid_speed_capacity.html&quot;&gt;ZFS Raidz Performance,
            Capacity and Integrity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;An updated version of an article comparing the performance of various ZFS vdev configurations&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The settings users in the test may not reflect your workload&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;If you are benchmarking ZFS, consider using multiple files across different datasets, and not
            making all of the writes synchronous&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Also, it is advisable to run more than 3 runs of each test&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Comparing the numbers from the 12 and 24 disk tests, it is surprising to see that the 12 mirror
            sets did not outperform the other configurations. In the 12 drive tests, the 6 mirror sets had about the
            same read performance as the other configurations, it is not clear why the performance with more disks is
            worse, or why it is no longer in line with the other configurations&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;More investigation of this would be required&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There are obviously so other bottlenecks, as 5x SSDs in RAID-Z1 performed the same as 17x SSDs in
            RAID-Z1&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Interesting results none the less&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;iXSystems&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nasanda.com/2016/03/ixsystems-freenas-mini-nas-device-reviewed/&quot;&gt;FreeNAS
            Mini Review&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Interview - Mark Felder - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:feld@freebsd.org&quot;&gt;feld@freebsd.org&lt;/a&gt;
            / &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/feldpos&quot;&gt;@feldpos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Ports, Ports and more Ports&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-configure-and-connect-to-a-private-openvpn-server-on-freebsd-10-1&quot;&gt;Digital
            Ocean&#39;s guide to setting up an OpenVPN server&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://undeadly.org/cgi?action=article&amp;amp;sid=20160316153158&amp;amp;mode=flat&amp;amp;count=0&quot;&gt;AsiaBSDCon
            OpenBSD Papers&lt;/a&gt;
            + Undeadly.org has compiled a handy list of the various OpenBSD talks / papers that were offered a few weeks
            ago at AsiaBSDCon 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Antoine Jacoutot (ajacoutot@) - OpenBSD rc.d(8) (slides | paper)
            Henning Brauer (henning@) - Running an ISP on OpenBSD (slides)
            Mike Belopuhov (mikeb@) - Implementation of Xen PVHVM drivers in OpenBSD (slides | paper)
            Mike Belopuhov (mikeb@) - OpenBSD project status update (slides)
            Mike Larkin (mlarkin@) - OpenBSD vmm Update (slides)
            Reyk Floeter (reyk@) - OpenBSD vmd Update (slides) &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Each talk provides slides, and some the papers as well. Also included is the update to ‘vmm’
            discussed at bhyveCon, which will be of interest to virtualization enthusiasts.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bitcoinist.net/bitcoin-devs-could-learn-a-lot-from-bsd/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin
            Devs could learn a lot from BSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;An interesting article this week, comparing two projects that at first glance may not be entirely
            related, namely BitCoin and BSD.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The article first details some of the woes currently plaguing the BitCoin development community,
            such as toxic community feedback to changes and stakeholders with vested financial interests being unable to
            work towards a common development purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This leads into the crux or the article, about what BitCoin devs could learn from BSD:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;First and foremost, the way code is developed needs change to stop the current negative trend in
            Bitcoin. The FreeBSD project has a rigid internal hierarchy of people with write access to their codebase,
            which the various Bitcoin implementations also have, but BSD does this in a way that is very open to fresh
            eyes on their code, allowing parallel problem solving without the petty infighting we see in Bitcoin. Anyone
            can propose a commit publicly to the code, make it publicly available, and democratically decide which
            change ends up in the codebase. FreeBSD has a tiny number of core developers compared to the size of their
            codebase, but at any point, they have a huge community advancing their project without hard forks popping up
            at every small disagreement. Brian Armstrong commented recently on this flaw with Bitcoin development,
            particularly with the Core Devs:&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;“Being high IQ is not enough for a team to succeed. You need to make reasonable tradeoffs,
            collaborate, be welcoming, communicate, and be easy to work with. Any team that doesn’t have this will be
            unable to attract top talent and will struggle long term. In my opinion, perhaps the biggest risk in Bitcoin
            right now is, ironically, one of the things which has helped it the most in the past: the Bitcoin Core
            developers.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A good summary of the culture that could be adopted is summed up as follows:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The other thing Bitcoin devs could learn from is the BSD community’s adoption of the Unix Design
            philosophy. Primarily “Worse is Better,” The rule of Diversity, and Do One Thing and Do It Well. “Worse is
            Better” emphasizes using extant functional solutions rather than making more complex ones, even if they
            would be more robust. The Rule of Diversity stresses flexibility of the program being developed, allowing
            for modification and different implementations without breaking. Do one Thing and Do it well is a mantra of
            the BSD and Unix Communities that stresses modularity and progress over “perfect” solutions. Each of these
            elements help to make BSD a wildly successful open source project with a healthy development community and
            lots of inter-cooperation between the different BSD systems. While this is the opposite of what we see with
            Bitcoin at present, the situation is salvageable provided changes like this are made, especially by Core
            Developers.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;All in all, a well written and interesting take on the FreeBSD/BSD project. We hope the BitCoin
            devs can take something useful from it down the road.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ben.eficium.net/2016/03/freebsd-cross-compiling-with-gcc.html&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            cross-compiling with gcc and poudriere&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Cross-Compiling, always a challenge, has gotten easier using poudriere and qemu in recent years.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;However this blog post details some of the particular issues still being face when trying to
            compile some certain ports for ARM (I.E. rPi) that don’t play nicely with FreeBSD’s default CLANG compiler.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The writer (Ben Slack) takes us through some of the work-arounds he uses to build some troublesome
            ports, namely lsof and libatomic_ops. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Note this is not just an issue with cross compile, the above mentioned ports also don’t build with
            clang on the Pi directly. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;After doing the initial poudriere/qemu cross-compile setup, he then shows us the minor tweaks to
            adjust which compiler builds specific ports, and how he triggers the builds using poudriere.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;With the actual Makefile adjustment being so minor, one wonders if this shouldn’t just be
            committed upstream, with some if (ARM) - USE_GCC=yes type conditional. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://devtalk.nvidia.com/default/topic/925607/unix-graphics-announcements-and-news/linux-solaris-and-freebsd-driver-364-12-beta-/&quot;&gt;Nvidia
            releases new Beta graphics driver for FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Added support for the following GPUs: GeForce 920MX &amp;amp; GeForce 930MX&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Added support for the Vulkan API version 1.0.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug that could cause incorrect frame rate reporting on Quadro Sync configurations with
            multiple GPUs.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Added a new RandR property, CscMatrix, which specifies a 3x4 color-space conversion matrix.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Improved handling of the X gamma ramp on GF119 and newer GPUs. On these GPUs, the RandR gamma ramp
            is always 1024 entries and now applies to the cursor and VDPAU or workstation overlays in addition to the X
            root window.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Fixes for bugs and added several other EGL extensions&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Beastie Bits&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://knoxbug.org/&quot;&gt;New TN Bug started&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gitweb.dragonflybsd.org/dragonfly.git/commitdiff/4a43469a10cef8c17553c342aab9d73611ea7bc8?utm_source=anzwix&quot;&gt;DragonFlyBSD
            Network/TCP Performance&#39;s gets a bump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freebsdfoundation.org/blog/introducing-a-new-look-for-the-foundation/&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            Foundation introduces a new website and logo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our producer made these based on the new logo:&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;http://q5sys.sh/2016/03/a-new-freebsd-foundation-logo-means-its-time-for-some-new-wallpapers/&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;http://q5sys.sh/2016/03/pc-bsd-and-lumina-desktop-wallpapers/&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;https://github.com/pcbsd/lumina/commit/60314f46247b7ad6e877af503b3814b0be170da8 &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://undeadly.org/cgi?action=article&amp;amp;sid=20160316190937&amp;amp;mode=flat&quot;&gt;IPv6
            errata for 5.7/5.8, pledge errata for 5.9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blather.michaelwlucas.com/archives/2577&quot;&gt;Sponsoring “PAM
            Mastery”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rocketgraph.com/s/v89jBkKN4e-&quot;&gt;A visualization of
            FreeBSD commits on GitHub for 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://undeadly.org/cgi?action=article&amp;amp;sid=20160309192510&quot;&gt;The
            VAX platform is no more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s20KPYDOsq&quot;&gt; Hunter - Utils for Blind&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2EHdI3z3L&quot;&gt; Chris - ZFS Quotas&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s21Nx1VSiU&quot;&gt; Anonymous - Tun, Tap and Me!&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2ZKK2DZTL&quot;&gt; Andrew - Navigating the BSDs&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s20duO29mN&quot;&gt; Brent - Wifi on BSD&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a
            href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Tokyo Debrief</title>
        <smi:episode>133</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_03_16-the_toyko_debrief"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_03_16-the_toyko_debrief</id>
        <published>2016-03-17T10:05:48-07:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-16T08:08:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0133.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="62556835"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0133.ogg"
                    fileSize="62556835"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0133.mp3"
                    fileSize="37002648"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/bsd-0133-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>JT</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Brad Davis</name>
            <email>brd@freebsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/so14k</uri>
        </contributor>
        <summary>This week on BSDNow, Allan and I are back from AsiaBSDCon &amp; we have an interview with Brad Davis
            about the new “Packaging Base” call-for-testing. We’ll be sharing our thoughts and stories on how the week
            went, along with updating you on the latest news.
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 133: The Tokyo Debrief&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;AsiaBSDCon 2016 - Wrap-up&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://svnweb.freebsd.org/changeset/base/296548&quot;&gt;FreeBSD gets Haswell
            graphics support in time for 11.0-RELEASE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The moment that many have been waiting for has finally arrived, support for Haswell graphics has
            been committed to FreeBSD -CURRENT&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The brings the DRM/i915 code up to date with Linux kernel 3.8.13&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Work has already started on updating to Linux kernel 3.9&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It is hoped that subsequent updates will be much easier, and much faster&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It does not appear to require setting the i915.preliminary&lt;em&gt;hw&lt;/em&gt;support loader
            tunable&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bhyvecon.org/bhyvecon2016-Mike.pdf&quot;&gt;OpenBSD vmm/vmd Update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;For the third year running, bhyvecon was held last week, during the lead up to AsiaBSDCon&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Bhyvecon has expanded, and now covers all virtualization on BSDs&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There were presentations on bhyve, Xen Dom0 on FreeBSD, Xen DomU for OpenBSD, and OpenBSD’s vmm&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;OpenBSD vmm started at the Brisbane 2015 hackathon in Australia&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Work continued through the summer and fall thanks to funding by the OpenBSD Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The presentation answered some outstanding questions, such as, why not just port bhyve?&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Initial focus is OpenBSD on OpenBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Loader currently supports FreeBSD and NetBSD as well&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;After the initial commits, other developers joined in to help with the work&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Reyk reworked the vmd and vmctl commands, to provide a better user interface&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Future plans:

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Nested VMX&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;i386 support&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;AMD SVM support&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Filesystem passthru&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Live migration (with ZFS like command syntax)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Other developers are working on related projects:

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;qemu interface: Allow qemu to be accelerated by the vmm backend, while providing emulated
            hardware, for legacy systems&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;KVM interface: Make vmm look like KVM, so existing tools like openstack “just work”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Interview - Brad Davis - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:brd@freebsd.org&quot;&gt;brd@freebsd.org&lt;/a&gt;
            / &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/so14k&quot;&gt;@so14k&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Packaging Base&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.freebsd.org/pipermail/freebsd-pkgbase/2016-March/000032.html&quot;&gt;Packaging
            the base system with pkg(8)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The official call for testing for FreeBSD’s pkg(8)’d base is out&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Users are requested to checkout the release-pkg branch, and build it as normal (buildworld,
            buildkernel)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Instead of installworld, run: make packages&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This will produce a pkg repo in the /usr/obj directory&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The post to the mailing list includes an example pkg repo config file to point to those packages&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Run: pkg update -r FreeBSD-base&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This will read the metadata from the new repository&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Then run: pkg install -g &#39;FreeBSD-*&#39;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This will find all packages that start with ‘FreeBSD-’ and install them&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In the future, there will be meta packages, so you can just install FreeBSD-base and it will pull
            in other packages are dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Currently, there are a large number of packages (over 700), because each shared library is
            packaged separately, and almost all optional features are in a separate package&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The number of packages is also increased because there are separate -debug, -profiling, etc
            versions of each package&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;New features are being added to pkg(8) to mark important system components, like libc, as ‘vital’,
            so they cannot be deleted accidently&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;However, in the case of using pkg(8)’d base to create a jail, the administrator should be able to
            delete the entire base system&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Classic conundrum: “UNIX does not stop you doing something stupid, as that would also stop you
            doing something clever”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Work is still ongoing&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;At AsiaBSDCon, after the interview was recorded, bapt@ and brd@ had a whiteboarding session and
            have come up with how they expect to handle the kernel package, to ensure there is a /boot/kernel.old for
            you to fall back to incase the newly installer kernel does not work correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.freebsd.org/pipermail/freebsd-stable/2016-March/084384.html&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            10.3-RC2 Now Available&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The second release candidate for FreeBSD 10.3 is now available for testing&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Notable changes include:

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Import an upstream fix for ‘zfs send -i’ to avoid data corruption in specific instances&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Boot loaders and kernel have been taught to handle ELF sections of type SHT&lt;em&gt;AMD64&lt;/em&gt;UNWIND.
            This does not really apply to FreeBSD 10.3, but is required for 11.0, so will make upgrades easier&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Various mkdb commands (/etc/services, /etc/login.conf, etc) commands now use fsync() instead of
            opening the files as O_SYNC, greatly increasing the speed of the database generation&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;From the earlier BETA3, the VFS improvements that were causing ZFS hangs, and the new ‘tryforward’
            routing code, have been reverted&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Work is ongoing to fix these issues for FreeBSD 11.0&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There are two open issues:

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A fix for OpenSSH CVE-2016-3115 has not be included yet&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;the re-addition of AES-CBC ciphers to the default server proposal list. AES-CBC was removed as
            part of the update to OpenSSH version 7.1p2, but the plan is to re-add it, specifically for lightweight
            clients who rely on hardware crypto offload to have acceptable SSH performance&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Please go out and test&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.opnsense.org/index.php?topic=2378.0&quot;&gt;OPNsense 16.1.6
            released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A new point-release of OPNsense has dropped, and apart from the usual security updates, some new
            features have been included&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;firmware: bootstrap utility can now directly install e.g. the development version&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;dhcp: all GUI pages have been reworked for a polished look and feel&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;proxy: added category-based remote file support if compressed file contains multiple files&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;proxy: added ICAP support (contributed by Fabian Franz)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;proxy: hook up the transparent FTP proxy&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;proxy: add intercept on IPv6 for FTP and HTTP proxy options&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;logging: syslog facilities, like services, are now fully pluggable&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;vpn: stripped an invalid PPTP server configuration from the standard configuration&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;vpn: converted to pluggable syslog, menu and ACL&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;dyndns: all GUI pages have been reworked for a polished look and feel&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;dyndns: widget now shows IPv6 entries too&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;dns forwarder: all GUI pages have been reworked for a polished look and feel&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;dns resolver: all GUI pages have been reworked for a polished look and feel&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;dns resolver: rewrote the dhcp lease registration hooks&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;dns resolver: allow parallel operation on non-standard port when dns forwarder is running as well&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;firewall: hide outbound nat rule input for &quot;interface address&quot; option and toggle bitmask
            correctly&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;interfaces: fix problem when VLAN tags weren&#39;t generated properly&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;interfaces: improve interface capability reconfigure&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;ipsec: fix service restart behaviour from GUI&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;captive portal: add missing chain in certificate generation&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;configd: improve recovery and reload behaviour&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;load balancer: reordered menu entries for clarity&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;ntp: reordered menu entries for clarity&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;traffic shaper: fix mismatch for direction + dual interfaces setup&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;languages: updated German and French&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.freebsd.org/pipermail/freebsd-arch/2016-March/017719.html&quot;&gt;Call
            for testing - ASLR patch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A patch that provides a first pass implementation of basic ASLR (Address Space Layout
            Randomization) for FreeBSD has been posted to the mailing list&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“Stack gap, W^X, shared page randomization, KASLR and other techniques are explicitly out of scope
            of this work.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“ASLR is enabled on per-ABI basis, and currently it is only enabled on native i386 and amd64
            (including compat 32bit) ABIs. I expect to test and enable ASLR for armv6 and arm64 as well, later”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“Thanks to Oliver Pinter and Shawn Webb of the HardenedBSD project for pursuing ASLR for FreeBSD.
            Although this work is not based on theirs, it was inspired by their efforts.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s20Z81SPq3&quot;&gt; Daniel - OpenZFS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2be4zDkG6&quot;&gt; Florian - JBODS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2o0MijCFy&quot;&gt; Hunter - SSL on DO&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2fXlOwdU7&quot;&gt; Ben - Backups&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2weBPb8sx&quot;&gt; Damian - Bug’in Me!&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a
            href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Scaling up with BSD</title>
        <smi:episode>132</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_03_10-scaling_up_with_bsd"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_03_10-scaling_up_with_bsd</id>
        <published>2016-03-10T10:00:39-07:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-16T08:14:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0132.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="50279983"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0132.ogg"
                    fileSize="50279983"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0132.mp3"
                    fileSize="31277861"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/bsd-0132-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>JT</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
        </contributor>
        <summary>This week, Allan &amp; I are away at AsiaBSDCon! (If you aren’t there, you are missing out). We will be
            back with a live episode next week. However, we’ve been asked for Allan to tell us about ScaleEngine’s use
            of BSD for a while now &amp; we want to take this time to share it with you. That &amp; some Beastie Bits
            for your consumption, all this week on BSDNow.
        </summary>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>BSD Behind The Chalkboard</title>
        <smi:episode>131</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_03_03-bsd_behind_the_chalkboard"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_03_03-bsd_behind_the_chalkboard</id>
        <published>2016-03-03T07:24:46-08:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-16T08:20:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jupiterbroadcasting/bsd-0131.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="77423944"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jupiterbroadcasting/bsd-0131.ogg"
                    fileSize="77423944"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jupiterbroadcasting/bsd-0131.mp3"
                    fileSize="48742495"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/bsd-0131-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>JT</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Jamie McParland</name>
            <email>mcparlandj@newberg.k12.or.us</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/nsdjamie</uri>
        </contributor>
        <summary>This week on the show, we have an interview with Jamie McParland of the Newburg public school district
            in Oregon. We are going to get an inside look at how they use BSD in various aspects operations across their
            network, as well as bringing you the latest news and questions. Keep it tuned to BSDNow, the place to
            B...SD!
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 131: BSD behind the chalkboard&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bsdcan.org/2016/list-of-talks.txt&quot;&gt;BSDCan 2016 List of Talks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;We are all looking forward to BSDCan&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Make sure you arrive in time for the Goat BoF, the evening of Tuesday June 7th at the Royal Oak,
            just up the street from the university residence&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There will also be a ZFS BoF during lunch of one of the conference days, be sure to grab your
            lunch and bring it to the BoF room&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Also, don’t forget to get signed up for the various DevSummits taking place at BSDCan. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/unix/ManyLoadAveragesOfUnix&quot;&gt;What
            does Load Average really mean&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Chris Siebenmann, a sysadmin at the University of Toronto, does some comparison of what “Load
            Average” means on different unix systems, including Solaris/IllumOS, FreeBSD, NetBSD, OpenBSD, and Linux&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It seems that no two OSes use the same definition, so comparing load averages is impossible&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;On FreeBSD, where I/O does not affect load average, you can divide the load average by the number
            of CPU cores to be able to compare across machines with different core counts&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sfconservancy.org/blog/2016/feb/25/zfs-and-linux/&quot;&gt;GPL violations
            related to combining ZFS and Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;As we mentioned in last week’s episode, Ubuntu was preparing to release their next version with
            native ZFS support. + As expected, the Software Freedom Conservancy has issued a statement detailing the
            legal argument why they believe this is a violation of the GPL license for the Linux kernel.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It’s a pretty long and complete article, but we wanted to bring you the summary of the whole, and
            encourage you to read the rest, since it’s good to be knowledgeable about the various open-source projects
            and their license conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;“We are sympathetic to Canonical&#39;s frustration in this desire to easily support more features
            for their users. However, as set out below, we have concluded that their distribution of zfs.ko violates the
            GPL. We have written this statement to answer, from the point of view of many key Linux copyright holders,
            the community questions that we&#39;ve seen on this matter. Specifically, we provide our detailed analysis
            of the incompatibility between CDDLv1 and GPLv2 — and its potential impact on the trajectory of free
            software development — below. &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;However, our conclusion is simple: Conservancy and the Linux copyright holders in the GPL
            Compliance Project for Linux Developers believe that distribution of ZFS binaries is a GPL violation and
            infringes Linux&#39;s copyright. We are also concerned that it may infringe Oracle&#39;s copyrights in ZFS.
            As such, we again ask Oracle to respect community norms against license proliferation and simply relicense
            its copyrights in ZFS under a GPLv2-compatible license.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://softwarefreedom.org/resources/2016/linux-kernel-cddl.html&quot;&gt;The
            Software Freedom Law Center’s take on the issue &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hansenpartnership.com/are-gplv2-and-cddl-incompatible/&quot;&gt;Linux
            SCSI subsystem Maintainer, James Bottomley, asks “where is the harm”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://freebsdfoundation.blogspot.ca/2016/02/freebsd-and-zfs.html&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            and ZFS &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;amp;px=DragonFlyBSD-i915-4.2&quot;&gt;DragonFly
            i915 reaches Linux 4.2 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The port of the Intel i915 DRM/KMS Linux driver to DragonFlyBSD has been updated to match Linux
            kernel 4.2&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Various improvements and better support for new hardware are included&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;One big difference, is that DragonFlyBSD will not require the binary firmware blob that Linux does&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Fran&#231;ois Tigeot explains: &quot;starting from Linux 4.2, a separate firmware blob is required
            to save and restore the state of display engines in some low-power modes. These low-power modes have been
            forcibly disabled in the DragonFly version of this driver in order to keep it blob-free.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Obviously this will have some disadvantage, but as those modes were never available on
            DragonFlyBSD before, users are not likely to miss them&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Interview - Jamie McParland - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mcparlandj@newberg.k12.or.us&quot;&gt;mcparlandj@newberg.k12.or.us&lt;/a&gt;
            / &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nsdjamie&quot;&gt;@nsdjamie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;FreeBSD behind the chalkboard&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;iXsystems&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/LinuxActionShow/comments/48c9nt/my_new_ixsystems_mail_server/&quot;&gt;My
            New IXSystems Mail Server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.gufi.org/2016/02/15/elk-first-part/&quot;&gt;Installing ELK on
            FreeBSD, Tutorial Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Are you an ELK user, or interested in becoming one? If so, Gruppo Utenti has a nice blog post /
            tutorial on how to get started with it on FreeBSD.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Maybe you haven’t heard of ELK, but its not the ELK in ports, specifically in this case he is
            referring to “ElasticSearch/Logstash/Kibana” as a stack.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Getting started is relatively simply, first we install a few ports/packages:

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;textproc/elasticsearch&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;sysutils/logstash&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;textproc/kibana43&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;www/nginx&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;After enabling the various services for those (hint: sysrc may be easier), he then takes us
            through the configuration of ElasticSearch and LogStash. For the most part they are fairly straightforward,
            but you can always copy and paste his example config files as a template.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.gufi.org/2016/02/23/elk-second-part/&quot;&gt;Follow up to
            Installing ELK on FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Jumping directly into the next blog entry, he then takes us through the “K” part of ELK,
            specifically setting up Kibana, and exposing it via nginx publically. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;At this point most of the CLI work is finished, and we have a great walkthrough of doing the
            Kibana configuration via their UI. We are still awaiting the final entry to the series, where the setup of
            ElastAlert will be detailed, and we will bring that to your attention when it lands. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ftp.cs.wisc.edu/paradyn/technical_papers/fuzz.pdf&quot;&gt;From 1989: An
            Empirical Study of the Reliablity of Unix Utilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A paper from 1989 on the results of fuzz testing various unix utilities across a range of
            available unix operating systems&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Very interesting results, it is interesting to look back at before the start of the modern BSD
            projects&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;New problems are still being found in utilities using similar testing methodologies, like afl
            (American Fuzzy lop)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;Google Summer of Code&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Both
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/organizations/4892834293350400/&quot;&gt;FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;and
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/organizations/6246531984261120/&quot;&gt;NetBSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Are running 2016 Google Summer of Code projects.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Students can start submitting proposals on March 14th.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In the meantime, if you have any ideas, please post them to the
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.freebsd.org/SummerOfCodeIdeas&quot;&gt;Summer Of Code Ideas Page &lt;/a&gt; on
            the FreeBSD wiki&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Students can start looking at the list now and try to find mentors to get a jump start on their
            project.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.dragonflybsd.org/pipermail/commits/2016-February/459424.html&quot;&gt;High
            Availablity Sync for ipfw3 in Dragonfly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Similar to pfsync, this new protocol allows firewall dynamic rules (state) to be synchronized
            between two firewalls that are working together in HA with CARP&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Does not yet sync NAT state, it seems libalias will need some modernization first&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Apparently it will be relatively easy to port to FreeBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This is one of the only features ipfw lacks when compared to pf&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;Beastie Bits&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.freebsd.org/pipermail/freebsd-stable/2016-February/084238.html&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            10.3-BETA3 Now Available&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://undeadly.org/cgi?action=article&amp;amp;sid=20160301141941&amp;amp;mode=expanded&quot;&gt;LibreSSL
            isnt affected by the OpenSSL DROWN attack&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mail-index.netbsd.org/netbsd-advocacy/2016/02/29/msg000703.html&quot;&gt;NetBSD
            machines at the Open Source Conference 2016 in Toyko&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://marc.info/?l=openbsd-ports-cvs&amp;amp;m=145650279825695&amp;amp;w=2&quot;&gt;OpenBSD
            removes Linux Emulation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://queue.acm.org/detail.cfm?id=2878574&quot;&gt;Time is an illusion
            - George Neville-Neil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openssh.com/txt/release-7.2&quot;&gt;OpenSSH 7.2 Released&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2qCKWWKv0&quot;&gt; Shane - IPSEC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s20CP3ty5P&quot;&gt; Darrall - 14TB Zpool&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slexy.org/view/s2qp7K9KBG&quot;&gt; Pedja - ZFS setup&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a
            href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
