<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed
        xml:lang="en-us"
        xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
        xmlns:smi="https://www.betterfeeds.org/series-media-info"
        xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
        xmlns:psc="http://podlove.org/simple-chapters">
    <title>BSD Now</title>
    <subtitle>A weekly show covering the latest developments in the world of the BSD family of operating systems. News,
        Tutorials and Interviews for new users and long time developers alike.
    </subtitle>
    <icon>http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/images/bsdnow-badge.jpg</icon>
    <media:thumbnail
            url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/images/bsdnow-badge.jpg"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow/bsdnow-2016-04.atom"
            rel="self"
            type="application/atom+xml"
            title="BSD Now"/>
    <link
            href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/"
            rel="alternate"
            type="text/html"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowMp3"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now MP3 Audio"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowOgg"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now OGG Audio"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowMobile"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now SD Video"/>
    <link
            href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BsdNowHd"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now HD Video"/>
    <link
            href="http://bitlove.org/jupiterbroadcasting/bsdnowhd/feed"
            rel="related"
            type="application/rss+xml"
            title="BSD Now HD Video (BitTorrent)"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow/bsdnow-2016-05.atom"
            rel="previous"
            type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow/bsdnow-2016-03.atom"
            rel="next"
            type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow.atom"
            rel="first"
            type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link
            href="https://feeds.betterfeeds.org/bsdnow/bsdnow-2013-09.atom"
            rel="last"
            type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/</id>
    <updated>2016-06-15T13:07:00Z</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Jupiter Broadcasting</name>
        <uri>www.jupiterbroadcasting.com</uri>
    </author>
    <smi:sequential>false</smi:sequential>
    <entry>
        <title>Cheri-picking BSD</title>
        <smi:episode>139</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_04_27-cheri_picking_bsd"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_04_27-cheri_picking_bsd</id>
        <published>2016-04-28T06:47:51-07:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-15T12:49:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0139.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="56290358"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0139.ogg"
                    fileSize="56290358"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0139.mp3"
                    fileSize="33611954"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/bsd-0139-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>JT</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/q5sys</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Brooks Davis</name>
            <email>brooks@FreeBSD.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/brooksdavis</uri>
        </contributor>
        <summary>This week, Allan is out of town, but since when has that ever stopped us from bringing you a new
            episode of BSDNow? We have news, feedback &amp; an excellent interview with Brooks Davis telling us about
            CheriBSD that you won’t want to miss.
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 139: Cheri-picking BSD&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/unix/FileSyncProblem&quot;&gt;Unix&#39;s
            file durability problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Another article by Chris Siebenmann from the University of Toronto&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This time, the issue was a lost comment on his Python based blog which uses files on disk rather
            than a database&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;After an unexpected restart of the system, a recently posted comment no longer existed&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The post goes on to investigate what the ‘right way’ to ensure file durability is&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The answer, as you might expect, is “it depends…”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Normally, fsync() should work, but it seems with ext4 and some other file systems, you must also
            fsync() the directory where the file was created, or it might not be possible to find the file after a crash&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Do you need to fsync() the parent of that directory too? Then what is fdatasync() for? What about
            just calling sync()?&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“One issue is that unlike many other Unix API issues, it&#39;s impossible to test to see if you
            got it all correct and complete. If your steps are incomplete, you don&#39;t get any errors; your data is
            just silently sometimes at risk. Even with a test setup to create system crashes or abrupt power loss (which
            VMs make much easier), you need uncommon instrumentation to know things like if your OS actually issued disk
            flushes or just did normal buffered writes. And straightforward testing can&#39;t tell you if what you&#39;re
            doing will work all the time, because what is required varies by Unix, kernel version, and the specific
            filesystem involved.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/python/HowISyncDataDWiki&quot;&gt;Second
            post by author: How I&#39;m trying to do durable disk writes &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=11511269&quot;&gt;Additional Discussion on
            Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The discussion on HN also gets into AIO and other more complicated facilities, but even those seem
            to be vague about when your data is actually safe&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;At least ZFS ensures you never get half of your new data, and half of your old data.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/FreeBSD_10.3-release_Openstack_Image.html&quot;&gt;Build
            a FreeBSD 10.3-release Openstack Image with bsd-cloudinit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Are you using FreeBSD and OpenStack or would you like to be? We next have a great tutorial which
            explains the ins-and-outs of doing exactly that. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Remy van Elst brings us a great walkthrough on his site on how to get started, and hint it
            involves just a few ‘pip’ commands. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;After getting the initial Python tools bootstrapped, next he shows us how to save our OpenStack
            settings in a sourceable shell command, which comes in handy before doing admin on a instance.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Next the ‘glance’ and ‘cinder’ tools are used to upload the target OS ISO file and then create a
            volume for it to install onto.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Next the VM is started and some specific steps are outlined on getting FreeBSD 10.3 installed into
            the instance. It includes some helpful hints as how to fix a mountroot error, if you installed to ada0, but
            need to mount via vtdb0 instead now. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;After the installation is finished, the prep for ‘cloudinit’ is done, and the resulting image is
            compressed and made ready for deployment. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;We’ve kinda stepped through some of the more gory steps here, but if OpenStack is something you
            work with, this tutorial should be at the top of your “must read” list.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://undeadly.org/cgi?action=article&amp;amp;sid=20160411201504&quot;&gt;Undeadly
            and HTTPS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Undeadly, the OpenBSD journal, is thinking of moving to HTTPS only&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In order to do this, they would like some help rewriting part of the site&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Currently, when you login to post comments, this is done over HTTPS, but to an stunnel instance
            running a custom script that gives you a cookie, and sends you back to the non-HTTPS site&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;They would like to better integrate the authentication system, and otherwise improve the code for
            the site&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There is some pushback as well, questioning whether it makes sense to block users who are unable
            to use HTTPS for one reason or another&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;I think it makes sense to have the site default to HTTPS, but, maybe HTTPS only doesn’t make
            sense. There is nothing private on the site, other than the authentication system which is optional, not
            required to post a comment.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There is also some discussion about the code for the site, including the fact that when the code
            was released, the salt for the password database was included&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This is not actually a security problem, but the discussion may be interesting to some viewers&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freebsdfoundation.org/journal/browser-based-edition/&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            Journal March/April Edition &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The next issue of the FreeBSD Journal is here, and this time it is about Teaching with Operating
            Systems&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In addition to the usual columns, including: svn update, the ports report, a conference report
            from FOSDEM, a meetup report from PortsCamp Taipei, A book review of &quot;The Algorithm Design Manual&quot;,
            and the Events Calendar; there are a set of feature articles about teaching&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Teaching with FreeBSD through Tracing, Analysis, and Experimentation&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;CHERI: Building a foundation for secure, trusted computing bases&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A brief history of Fast Filesystems&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There is also an interview with Gleb Smirnoff, a member of the Core team, release engineering, and
            the deputy security officer, as well as a senior software developer at Netflix&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Get the latest issue from your favourite mobile store, or the “Desktop Edition” directly in your
            browser from the FreeBSD Foundation’s website&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Interview - Brooks Davis - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:brooks@FreeBSD.org&quot;&gt;brooks@FreeBSD.org&lt;/a&gt;
            / &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brooksdavis&quot;&gt;@brooksdavis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;CHERI and Capabilities&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ixsystems.com/blog/truenas-three-peats/&quot;&gt;TrueNAS
            Three-Peats!!!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://linux.softpedia.com/blog/ubuntubsd-is-looking-to-become-an-official-ubuntu-flavor-502746.shtml&quot;&gt;UbuntuBSD
            Is Looking To Become An Official Ubuntu Flavor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;You may recall a few weeks back that we were a bit surprised by the UbuntuBSD project and its
            longevity / goals.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;However the project seems to be pushing forward, with news on softpedia.com that they are now
            seeking to become an ‘official’ Ubuntu Flavor. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;They’ve already released a forth beta, so it seems the project currently has some developers
            pushing it forward:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&quot;I would like to contribute all my work to Ubuntu Community and, if you think it is worthy,
            make ubuntuBSD an official Ubuntu project like Xubuntu or Edubuntu,&quot; said Jon Boden. &quot;If you&#39;re
            interested, please let me know how would you like me to proceed.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.appliedcompscilab.com/its_just_bits/index.html&quot;&gt;It&#39;s Just
            Bits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;We have next an interesting blog post talking about the idea that “It’s just all bits!”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The author then takes us down the idea of no matter how old or mysterious the code may be, in the
            end it is ending up as bits arranged a certain way.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Then the article transitions and takes us through the idea that old bits, and bits that have grown
            too large should often be good candidates for replacement by “simpler” bits, using OpenBSD as an example.
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;“The OpenBSD community exemplifies this in many ways by taking existing solutions and simplifying
            them. Processing man pages is as old as Unix, and even in the 21st century OpenBSD has taken the time to
            rewrite the existing solution to be simpler and safer. It&#39;s just bits that need to be turned into other
            bits. Similarly, OpenBSD has introduced doas as an alternative to sudo. While not replacing sudo entirely,
            doas makes the 99.99% case of what people use sudo for easier and safer. They are just bits that need to be
            authenticated. “&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;All in all, a good read, and it reinforces the point that nothing is really truly “finished”. As
            computing advances and new technologies / practices are made available, sometimes it makes a lot of sense to
            go back and re-write things in order to simplify the complexity that has snuck in over time.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.freebsd.org/pipermail/svn-src-head/2016-April/084288.html&quot;&gt;Disk
            IO limiting is coming to FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A much requested feature for both Jails and VM’s on FreeBSD has just landed with
            experimental support in -HEAD, Disk IO limiting!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Commit message states as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;“Add four new RCTL resources - readbps, readiops, writebps and writeiops,
            for limiting disk (actually filesystem) IO.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Note that in some cases these limits are not quite precise. It&#39;s ok,
            as long as it&#39;s within some reasonable bounds.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Testing - and review of the code, in particular the VFS and VM parts - is
            very welcome.”&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Well, what are you waiting for? This is a fantastic new feature which I’m sure will get
            incorporated into other tools for controlling jails and VM’s down the road.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;If you give it a spin, be sure to report back bugs so they can get quashed in time for 11.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;BeastieBits&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.softpedia.com/news/pc-bsd-10-3-is-the-last-in-the-series-pc-bsd-11-0-arrives-later-this-year-502570.shtml&quot;&gt;PC-BSD
            10.3 Is the Last in the Series, PC-BSD 11.0 Arrives Later This Year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mail-index.netbsd.org/source-changes/2016/04/10/msg073939.html&quot;&gt;ASLR
            now on by default in NetBSD amd64&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.dragonflybsd.org/pipermail/users/2016-April/228682.html&quot;&gt;Daniel
            Bilik&#39;s fix for hangs on Baytrail&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pgcon.org/2016/&quot;&gt;Don’t forget about PGCon 2016&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2016.eurobsdcon.org/call-for-papers/&quot;&gt;Get your paper in
            for EuroBSDCon 2016, deadline is May 8th&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/QdGWn0TW&quot;&gt; John - Destroy all Dataset&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/43YkwBjP&quot;&gt; Thomas - Misc Questions&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/gdi3pswe&quot;&gt; Ben - ZFS Copy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/E9n938D1&quot;&gt; Bryson - SysV IPC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/bgGTmbDG&quot;&gt; Drin - IPSEC &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a
            href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Rushing into BSD</title>
        <smi:episode>138</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_04_20-rushing_into_bsd"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_04_20-rushing_into_bsd</id>
        <published>2016-04-21T11:37:18-07:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-15T12:55:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0138.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="79055263"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0138.ogg"
                    fileSize="79055263"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jnite/bsd-0138.mp3"
                    fileSize="46511429"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/bsd-0138-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>TJ</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/blakkheim</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Benedict Reuschling</name>
            <email>bcr@freebsd.org</email>
        </contributor>
        <summary>This week on the show, we will be talking to Benedict Reushling about his role with the FreeBSD
            foundation and the journey that took him there. That plus a few weeks worth of news to get caught up on,
            coming up next on BSDNow!
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 138: Rushing into BSD&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hardenedbsd.org/article/shawn-webb/2016-04-15/introducing-full-pie-support&quot;&gt;HardenedBSD
            introduces full PIE support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;PIE base for amd64 and i386&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Only nine applications are not compiled as PIEs&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Tested PIE base on several amd64 systems, both virtualized and bare metal&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Hoped to be to enabled it for ARM64 before or during BSDCan.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Shawn will be bringing ten Raspberry Pi 3 devices (which are ARM64) with to BSDCan, eight of which
            will be given out to lucky individuals. “We want the BSD community to hack on them and get ARM64/Aarch64
            fully functional on them.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://m.cacm.acm.org/magazines/2016/3/198874-lessons-learned-from-30-years-of-minix/fulltext&quot;&gt;Lessons
            learned from 30 years of MINIX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Eat your own dog food.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;By not relying on idiosyncratic features of the hardware, one makes porting to new platforms much
            easier.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The Internet is like an elephant; it never forgets.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;When standards exist (such as ANSI Standard C) stick to them.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Even after you have adopted a strategy, you should nevertheless reexamine it from time to time.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Keep focused on your real goal, Einstein was right: Things should be as simple as possible but not
            simpler.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.pfsense.org/?p=2008&quot;&gt;pfSense 2.3 released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Rewrite of the webGUI utilizing Bootstrap&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;TLS v1.0 disabled for the GUI&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Moved to a FreeBSD 10.3-RELEASE base&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;PHP Upgraded to 5.6&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The &quot;Full Backup&quot; feature has been deprecated&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Closed 760 total tickets of which 137 are fixed bugs&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Known Regressions&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;OpenVPN topology change&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;IP aliases with CARP IP parent lose their parent interface association post-upgrade &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;IPsec IPComp does not work.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;IGMP Proxy does not work with VLAN interfaces.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Many other updates and changes&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://opnsense.org/opnsense-16-1-10-released/&quot;&gt;OPNsense 16.1.10
            released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;openvpn: revive windows installer binaries&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;system: improved config history and backup pages layout&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;system: increased backup count default from 30 to 60&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;system: /var /tmp MFS awareness for crash dumps added&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;trust: add “IP security IKE intermediate” to server key usage&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;firmware: moved reboot, halt and defaults pages to new home&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;languages: updates to Russian, French, German and Japanese&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Many other updates and changes&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Interview - Benedict Reuschling - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:bcr@freebsd.org&quot;&gt;bcr@freebsd.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;FreeBSD Foundation in Europe&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.daemonology.net/blog/2016-04-11-write-opinionated-workarounds.html&quot;&gt;Write
            opinionated workarounds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Colin Percival has written a great blog post this past week, specifically talking about his policy
            of writing “opinionated workarounds”.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The idea came about due to his working on multi-platform software, and the frustrations of dealing
            with POSIX violations&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The crux of the post is how he deals with these workarounds. Specifically by &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt;
            applying them to the particular system in which it was required. And doing so loudly. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This has some important benefits. First, it doesn’t potentially expose other systems to bugs /
            security flaws when a workaround doesn’t
            “work” on a system for which it wasn’t designed. Secondly it’s important to complain. Loudly. This lets the
            user know that they are running on a system that doesn’t adhere to POSIX compliance, and maybe even get the
            attention of a developer who could remedy the situation.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ftp.netbsd.org/pub/NetBSD/security/advisories/NetBSD-SA2016-003.txt.asc&quot;&gt;Privilege
            escalation in calendar(1)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;File this one under “Ouch that hurts” a new security vuln has been posted, this time against
            NetBSD’s ‘calendar’ command.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Specifically it looks like some of the daily scripts uses the ‘-a’ flag, which requires super-user
            privs in order to process all users calendar files and mail the results.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;However the bug occurred because the calendar command didn’t drop priv properly before executing
            external commands (whoops!)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;To workaround you can set run_calendar=NO in the daily.conf file, or apply the fixed binary from
            upstream.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pgcon.org/2016/&quot;&gt;PGCon 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;PGCon 2016 is now only 4 weeks away&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The conference will be held at the University of Ottawa (same venue as BSDCan) from May 17th to
            20th&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Tutorials: 17-18 May 2016 (Tue &amp;amp; Wed)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Talks: 19-20 May 2016 (Thu-Fri)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Wednesday is a developer unconference.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Saturday is a user unconference.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“PGCon is an annual conference for users and developers of PostgreSQL, a leading relational
            database, which just happens to be open source. PGCon is the place to meet, discuss, build relationships,
            learn valuable insights, and generally chat about the work you are doing with PostgreSQL. If you want to
            learn why so many people are moving to PostgreSQL, PGCon will be the place to find out why. Whether you are
            a casual user or you&#39;ve been working with PostgreSQL for years, PGCon will have something for you.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;New to PGSQL? Just a user? Long time developers? This conference has something for you. &lt;a
            href=&quot;https://www.pgcon.org/2016/schedule/events.en.html&quot;&gt;A great lineup of talks&lt;/a&gt;,
            plus unconference days focused on both users and developers&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://2016.eurobsdcon.org/call-for-papers/&quot;&gt;CfP EuroBSDCon 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The call for papers has been issued for EuroBSDCon 2016 in Belgrade, Serbia&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The conference will be held from the 22nd to 25th of September, 2016&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The deadline for talk submissions is: Sunday the 8th of May, 2016&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Submit your talk or tutorial proposal before it is too late&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Beastie Bits&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.michaelwlucas.com/nonfiction/fmaz&quot;&gt;“FreeBSD Mastery:
            Advanced ZFS” has officially been released &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/ligurio/f6114bd1df371047dd80ea9b8a55c104&quot;&gt;Support
            of OpenBSD pledge(2) in programming Languages&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://daemonforums.org/showthread.php?t=9781&quot;&gt;pkgsrcCon 2016
            -Call for Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.netbsd.org/tnf/entry/talks_about_blacklistd&quot;&gt;Christos
            Zoulas talks about blacklistd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blather.michaelwlucas.com/archives/2617&quot;&gt;Penguicon 2016
            Lucas Track Schedule&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/HiiDpGcT&quot;&gt; Peter - NVME&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/L5XeVS1H&quot;&gt; Jeremy - Wireless Gear&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/yrCEnkWt&quot;&gt; Ted - Rpi2 Packages&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a
            href=&quot;https://wiki.freebsd.org/FreeBSD/arm/crossbuild&quot;&gt;Cross Building Wiki&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/pYFC1vdQ&quot;&gt; Geoff - Jail Failover&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/WEgN0ZVw&quot;&gt; Zach - Graphical Bhyve?&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a
            href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>FreeNAS Mini XL</title>
        <smi:episode>137</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_04_14-freenas_mini_xl"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_04_14-freenas_mini_xl</id>
        <published>2016-04-14T11:15:50-07:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-15T13:02:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0137.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="31233775"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0137.mp3"
                    fileSize="19369368"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0137.ogg"
                    fileSize="31233775"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/bsd-0137-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>TJ</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/blakkheim</uri>
        </contributor>
        <summary>This week on BSD Now, I’m out of town for the week, but we have a special unboxing video to share with
            you that you won’t want to miss. That, plus the latest BSD news, is coming your way right now!
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 137: FreeNAS Mini XL&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.cochard.me/2016/01/example-of-freebsd-bug-hunting-session.html&quot;&gt;Example
            of a FreeBSD bug hunting session by a simple user&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Don’t be fooled, Olivier Cochard-Labb&#233; is a bit more than just a FreeBSD user&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Original founder of the FreeNAS project many years ago, and currently leads the BSD Router Project
            (designed as a replacement for “Big Iron” routers like Cisco’s etc)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;However, he is not actually a committer on any of the BSD projects, and is mostly focused on
            networking, rather than development, so it is fair to call him a user&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;He walks us through a bug hunting session that started when he updated his wireless router&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“My wireless-router configuration was complex: it involves routing, wireless in hostap mode, ipfw,
            snort, bridge, openvpn, etc.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Provides helpful advice on writing problem reports to developers, including trying to reproduce
            your issue with as minimal a setup as possible. This both reduces the amount of setup a developer has to do
            to try to recreate your issue, and can often make it more obvious where the problem actually lies&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;As you might expect, the more he researched the problem, the more questions he had&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The journey goes through the kernel debugger, learning dtrace, and reading some source code&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In the end it seems the problem is that the bridge interface marks itself as down if none of the
            interfaces are in an ‘UP’ state. The wireless interface was in the unknown state, and was actually up, but
            when the wired interface was disconnected, this caused the bridge to mark it self as down.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ribalinux.blogspot.com/2016/04/how-to-install-openbsd-59-plus-xfce.html&quot;&gt;How-to
            Install OpenBSD 5.9 plus XFCE desktop and basic applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Now this is the way to do videos. Over at the RibaLinux blogspot site, we have a great video
            showing how to setup and install OpenBSD 5.9 with XFCE and basic desktop applications.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Along with the video tutorial, another nicety is the commands-used script, so you can see exactly
            how the setup was done, without having to pause/rewind the video to keep up. &lt;a href=&quot;http://ribalinux.blogspot.com/2016/04/how-to-install-pc-bsd-103.html&quot;&gt;How
            to install PC-BSD 10.3&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In addition to the OpenBSD 5.9 setup video, they just published a PC-BSD 10.3 installation video
            as well, check it out!&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/tanb/f8fefa22332edc7a641d&quot;&gt;FreeBSD on xhyve
            tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Originally only able to boot linux, xhyve, a “sort of” port of bhyve to OS X, can now run FreeBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This tutorial makes it much easier, providing a script&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There are a few small command line flag differences from bhyve on FreeBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The tutorial also covers sharing a directory between the guest and the host, resizing and growing
            the disk for the guest, and converting a QEMU image to be run under xhyve&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unixmen.com/configure-sshguard-ipfw-firewall-freebsd&quot;&gt;How to
            Configure SSHguard With IPFW Firewall On FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It’s been a while, but UNIXMen has dropped on us another FreeBSD tutorial, this time on how to
            setup IPFW and ‘sshguard’ to protect your system.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;In this tutorial they first lay down the rationale for picking IPFW as the firewall, but the
            reasons mainly boil down to IPFW being developed primarily on FreeBSD, and as such isn’t lagging behind when
            it comes to features / support.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Interestingly enough, they also go the route of adding their own /usr/local/etc/rc.firewall script
            which will be used to specify TCP/UDP ports to open through IPFW via the rc.conf file&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Once that setup is complete (which you can just copy-n-paste) they then move onto ‘sshguard’
            setup.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Specifically you’ll need to be sure to install the correct port/pkg, sshguard-ipfw in order to
            work in this setup, although sshguard-pf and friends are available also.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The article mentions that the name ‘sshguard’ can also be misleading, since it can be used to
            detect brute force attempts into a number of services.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;From there a bunch of configuration is thrown at you, which will allow you to start making the
            most out of sshguard’s potential, well worth your read if you are using IPFW, or even PF and want to get the
            basics down of using sshguard properly.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;FreeNAS Mini XL Video Unboxing&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Beastie Bits&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/NJ7lpso.png&quot;&gt;Amazon lists FreeBSD as &#39;Other Linux&#39;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.dragonflybsd.org/pipermail/commits/2016-April/459667.html&quot;&gt;sbin/hammer:
            Make hammer commands print root volume path&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.dragonflybsd.org/pipermail/commits/2016-April/459674.html&quot;&gt;sbin/hammer:
            Print volume list after volume-add|del&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mwlauthor/status/716328414072872960&quot;&gt;Front cover
            reveal for the upcoming &#39;FreeBSD Mastery: Advanced ZFS&quot; book&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;If you don’t already have one, get your &lt;a href=&quot;http://linuxpillow.blogspot.com/2016/03/world-backup-day.html&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            Pillow&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/raw/JBbMj87t&quot;&gt; Daniel - SysVIPC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/raw/54ngYVEN&quot;&gt; Shane - OpenToonz&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a
            href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>This is GNN</title>
        <smi:episode>136</smi:episode>
        <link
                rel="alternate"
                type="text/html"
                href="http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_04_06-this_is_gnn"/>
        <id>http://www.bsdnow.tv/episodes/2016_04_06-this_is_gnn</id>
        <published>2016-04-07T09:45:57-07:00</published>
        <updated>2016-06-15T13:07:00Z</updated>
        <link
                href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0136.ogg"
                rel="enclosure"
                length="78731509"
                type="audio/ogg"/>
        <media:group>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.ogg/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0136.ogg"
                    fileSize="78731509"
                    type="audio/ogg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="true"/>
            <media:content
                    url="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/traffic.libsyn.com/jbmirror/bsd-0136.mp3"
                    fileSize="46238083"
                    type="audio/mpeg"
                    medium="audio"
                    isDefault="false"/>
            <media:thumbnail
                    url="http://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/bsd-0136-v.jpg"/>
        </media:group>
        <contributor>
            <name>Kris Moore</name>
            <email>kris@pcbsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/pcbsdkris</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>Allan Jude</name>
            <email>allan@jupiterbroadcasting.com</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/allanjude</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>TJ</name>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/blakkheim</uri>
        </contributor>
        <contributor>
            <name>George Neville-Neil</name>
            <email>gnn@freebsd.org</email>
            <uri>https://twitter.com/gvnn3</uri>
        </contributor>
        <summary>This week on the show, we will be interviewing GNN of the FreeBSD project to talk about the new
            TeachBSD initiative. That plus the latest BSD headlines, all coming your way right now!
        </summary>
        <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Episode 136: This is GNN&lt;/h1&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freebsd.org/releases/10.3R/announce.html&quot;&gt;FreeBSD
            10.3-RELEASE Announcement &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;FreeBSD 10.3 has landed, with extended support until April 30, 2018&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This is likely to be the last extended support release, as starting with 11, the new support model
            will encourage upgrading to the latest minor version by ending support for the previous minor version
            approximately 2 months after each point release. The Major version / stable branch will still be supported
            for the same 5 year term. This will allow the FreeBSD project to move forward more quickly, while still
            providing the same level of long term support&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The UEFI boot loader is much improved, and now supports booting root-on-ZFS, and the beastie menu&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The beastie menu itself has been updated with support for ZFS Boot Environments&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The CAM Target Layer (CTL) now supports High Availability, allowing the construction of much more
            advanced storage systems&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The 64bit Linux Emulation Layer was backported&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Reroot support was added, allowing the system to boot off of a minimal image, such as a mfsroot
            and then reload all of userland from a different root file system (such as iSCSI, NFS, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The version of xz(1) has been updated to support multi-threaded compression&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;sesutil(8) has been introduced, making it easier to manage large storage nodes&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Various ZFS updates&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;As usual, a huge number of driver updates are also included&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.nongnu.org/archive/html/libreboot/2016-04/msg00010.html&quot;&gt;How
            to use OpenBSD with Libreboot: detailed instructions &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This tutorial covers installing OpenBSD on a Thinkpad X200 using Libreboot, a replacement for the
            traditional BIOS/firmware that comes from the manufacturer&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“Since 5.9, OpenBSD supports EFI boot mode, which means that it also have had to support
            framebuffer out of the box, so lack of proprietary VGA BIOS blob is no longer a problem and you can boot it
            with unmodified Libreboot binary release 20150518.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“In order to install OpenBSD on such a machine you will need someadditional preparations, since
            regular install59.fs won&#39;t work because bsd.rd doesn&#39;t have a framebuffer console.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A few extra steps are required to get it going, but they are outlined in the post&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This may be very interesting to those who prefer not to depend on binary blobs&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.llvm.org/pipermail/llvm-dev/2016-March/096449.html&quot;&gt;Linking
            the FreeBSD base system with lld -- status update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The FreeBSD Foundation’s Ed Maste provides an update on the LLVM mailing list about the progress
            of replacing the GNU linker with the lld in the FreeBSD base system&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;“I&#39;m pleased to report that I can now build a runnable FreeBSD system using lld as the linker
            (for buildworld), with a few workarounds and work-in-progress patches. I have not yet extensively tested the
            result but it is possible to login to the resulting system, and basic sanity tests I&#39;ve tried are
            successful. Note that the kernel is still linked with ld.bfd.”&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Outstanding Issues

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Symbol version support (PR 23231). FreeBSD uses symbol versioning for backwards compatibility&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Linker script expression support (PR 26731). The FreeBSD kernel linker scripts contain expressions
            not currently supported by lld&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Library search paths. GNU LD automatically searches /lib, and lld does not&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;the -N flag makes the text and data sections RW and does not page-align data.
            It is used by boot loader components.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The -dc flag assigns space to common symbols when producing relocatable output (-r). It is used by
            the /rescue build, which is a single binary assembled from a collection of individual tools (sh, ls, fsck,
            ...)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;-Y adds a path to the default library search path. It is used by the lib32 build, which provides
            i386 builds of the system libraries for compatibility with i386 applications.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;With the ongoing work, it might be possible for FreeBSD 11 to use lld by default, although it
            might be best to wait to throw that particular switch&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2016/04/forget-apple-vs-fbi-whatsapp-just-switched-encryption-billion-people/&quot;&gt;Your
            favorite billion user company using BSD just flipped on encryption for all their users -- and it took 15
            Engineers to do it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;With the help of Moxie Marlinspike’s Open Whisper Systems, WhatsApp has integrated the ‘Signal’
            encryption system for all messages, class, pictures, and videos sent between individuals or groups&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It uses public key cryptography, very similar to GPG, but with automated public key servers&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It also includes a system of QR codes to verify the identity of individuals in person, so you can
            be sure the person you are talking to is actually the person you met with&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;WhatsApp runs their billion user network, using FreeBSD, with only about 50 engineers&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Only 15 of those engineers we needed to work on the project that has now deployed complete
            end-to-end encryption across the entire network&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The Wired article is very detailed and well worth the read&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Interview - George Neville-Neil - &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:gnn@freebsd.org&quot;&gt;gnn@freebsd.org&lt;/a&gt;
            / &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gvnn3&quot;&gt;@gvnn3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Teaching BSD with Tracing&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;News Roundup&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freebsdfoundation.org/blog/faces-of-freebsd-2016-scott-long/&quot;&gt;Faces
            of FreeBSD 2016: Scott Long&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It’s been awhile since we’ve had a new entry into the “Faces of FreeBSD” series, but due to
            popular demand it’s back!&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;This installment features developer Scott Long, who currently works at NetFlix, previously at
            Yahoo and Adaptec.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Scott got a very early start into BSD, first discovering i386BSD 0.1 on a FTP server at Berkeley,
            back at 1992. From there on it’s been a journey, following along with FreeBSD since version 1.0 in 1993.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;So what stuff can we blame Scott for? In his own words:&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;I’ve been a source committer since 2000. I got my start by taking over maintainership of the
            Adaptec ‘aac’ RAID driver. From 2002-2006 I was the Release Engineer and was responsible for the 5.x and 6.x
            releases. Though the early 5.x releases were not great, they were necessary stepping stones to the success
            of FreeBSD 6.x and beyond. I’m exceptionally proud of my role in helping FreeBSD move forward during that
            time.&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;I authored and maintained the ‘mfi’ and ‘mps’ storage drivers, the ‘udf’ filesystem driver, and
            several smaller sound and USB drivers. I’ve maintained, or at least touched, most of the storage device
            drivers in the system to some extent, and I implemented medium-grained locking on the CAM storage stack.
            Recently I’ve been working on overall system scalability and performance.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://asciiflow.com/&quot;&gt;ASCII Flow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;A website that lets to draw and share ASCII diagrams&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Great for network layout maps, rack diagrams, protocol analysis etc&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Use it in your presentations and slides&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/open?id=0BynxTTJrNUOKeWxCVm1ERExrNkU&quot;&gt;Sample
            &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lowlevelbits.org/system-under-test-freebsd/&quot;&gt;System Under Test:
            FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Part of a series looking at testing across a number of projects&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Outlines the testing framework of FreeBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Provides a mini-tutorial on how to run the tests&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There are some other tests that are now covered, but this is due to a lack of documentation on the
            fact that the tests exist, and how to run them&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;There is much ongoing work in this area&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rhyous.com/2016/04/01/microsoft-announces-it-is-acquiring-freebsd-for-300-million/&quot;&gt;Worst
            April Fools Joke EVER!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;While a bad April Fool’s joke, it also shows some common misconceptions&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The FreeBSD Foundation does not own the source repository, it is only the care taken of the
            trademark, and other things that require a single legal entity&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;OpenBSD and NetBSD are not ‘sub brands’ of FreeBSD&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Bash was not ported to Windows, but rather Windows gained a system similar to FreeBSD’s
            linux_compat&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;It would be nice to have ZFS on Windows&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Beastie Bits&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.freebsd.org/threads/55642/&quot;&gt;Credit where credit&#39;s
            due...&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stable.mtier.org/&quot;&gt;M:Tier&#39;s OpenBSD packages and
            binpatches updated for 5.9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nycbug.org/index.cgi&quot;&gt;NYC BUG Meeting (2016-04-06) -
            Debugging with LLVM, John Wolfe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.dragonflybsd.org/pipermail/commits/2016-March/459651.html&quot;&gt;Need
            to create extremely high traffic loads? kq_sendrecv is worth checking out&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/CharmBUG/events/230048300/&quot;&gt;If you&#39;re
            in the Maryland region, CharmBug has a meetup next week&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dragonflybsd.org/docs/how_to_get_to_the_desktop/&quot;&gt;How
            to get a desktop on DragonFly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/q5sys/status/717509675630084096&quot;&gt;Linux vs
            BSD Development Models &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;h2&gt;Feedback/Question&lt;/h2&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/raw/GrM0jKZK&quot;&gt; Paulo - ZFS Setup&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/raw/13KCkhMU&quot;&gt; Jonathan - Installation &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/wsx90L2m&quot;&gt; Andrew - Career / School&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;

            &lt;hr&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Send questions, comments, show ideas/topics, or stories you want mentioned on the show to &lt;a
            href=&quot;mailto:feedback@bsdnow.tv&quot;&gt;feedback@bsdnow.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
